<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:16:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Lanterns 007</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lanterns-007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:16:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lanterns-007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think that this might be the newest of all the comics I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; is a series starring Simon Baz and Jessica Cruz, two novice members of the Green Lantern Corps, each saddled with their own hang-ups about being a hero. They were paired up by Hal Jordan and tasked with protecting Earth while he went out into outer space to locate the rest of the Green Lantern Corps (as they had gone missing at the time). Also, like any good buddy cop story, the two despise each other at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first arc of &lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; does a pretty respectable job of following Simon and Jessica through their trials of overcoming self-doubt, an irritating partner, and a potential invasion of earth by the Red Lanterns. This issue marks the beginning of a new story arc (and the denouement to the previous arc), so we get to see what the next phase of the protagonists&amp;rsquo; relationship looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; 007 features Simon and Jessica standing next to one another, in their uniforms, in front of a series of floating GL insignias. Simon holds his ring hand in front of him while Jessica raises hers high above her head.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Green-Lanterns-007.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Green Lanterns 007, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Green Lanterns issue 007&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue, set on Halloween, begins with a focus on Jessica&amp;rsquo;s perspective, coming to grips with being a GL and having to spend time with Simon&amp;rsquo;s family. In a pretty funny move, she bails out of family activities (readying treats for Halloween), claiming to herself that she&amp;rsquo;s not a people person, and instead tries to &amp;ldquo;find Darkseid and see what he&amp;rsquo;s doing for dinner,&amp;rdquo; even going so far as to ask her ring to call him (the ring: &amp;ldquo;Call sent to voice mail.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Simon catches her and begs for her help dealing with his family&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s clear that they have that much in common&amp;ndash;and the two do some baking as a way to contribute to the household and get to know one another better. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice chiasmus where Simon decides to bail on the baking (it&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; the way his mother makes it), and it becomes Jessica&amp;rsquo;s turn to talk her partner down from doing something stupid. After Simon explains his relationship with his mother to Jessica, the two have an epiphany to cook with the aid of their power rings (allowing them to multitask much more easily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: after revealing himself as a GL to his mom, Simon convinces her to try a cookie &amp;hellip; and she doesn&amp;rsquo;t hate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all of this, Farid (Simon&amp;rsquo;s nephew) has been screwing around with Rami, a Guardian of Oa hiding out in the family&amp;rsquo;s attic. Rami senses that some threat (revealed to be the Dominators) is coming, and &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; bails from the house. The two GLs recognize they need to go after him, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this issue is pretty solid in terms of character development. Action-wise, it&amp;rsquo;s very &amp;ldquo;boring,&amp;rdquo; but in the context of the preceding six issues, it&amp;rsquo;s a really enjoyable moment of rest. There had been a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of action in those issues focusing on the problems that Jessica and Simon each felt about their ability to be a hero, and the interaction between them&amp;ndash;and the rest of Simon&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;ndash;here becomes a useful and satisfying progression from their overcoming some of those problems in their fight against the Red Lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was not initially sold on Simon Baz as a GL (because he used a gun! which I still think is kind of a lame early gimmick), I have come to really enjoy the presentation of his character in this series. I think that he works well with Jessica&amp;ndash;a character I wasn&amp;rsquo;t well-versed in before this series&amp;ndash;to give the GL franchise a pairing that feels fresh and innovative. (I mean, as iconic as Hal Jordan is, it&amp;rsquo;s not really that fascinating to watch a guy who believes, and often proves, he can do anything he wants.) Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just the longtime Marvel fan in me, but the relatability of Simon &amp;amp; Jessica as heroes-who-don&amp;rsquo;t-always-think-they-live-up-to-the-role really do a lot to make this series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astro City 024</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 18:50:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Green Lantern remains perhaps my favorite character-specific franchise, &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt; is far and away my single favorite series, ever. It is superhero comics world-building done expertly, pulling together and twisting tropes in a way that has not been done as fully, consistently, or enjoyably by anyone else. Kurt Busiek has it all together here and presents it in full force with Alex Ross covers and (usually) Brent Anderson art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt; is a comic whose stories focus on the titular city (located on the west coast, standing in the place of San Francisco or Seattle), which is populated by more than a century of superhero history. There&amp;rsquo;s an homage or parody to pretty much every superhero type; the very first issue provides an incredible Superman tale via the stand-in Samaritan, the greatest storyline in the title involves a Batman and Robin pair, there&amp;rsquo;s a wisecracking acrobat who annoys &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; he runs into or teams up with, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue, in the third (current) volume, focuses on a talking gorilla from the fabled antarctic Gorilla Mountain. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. What does the gorilla&amp;ndash;who goes by the name &amp;ldquo;Sticks&amp;rdquo; (a nickname for his drumming and because his original name was apparently &amp;ldquo;Stekk&amp;rdquo;)&amp;ndash;want to do with his life? Play music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous issue detailed his initial arrival in Astro City, trying out for a band, and getting caught up in the world of superheroics (after all, he&amp;rsquo;s a talking gorilla! and he has some military training from the Gorilla Mountain forces).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover features Sticks in action, fangs bared, arms raised, and drumsticks in hand(s) as he&amp;rsquo;s in the middle of &lt;em&gt;pounding&lt;/em&gt; on a drum set (whose bass drum features the iconic Astro City &amp;ldquo;rocket&amp;rdquo; icon). An explosion of purple and green motion lines suggest this is a snapshot of an incredibly wild performance.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Astro-City-024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Astro City 024, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Astro City issue 024&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In this issue, we learn about Sticks&amp;rsquo; past&amp;ndash;why he left Gorilla Mountain and how it&amp;rsquo;s impacted his decision to try being a superhero, since he fits in more easily with them than with the average Astro City resident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the while, Sticks struggles with doing the right thing and &lt;em&gt;wanting&lt;/em&gt; to do the right thing, namely whether or not he should be a superhero just because he can, or if it&amp;rsquo;s better left to those with the drive to pursue it. As he states in a thought/narrative caption: &amp;ldquo;It takes the right kind of &lt;strong&gt;person&lt;/strong&gt; to do this kind of thing. To make it their life, their &lt;strong&gt;mission&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, he quits and reconnects with his old bandmates. Unfortunately, they don&amp;rsquo;t all agree on whether or not to keep associating with Sticks; after all, as a talking gorilla, he draws attention by super-villains and that could be dangerous for his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he&amp;rsquo;s understandable about it, Sticks is nonetheless hurt, and it shows (there&amp;rsquo;s something a bit astounding about feeling a sympathetic connection to a gorilla in a t-shirt). While he sits on a roof at night, Samaritan comes to visit and offers the sort of advice that the best Superman stories always allow him to provide: genuine empathy and consideration that lead toward an optimistic future always left in the listener&amp;rsquo;s hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samaritan acknowledges Sticks doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to be a superhero and doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to convince him otherwise. Instead, he demonstrates that he believes &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a way. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; a way. I &lt;strong&gt;believe&lt;/strong&gt; that. Don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;give up&lt;/strong&gt;. Find a way to do what you love. If I can help, you can call on me. I&amp;rsquo;ll give you an alert code. But find a &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much more of a &lt;em&gt;samaritan&lt;/em&gt; can one be, if not to help lift up another and assist them toward their goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sticks decides to take on the temporary identity of &amp;ldquo;Tuxedo Gorilla&amp;rdquo; in order to make a few higher-profile busts to draw the press so that he can make an announcement: he&amp;rsquo;s having auditions for a super-powered band. His superhero contacts provide security so that no one can disrupt the proceedings (including blocking any sensors attempting to learn the secret identities of auditioners), and he manages to get together a group that have music-oriented abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a record contract ready, Sticks and company decide to record some tricks and &amp;ldquo;fight a little crime along the way&amp;rdquo; as the group &lt;em&gt;Powerchord&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that I love every issue of &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt;, and this is no different. Sticks&amp;rsquo; story is a fantastic origin tale and an accessible jumping-on point for new readers (well, assuming they read issue 023 first). There are so many clear nods to existing comic characters and ideas&amp;ndash;most obviously being Gorilla Mountain&amp;rsquo;s debt to Gorilla City from &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ndash;and they&amp;rsquo;re all taken in really interesting and new directions while feeling familiar or comfortable in the best way(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could only read one comic series from this point forward, it would be &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt;, without question. And I would stand by that decision happily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange 072</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 22:44:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, a note: my random number generator seems to keep pointing me to issues numbering in the 70s. An interesting trend so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so, more Doctor Strange! And this time, it&amp;rsquo;s from the 1970s-80s series (a predecessor to the series discussed in my earlier Doctor Strange review).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; #072 shows Doctor Strange, with an absolutely &lt;em&gt;metal&lt;/em&gt; beard, wrapped in the tentacles of some green Lovecraftian creature whose limbs and cilia are writhing about. Doctor Strange gestures with one hand to fire some pink energy at his opponent.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-072.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange 072, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange issue 072&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story apparently starts in the Dark Dimension, or some related dimension, as we learn that Umar (Dormammu&amp;rsquo;s sister) is extracting tribute (aka taxes) in the form of mystic energy from her subjects. Technically, her tax collectors are doing this, on a platform in a public square that looks like it doubles as a French Revolution-era guillotine stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Strange has the best cloak/robe I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen him in (as he&amp;rsquo;s undercover or otherwise incognito, it appears), and&amp;ndash;again&amp;ndash;his hair looks &lt;em&gt;dope as hell&lt;/em&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to understate this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Doctor Strange and a handful of rebels storm the tax collector&amp;rsquo;s stage and collect the paid tributes (which have been condensed into small orbs or coins). Naturally, the citizens are a little pissed. There&amp;rsquo;s a really disturbing coincidental parallel to recent affairs, I think. Consider this exchange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Your rebellion&amp;rsquo;s public support is still somewhat lacking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rahl (a rebel)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;I know. The problem is that Umar has made herself appear benevolent and gracious to the people of the Dark Dimension. And after her brother&amp;rsquo;s reign of terror, there&amp;rsquo;s an illusion of good feeling in the realm. Things seem better to those who enjoy full citizenship, and so they&amp;rsquo;re afraid to support us. They fear that things might go back to the way they were!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Then your most urgent goal is to get the people to see Umar for what she really is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this goal is punctuated by an immediate need to fight some Mindless Ones, so at least there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of magical combat for the reader uninterested in interdimensional politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: the password chosen by Clea for entry into the rebels&amp;rsquo; stronghold is &amp;ldquo;Yo, Adriene &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s me, Rocky!&amp;rdquo; because&amp;ndash;according to Clea&amp;ndash;she chose an Earth-based pop culture reference (&amp;ldquo;things I remembered from your television, Stephen&amp;rdquo;) with the assumption that Umar&amp;rsquo;s subjects would never be able to guess it. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I&amp;rsquo;m shocked Doctor Strange has a television. I mean, he seems the type who&amp;rsquo;d be just snobby enough to pride himself in not watching TV and instead getting news updates and whatever from benevolent imp messengers or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, back on Earth, apparently Wong has to shut down the advances of Sara, an attractive girl who appears to be trying her best to engage Wong in a genuine relationship despite his unnerving dedication to being Doctor Strange&amp;rsquo;s manservant. (I mean, surely the good doctor would &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; his closest friend and companion to seek out intimate companionship, right?!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we&amp;rsquo;re only halfway through this story, and I have no clue what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Umar does her best, and fails, to spy on Strange through scrying magics. She does at least have a minor epiphany that he may be &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt;, including in her own dimension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Strange and Rahl go to visit the prisoner Orini&amp;ndash;Clea&amp;rsquo;s father, and Umar loyalist? I admit I am unfamiliar with this character&amp;ndash;and Strange uses the Eye of Agamotto to magically coerce Orini to give up the secrets of Umar&amp;rsquo;s army. Also, we learn the shocking revelation that Clea&amp;rsquo;s mother is Umar herself, having slept with Orini and abandoned the baby with him after Clea&amp;rsquo;s birth. Naturally, Clea is a bit taken aback by this when Strange informs her of the news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the rebels decide to storm one of Umar&amp;rsquo;s caravans (which looks &lt;em&gt;hilarious&lt;/em&gt; as an Oregon Trail-style wagon train with giant lizard beasts of burden and moving along on a Ditkoesque floating pathway), Clea frees her father to have a conversation with him as parent and child. He promptly beats the hell out of her, or so we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to assume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, there is an &lt;strong&gt;awesome&lt;/strong&gt; mystical moment where a caravan guard throws a canvas that, as it unfurls, opens a &amp;ldquo;portable warp&amp;rdquo; through which emerges a creature&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m guessing the monster from the cover&amp;ndash;that has a sharp beak and looks a lot like the alien from &lt;em&gt;Watchmen&lt;/em&gt; sans eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Doctor Strange tries to intervene and help the rebels, he is pulled &amp;hellip; somewhere else (it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say, since the background is all black) &amp;hellip; by &amp;ldquo;the outcasts,&amp;rdquo; creatures of various species, or so I gather (they have different hands/limbs, but we can&amp;rsquo;t see any of their facial features), who want to keep themselves hidden from Umar. When Strange says he wants to help regardless, they let him know it&amp;rsquo;s too late&amp;ndash;the rebels have fallen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a second cliffhanger moment, Orini arrives at Umar&amp;rsquo;s palace, bringing an unconscious Clea to his former lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story was dope, and is packed with some essential Doctor Strange plot tropes as well as moving along some character development for Clea and the residents of the Dark Dimension in general. I really wish Doctor Strange grew his hair out this way in the comics&amp;ndash;it really adds some metal/punk aesthetic to a character that is so often depicted as being very conservative in personal style, even despite the focus of his life&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Comics Presents 072</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 17:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Comics Presents&lt;/em&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt;) is a series that interested me for the longest time: it was an anthology comic that tended to have four stories (each 8 pages) of varying length, by which I mean that one story might have 8-10 parts, another might have 4-6, another might only be a single 8-page story, and so on. So a reader was likely to get some really fascinating story turnover in any given collection of issues. When I was young, &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; introduced me to some characters that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever would have checked out otherwise, most notably (for me) Shang-Chi, but also minor characters like Stingray or the Collective Man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary story of many &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; issues featured Wolverine&amp;ndash;unsurprising, given his ability to sell pretty much any comic where he appeared on the cover. &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; 072, however, is important because it begins the tale of an incredibly significant part of Wolverine&amp;rsquo;s backstory, written &amp;amp; drawn by Barry Windsor-Smith: the Weapon X experiments that bonded adamantium to his skeleton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover for issue 072, like all of the &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; covers, is wraparound, with the primary (Wolverine) story featured on the front and the characters of the other three stories&amp;ndash;Daredevil, Shanna the She-Devil, and Red Wolf&amp;ndash;on the back. On the front half, Wolverine stands, the right half of his body covered by his classic brown-and-yellow suit, and his left half naked with a number of protruding spikes in preparation for his adamantium injections. Behind him is a large skull (likely his own), with similar spikes. Flames beneath a blank blue canvas comprise the background, layered (from top down) yellow, orange, and red. At the top of the page, below the comic&amp;rsquo;s title/logo, are the words: &amp;ldquo;Before Wolverine there was Weapon X.&amp;rdquo; On the back half of the cover, Shanna is posed crouching (with a caption box that declares &amp;ldquo;Her &lt;strong&gt;jungle&lt;/strong&gt; reeks of &lt;strong&gt;evil&lt;/strong&gt;, and SHANNA must &lt;strong&gt;confront&lt;/strong&gt; it.&amp;ldquo;), while Red Wolf leaps behind her, up and to her left (captioned &amp;ldquo;RED WOLF &lt;strong&gt;faces&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;death&lt;/strong&gt; of his &lt;strong&gt;partner Lobo&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;ldquo;). Behind her, down and to the right, Daredevil similarly jumps forward, swinging his billy club (caption: &amp;ldquo;DAREDEVIL is &lt;strong&gt;helpless&lt;/strong&gt; when things come to a &lt;strong&gt;head&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;New York&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;). What appears to be the back side of the large skull from the front cover looms behind the figures.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Marvel Comics Presents 072, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Marvel Comics Presents issue 072&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Weapon X&amp;rdquo; story in this issue must have been &lt;em&gt;ridiculously&lt;/em&gt; confusing to everyone when it initially came out, since it consists of three threads: (1) Wolverine down on his luck in the Yukon, drinking and getting in fights; (2) flashes of the Weapon X experiments themselves, provided without explanation/context; (3) panels of a scientist performing some sort of experiment that may or may not be (but almost certainly is) related to the Weapon X project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually pick up this issue until last year, but I already knew the general beats to this story. I have to say, in its serialized form, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed since there&amp;rsquo;s no real room for anything to breathe here (although I get that BWS is trying to let things unfold in a somewhat-similar manner to Logan&amp;rsquo;s ability to comprehend what happened to him). The art style and the narration is solid&amp;ndash;it does its job of leaving me wanting more. I&amp;rsquo;m just torn in both wanting more and not feeling like I really had &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; in this portion to really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shanna comic provided is part 5 of its story. I&amp;rsquo;m stoked going in because there&amp;rsquo;s Paul Gulacy art&amp;ndash;which I know is not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea but he is great at &amp;ldquo;realistic&amp;rdquo; comic stories (such as his run on &lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt;) so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting strong work here. Shanna and some others are tracking diamond smugglers and poachers through/near Tanzania. This part of the story does a really successful job at showing the violence and tragedy that accompanies such acts, and the cliffhanger&amp;ndash;where Shanna discovers someone (a local?) buried up to his neck amid massive anthills&amp;ndash;is creepy and suspenseful. Unlike with the Wolverine story, I have a clear sense of where this is going (without bringing in retrospective knowledge of the overall plot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to explain the Daredevil component (it&amp;rsquo;s part 4 and the final part, apparently, of a story). There&amp;rsquo;s apparently been a heat weave, and tensions are running high as people get frustrated. A woman named Ms. Pinkwater, whose defining feature is a Carmen Sandiego hat, is doing &amp;hellip; something? I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure it out. Anyway, apparently a bunch of people hold hands and sing or something, and it causes rain to fall and all tensions in the city to relax. Daredevil doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do anything other than read a handwritten note that asks him not to do anything. What the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Red Wolf story&amp;ndash;which I think is a standalone story&amp;ndash;is equally weak. Red Wolf begins in a lodge, ruminating on the loss of his wolf partner Lobo, while a truck full of drunks look for something to hunt. They eventually discover a mother wolf feeding her cubs and proceed to kill almost all of them (save one), when Red Wolf finally acts. Even then, he&amp;rsquo;s nearly taken out until one of the hunters decides they&amp;rsquo;ve gone too far and has a standoff with his buddy. Red Wolf, meanwhile, takes the surviving cub (presumably to raise himself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this issue is a decent representative for &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; in general: there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting experimentation happening and some solid, compelling story work &amp;hellip; but there are also stinkers that don&amp;rsquo;t feel really worthwhile or well-realized. Does the former cancel out the latter? Yes and no&amp;ndash;certainly enough, for me, to not absolutely hate the series, but not so much that I forget nostalgia is a big part of my enjoyment of this series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal Man 076</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 23:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first Vertigo post for this blog is also the first &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, Animal Man. Such a great character raised out of mediocre beginnings. Without getting &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; mired in details, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to say that Buddy Baker&amp;ndash;Animal Man&amp;ndash;can tap into the abilities of animals and make use thereof to fight injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, unlike most superheroes, he has a family (a wife, Ellen, and two children, Cliff and Maxine). This is important, because the central conflict in Buddy&amp;rsquo;s life is the tug-of-war that &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt; occurs between his desire to live a normal life with his family and his desire to use his powers in the best and most effective way possible (often to try and raise awareness about animal rights and ecological issues). This tug-of-war has led Buddy to some interesting places (for the reader, at least; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much ruined his life over and over again). At least, this is what happened to the character in the first volume of his own series; Grant Morrison set up this model and pretty much every author working on &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; since has followed suit, although they may have tweaked some specifics here and there, like looking at how Ellen deals with her completely absurd life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, Buddy went through a significant metamorphosis that left him in the body of a chimerical creature with the attributes of all kinds of animals, and he decided to use his new appearance to help found a church that would worship his daughter Maxine and her even-more-powerful animal-related powers&amp;ndash;the church is even called &amp;ldquo;The Life-Power Church of Maxine&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;set up half-seriously and half-deceptively by the Bakers and their closest friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to issue 076, then, shows Buddy in his animal-avatar form flying through a red sky over what appears to be the upraised arms/hands of an angry mob, given the tools and guns held aloft by those arms.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Animal-Man-076.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Animal Man 076, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Animal Man issue 076&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story begins with several pages narrated via in-universe comics drawn by budding cartoonist Cliff Baker, who lets us know that the Life-Power Church is on its way to Montana in search of some promised land where people and animals can live in harmony. They&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with some hunters and other critics along the way, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cartoon has been mailed to Ellen, who&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; with her family but instead with a small group of lesbian activists (that&amp;rsquo;s not a snarky, bigoted comment by me&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s how the characters were introduced and how they continue to be portrayed; a few issues before this one, Ellen notes to Buddy that she&amp;rsquo;s felt a connection growing between her and Sarah, one of the activists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the Life-Power Church is facing off against the National Guard in Nebraska (there&amp;rsquo;s references to a &amp;ldquo;plague&amp;rdquo; that has affected a number of people across the country, where they dream of themselves as animals running wild on human society), and Ellen&amp;rsquo;s conflicted between staying put with Sarah and being there in Nebraska for her family; the conversation in this scene does a pretty solid job of demonstrating various characters&amp;rsquo; takes on the situation so that no one seems to have the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;most correct&amp;rdquo; answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an equally intriguing scene between Maxine and a follower of the LFC (Ray, given the Church name &amp;ldquo;Manta Ray&amp;rdquo;) who&amp;rsquo;s secretly a government agent awaiting the order to assassinate Maxine, Buddy, or both. But she finds herself questioning her ability to murder a child if so commanded when she takes an impromptu romp/bath in a nearby river with Maxine and a throng of animal companions/guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray&amp;rsquo;s plot intertwines with that of an older man named Jack who&amp;rsquo;s looking to save his son from the LFC cult. Ray ends up getting caught by some locals who decide to rape her in the corn fields. Jack saves her, figuring that she can&amp;rsquo;t have made any poor decisions (that is, it&amp;rsquo;s not her fault she was caught and is being tortured, it&amp;rsquo;s the Church&amp;rsquo;s) that his own son didn&amp;rsquo;t make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly(?), there&amp;rsquo;s very little Buddy himself in this issue &amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t find myself disappointed by that fact. The overall story is really well fleshed out by the focus on these peripheral characters impacted by his actions from earlier issues. It really makes the world come alive in a way that you don&amp;rsquo;t get with close examinations of only a comic&amp;rsquo;s core characters. For example: we don&amp;rsquo;t ever really have that many opportunities for the development of peripheral characters in &lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;/em&gt; whose lives were affected by the actions of Batman or his rogues&amp;rsquo; gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cable 011</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 19:58:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s review features Cable, a character that, along with Deadpool, has somehow managed to survive the &amp;lsquo;90s boom that spawned him. I was never fully sold on the &lt;strong&gt;extreme&lt;/strong&gt; nature of the Liefeld X-Force, but I suppose I get why Cable remains interesting to many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was, for some time, the consummate 1980s action hero ideal, a &amp;ldquo;mystery man&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;tactical badass&amp;rdquo; that speaks directly to the fantasies of the stereotypical superhero comic consumer. Plus, he has a cool eye scar and a metal arm! (Ironically, I think the Magog design for &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt;, meant to play on all the Cable-era tropes that Waid &amp;amp; Ross hated, is much more awesome.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since his introduction, Cable&amp;rsquo;s been fleshed out a lot more, and the &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; series that this issue (discussed more below) comes from has a really interesting initial story premise: Cable has to flee to the future with a special infant girl, who is supposed to one day be the mutant messiah, and he tries to keep her alive while mutant cop/ethnic cleanser Bishop chases them both through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; #011 features an image of young Hope Summers in front of a white background, where she is dressed in an adorably ill-fitting X-Men uniform resembling Cable&amp;rsquo;s outfit (complete with giant shoulder pads) and wielding an oversized gun of some sort &amp;hellip; maybe a sawed-off gatling gun or something?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Cable-011.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Cable 011, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cable issue 011&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Okay, so when this issue begins, Cable has taken Hope (although in the comic Hope does not yet have a name) to an oasis-like settlement in a post-apocalyptic hellscape populated by vicious insectoid beings (called &amp;ldquo;the cockroach army&amp;rdquo; by Cable). Cable has a wife named Hope, met during one of the time-jumps made by Cable and the child he&amp;rsquo;s protecting, who ends up dying during a bandit attack, and so he names the child Hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining humans devise a bomb or gas or something to destroy the cockroaches, but Cable worries they&amp;rsquo;ll kill the humans too. So, he and Hope jump a hundred years into the future, surrounded by salt flats and human skeletons. The image (a two-page spread) is actually pretty incredible, the clean art style juxtaposed with the apocalyptic horror and Hope&amp;rsquo;s vomiting from the experience of sliding through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: this issue, more than many before it in this series, really calls to mind the Futurama episode where Fry, Professor Farnsworth, and Bender use a time machine and witness the end of the universe. (Like the Futurama crew, Cable can only jump into the future.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I enjoyed this series (picking up the first twenty or so issues from a dollar bin) in part because Cable is depicted stylistically so far from his Liefeld origins: no ludicrous thigh pouches, consistent realistic proportions, and his relationship with the child Hope is really believable: he&amp;rsquo;s clearly come around from seeing this as a duty put upon him to a genuine parental concern for her well-being. It&amp;rsquo;s like an X-Men version of &lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt;, and I mean that as a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one page, there&amp;rsquo;s a moment that &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be a reference to Philip K. Dick&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Second Variety&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Cable hunts a wolf that turns out to be a machine with a wolf&amp;rsquo;s external appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, the focus on Cable and Hope is really quite enjoyable. The conflict is almost entirely on Cable trying to decide what sorts of details to tell Hope about the past and her potential destiny (along with details about child development and puberty) rather than on forcing gunfights and explosions and whatnot into the mix. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of characterization here, and maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the sheer lack of possible distractions that has made it possible or my interest in depressing apocalyptic wasteland stories, but &amp;hellip; yeah, I dig this issue. This Cable is so much more interesting than when he was a mix of Kyle Reese and the Terminator but with no real backstory to lean on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of Kung Fu 071</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 23:21:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shang-Chi, the master of kung fu, is one of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s greatest martial arts characters, and one who was born during the company&amp;rsquo;s 1970s-era efforts to exploit the martial arts movie craze (although I admit I&amp;rsquo;m a bigger fan of Shang-Chi frenemy Shen Kuei, &amp;ldquo;the Cat&amp;rdquo;). This series is definitely a reflection of that time, and it&amp;rsquo;s Doug Moench&amp;rsquo;s magnum opus (although, sadly, this particular issue doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature Paul Gulacy, whose work meshed excellently with Moench, although the artist here, Mike Zeck, also does a solid job with the kung fu/espionage style the book goes for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the character&amp;rsquo;s world even more incredible, it&amp;rsquo;s filled with a cast of pulp homages: Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s father is Fu Manchu (although Marvel lost the rights to the character, so he&amp;rsquo;s not actually called that&amp;mdash;or any other&amp;mdash;name any more, instead referred to by vague descriptions), and Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s super-spy BFF, MI-6 agent Clive Reston, is &lt;em&gt;heavily implied&lt;/em&gt; to be the son of James Bond, while his mentor Sir Denis Nayland-Smith (an enemy of Fu Manchu&amp;rsquo;s) is suggested to be a relative of Sherlock Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so &lt;em&gt;MoKF&lt;/em&gt; 071. This issue has an incredible cover&amp;mdash;Shang-Chi is posed ready for a fight, barefoot and clad only in his red pants and bandana, in front of a giant yin-yang symbol. The background is also a massive jigsaw puzzle whose pieces begin to fall apart near the bottom of the image. (There&amp;rsquo;s a jigsaw motif running through this issue, just FYI.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Master of Kung Fu 071, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Master of Kung Fu issue 071&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue opens with a fantastic two-page spread wherein Shang-Chi recaps a bunch of recent storylines, all laid out as interlocking jigsaw pieces. The next several pages explore Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s coming to terms with various close relationships (a love interest, Juliette; even more intense and long-term love interest, Leiko Wu; and BFF Clive Reston) and the changes that had occurred in regards to each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, this issue then segues into a conversation scene while Shang-Chi and Leiko (who&amp;rsquo;s been putting together a jigsaw puzzle of a yin-yang symbol) share a pizza. After they eat, they visit a martial arts studio and engage in a friendly bout to exercise &amp;amp; train, making an impressive enough showing that all the other individuals present stop to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After they go to a movie and return home, the comic ends on a cliffhanger where a battered Sir Denis bursts into their home, seeking help with supposed corruption in the MI-6 agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not a tremendous amount of action in this comic, but that&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing. Shang-Chi has always been depicted as an extremely introspective character who seeks a path to enlightenment and peace with every action he takes and every phenomenon he witnesses. That he reflects on a number of the major plots in the comic so far is a totally human move (in addition to having the practical effect of catching up newer readers to the series&amp;rsquo; progression). I found myself nodding along, persuaded by Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s line of reasoning as he attempted to make sense of the insanity that is life in a pulp comic book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt; is a series that I try to collect through dollar bins; I know that Marvel has recently begun reprinting the series in massive omnibus form, but, given its content and focus, the comic really seems best experienced when one is exposed to the feel and smell of crappy older comic paper. It just seems appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doom Patrol 041 (1987)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doom-Patrol-041/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 23:51:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doom-Patrol-041/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite expect an issue of &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; to appear so soon, but here we are. Possibly the single greatest comic run I own, by the author whose work(s) I try to follow more than any other (Grant Morrison). (As an aside, I had the help of a friend in completing this run some time ago, and I am reminded that I still need to pay her back for her help in doing so.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doom Patrol, as characters, have always fascinated me in the way that the X-Men tend to for most readers. They&amp;rsquo;re outcasts who fight against the banality of the status quo and champion individuals and groups on the margins of society. Of course, the original Doom Patrol team managed to out-hero the X-Men by giving their lives for a small fishing village. And the characters stayed dead for some time! (This is unheard of in comics, unless you were Ben Parker or Bucky Barnes &amp;hellip; at least until the early 2000s.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, having Grant Morrison provide his take on the Doom Patrol is/was positively awesome, especially since this take involves surrealism, dada, comics deconstructionism, and a fundamental plot-line later ripped off by M. Night Shyamalan for his movie &lt;em&gt;Unbreakable&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; 041, by Simon Bisley (I think? I feel pretty sure about this, since he loves to do hyper-detailed elbows), is suitable for the comic: there&amp;rsquo;s a naked, faceless woman (a character named Rhea, who appears within the issue) floating above a naked, muscular humanoid with a tail and visible spine nearly protruding through its skin. To the right of these figures are various skulls and skeletal limbs; at least one of the skulls appears to be screwed or bolted to some mechanical/industrial apparatus.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doom-Patrol-041.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doom Patrol 041, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doom Patrol issue 041&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, the issue begins in a typically cryptic Morrison way, with a woman visiting &amp;ldquo;one of the five&amp;rdquo; lost and found offices that are special in some way. They contain lost memories, confidences, innocence, etc. The woman visiting the office is looking for Flex Mentallo, a comic character lost since the 1950s. I love Flex Mentallo, so I&amp;rsquo;m stoked to see if he makes an appearance in this issue, although his &amp;ldquo;first appearance&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually occur until the next issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robotman is in his &amp;ldquo;spider legs&amp;rdquo; phase in this issue, which was another neat twist on the character&amp;mdash;I liked this aesthetic more than his giant shoulder-pads during this run. I always appreciated Robotman for his sleek look; the shoulders scream &amp;lsquo;90s and it&amp;rsquo;s just not a great look. That said, I do appreciate that it&amp;rsquo;s a kind of expression of his efforts to find a personal style, since he&amp;rsquo;s basically a disembodied brain in a mobile tin can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot of this issue is a climax to a multi-issue storyline. Here, the anathematicians face off against the agent of the kaleidoscope in a battle of &lt;em&gt;potlatch&lt;/em&gt; (having had the concept introduced to them by the Negative Man) wherein they take turns destroying more and more important &amp;amp; valuable symbols of their ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Robotman, on the advice of Rhea, plants a flower and a giant angel (in the form of a massive rock with three or more human faces on which sits a city) comes to life and is apparently named Balzizras. It had created a world devoid of creativity, being able to imagine only simple conflict between those warring ideologies. Now, the flower allows for free imagination: &amp;ldquo;The creator&amp;rsquo;s come down &lt;strong&gt;among&lt;/strong&gt; you, not as a &lt;strong&gt;judge&lt;/strong&gt;, but as a sort of imaginative energy. Pretty neat, huh?&amp;rdquo; When Robotman asks if it&amp;rsquo;s really an angel, Rhea replies: &amp;ldquo;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s either &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; or the psychic projection of a woman called &lt;strong&gt;Ilse Krauss&lt;/strong&gt; who&amp;rsquo;s lying in a hospital bed in &lt;strong&gt;Bremen&lt;/strong&gt;, dying of brain cancer. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to be sure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of concept that I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; reading about in comics. Morrison knows exactly how to tap into the part of my brain that drinks in the most incredible high-concept ideas spitballed in half-formed states, since they allow the reader the opportunity to imagine how the ideas might be realized. The conflict is resolved by heroes who are willing to consider completely absurd and seemingly unrelated solutions, and the payoffs are frequently not returns to the status quo but radical paradigm shifts in which the characters (and the reader, hopefully?) develop further via the enlightenment they&amp;rsquo;ve gained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much every storyline in Morrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; run achieves this without disappointing; the same can be said of his &lt;em&gt;JLA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;All-Star Superman&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;New X-Men&lt;/em&gt; runs (maybe not quite to this extent with &lt;em&gt;New X-Men&lt;/em&gt;, perhaps). It&amp;rsquo;s this desire to use the superhero mythos as a way to promote internal philosophical development on the part of the reader that makes me appreciate Morrison&amp;rsquo;s writing. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting when superheroes are taken seriously (a la &lt;em&gt;Watchmen&lt;/em&gt;), but it&amp;rsquo;s even more interesting to me when the concept of the superhero is taken philosophically and explored as a potential humanist value system (or at least the vehicle for one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yeah. I love the Doom Patrol and I love this issue&amp;rsquo;s story as an awe-inspiring demonstration of superheroes through those characters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>