<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/doctor-strange/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/doctor-strange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme 016 (1988)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 23:04:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps fitting that the first comic randomly selected to serve as a review post is a &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comic, since I have long adored the character. (I used to have more comics featuring Doctor Strange than any other, but I&amp;rsquo;ve since collected far more Green Lantern-related comics &amp;hellip; so expect a few of those to make appearances.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover, shown below, is suitably interesting: Baron Blood has thrown(?) or is otherwise causing Doctor Strange to be flung upside-down through the night sky, off of some jungle or forest cliff, with a large, full moon illuminating everything from the background. Baron Blood has some seriously long underarm wings here, like he learned about Batman&amp;rsquo;s cape or something.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue, titled &amp;ldquo;Love and Haiti&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (classic Marvel pun?). There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love: Roy Thomas (partially) on writing duties. A cast that includes Morbius, Marie LaVeau the &amp;ldquo;Voodoo Queen,&amp;rdquo; Baron Blood, and Brother Voodoo. It is, unfortunately, the middle point of a five-issue arc, so there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; backstory to catch up readers, but other details are left unstated&amp;ndash;although I never felt like I was really lost at any point. This issue (from 1990) is well before the era of plot decompression for the sake of publishing an eventual TPB collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art by Jackson Guice seems very &amp;ldquo;workhorse&amp;rdquo; in comparison to the early &amp;lsquo;90s Image style explosion, but I appreciate it now in a way that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could have at age 9 (not that I owned it then&amp;ndash;I think I picked up this issue in a lot of &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comics around 2001). Stephen Strange looks like an older doctor. Poses seem relatively realistic, save for when characters/phenomena suggest they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be (like someone floating upside-down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awkward moment: during a fight with vampires&amp;ndash;in an alley in Port-au-Prince, of course&amp;ndash;Morgana Blessing calls out both to &amp;ldquo;Mr. Drumm&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dr. Morbius&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; poor Brother Voodoo getting &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; credit for his educational credentials until he took up the mantle of Sorcerer Supreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome moment: Dracula making a &lt;em&gt;phone call&lt;/em&gt; in order to set up an attack on an enemy. This is easily the best dialogue of the issue (the panel art is similarly wonderful):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dracula: &amp;ldquo;I want you to set a &lt;strong&gt;trap&lt;/strong&gt; for my accursed descendant, &lt;strong&gt;Frank Drake&lt;/strong&gt;, upon his arrival in Brazil. You will be richly rewarded.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danny Summers: &amp;ldquo;You bet your bat I will, Drac! &lt;strong&gt;Danny Summers&lt;/strong&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t do &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, I found myself really annoyed that Baron Blood, despite having an absolutely fantastic character name, has a pretty weak schtick&amp;ndash;or, at least, they really play up his weaknesses in this issue. If he changed up his costume&amp;rsquo;s color scheme, he might seem more intimidating. If he seemed like more of a mastermind, he might seem more dangerous. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t know: has Baron Blood ever been the big threat in a horror-oriented story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I think Doctor Strange casts a total of three spells in this issue, and none of them really plays up the surreal trip that Ditko originally demonstrated could (and &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;) be at the center of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s arcane/occult aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with luck my future reviews will become more coherent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>