<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Namor on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/namor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Namor on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:58:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/namor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Namor, The Sub-Mariner 014</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Namor-014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:58:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Namor-014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Namor, The Sub-Mariner&lt;/em&gt; was the first comic for which I ever had a subscription (my subscription was from issue 18-29). I don&amp;rsquo;t recall all the details about this, but I know that we had some sort of postal issue that prevented me from getting an issue or two initially, so my dad and I called Marvel. It turned out that they were having a Christmas party at the time, and Stan Lee himself picked up the phone. He very kindly took our info to get things sorted out, and I got my twelve issues of &lt;em&gt;Namor&lt;/em&gt; and the appropriate annual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comic &amp;hellip; Namor has always been a super-interesting character to me (Marvel&amp;rsquo;s first &amp;ldquo;mutant,&amp;rdquo; a Golden Age character, a potential voice for ecological issues, the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest eyebrows, etc.) but I cannot &lt;strong&gt;stand&lt;/strong&gt; John Bryne&amp;rsquo;s art. Everyone has the same face. Everyone has the same body. (I feel the same way about Mark Bagley&amp;rsquo;s art, as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover for issue 014&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Namor-014.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Namor, The Sub-Mariner 014, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Namor, The Sub-Mariner issue 014&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue begins with Phoebe Marrs, jerk CEO, chewing out her board during a meeting and then firing her assistant when said assistant makes an under-the-breath comment about Phoebe being a &amp;ldquo;lucky girl&amp;rdquo; when Namor comes to visit her. Not really the best way to win over a reader, since we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be interested in Namor&amp;rsquo;s romantic relationship with Phoebe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Phoebe and Namor go to visit her son, whose existence is a secret and who lives in a house that &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; knows about. What the hell, Phoebe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a quick interlude in Atlantis, where we learn that Namor&amp;rsquo;s former (and dead) wife, the Lady Dorma, has turned out to be alive! (Spoiler: in a later issue, it turns out she&amp;rsquo;s actually one of many clones that a crazy Atlantean scientist created.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s a scene with Danny Rand (who&amp;rsquo;s supposedly dead, if I recall, from the end of the &lt;em&gt;Power Man and Iron Fist&lt;/em&gt; series) and also Ka-Zar (and Zabu, his sabretooth tiger). They&amp;rsquo;re up to something obviously sinister&amp;ndash;maybe destroying the environment in the Savage Land or something?&amp;ndash;but I find myself completely uninterested in this story. (We&amp;rsquo;re only at the halfway point here, too. Not good.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Phoebe&amp;rsquo;s secret house, Phoebe tells Namor about how she came to have a secret son. But then a giant griffin flies in out of the air. (I think it&amp;rsquo;s actually a manticore.) Apparently, Namor and the griffin have fought before, but I seriously do not remember this character &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Namor and the griffin tussle, and then Namor domesticates it somehow and Phoebe declares her love for Namor, kissing him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue was a &lt;em&gt;slog&lt;/em&gt;. Unfortunately, from what I remember of my subscription to this series, the next dozen or so issues aren&amp;rsquo;t any better &amp;hellip; which is a shame, because Namor the character is fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>