<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 22:44:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange 072</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 22:44:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, a note: my random number generator seems to keep pointing me to issues numbering in the 70s. An interesting trend so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so, more Doctor Strange! And this time, it&amp;rsquo;s from the 1970s-80s series (a predecessor to the series discussed in my earlier Doctor Strange review).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; #072 shows Doctor Strange, with an absolutely &lt;em&gt;metal&lt;/em&gt; beard, wrapped in the tentacles of some green Lovecraftian creature whose limbs and cilia are writhing about. Doctor Strange gestures with one hand to fire some pink energy at his opponent.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-072.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange 072, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange issue 072&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story apparently starts in the Dark Dimension, or some related dimension, as we learn that Umar (Dormammu&amp;rsquo;s sister) is extracting tribute (aka taxes) in the form of mystic energy from her subjects. Technically, her tax collectors are doing this, on a platform in a public square that looks like it doubles as a French Revolution-era guillotine stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Strange has the best cloak/robe I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen him in (as he&amp;rsquo;s undercover or otherwise incognito, it appears), and&amp;ndash;again&amp;ndash;his hair looks &lt;em&gt;dope as hell&lt;/em&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to understate this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Doctor Strange and a handful of rebels storm the tax collector&amp;rsquo;s stage and collect the paid tributes (which have been condensed into small orbs or coins). Naturally, the citizens are a little pissed. There&amp;rsquo;s a really disturbing coincidental parallel to recent affairs, I think. Consider this exchange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Your rebellion&amp;rsquo;s public support is still somewhat lacking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rahl (a rebel)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;I know. The problem is that Umar has made herself appear benevolent and gracious to the people of the Dark Dimension. And after her brother&amp;rsquo;s reign of terror, there&amp;rsquo;s an illusion of good feeling in the realm. Things seem better to those who enjoy full citizenship, and so they&amp;rsquo;re afraid to support us. They fear that things might go back to the way they were!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Then your most urgent goal is to get the people to see Umar for what she really is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this goal is punctuated by an immediate need to fight some Mindless Ones, so at least there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of magical combat for the reader uninterested in interdimensional politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: the password chosen by Clea for entry into the rebels&amp;rsquo; stronghold is &amp;ldquo;Yo, Adriene &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s me, Rocky!&amp;rdquo; because&amp;ndash;according to Clea&amp;ndash;she chose an Earth-based pop culture reference (&amp;ldquo;things I remembered from your television, Stephen&amp;rdquo;) with the assumption that Umar&amp;rsquo;s subjects would never be able to guess it. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I&amp;rsquo;m shocked Doctor Strange has a television. I mean, he seems the type who&amp;rsquo;d be just snobby enough to pride himself in not watching TV and instead getting news updates and whatever from benevolent imp messengers or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, back on Earth, apparently Wong has to shut down the advances of Sara, an attractive girl who appears to be trying her best to engage Wong in a genuine relationship despite his unnerving dedication to being Doctor Strange&amp;rsquo;s manservant. (I mean, surely the good doctor would &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; his closest friend and companion to seek out intimate companionship, right?!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we&amp;rsquo;re only halfway through this story, and I have no clue what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Umar does her best, and fails, to spy on Strange through scrying magics. She does at least have a minor epiphany that he may be &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt;, including in her own dimension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Strange and Rahl go to visit the prisoner Orini&amp;ndash;Clea&amp;rsquo;s father, and Umar loyalist? I admit I am unfamiliar with this character&amp;ndash;and Strange uses the Eye of Agamotto to magically coerce Orini to give up the secrets of Umar&amp;rsquo;s army. Also, we learn the shocking revelation that Clea&amp;rsquo;s mother is Umar herself, having slept with Orini and abandoned the baby with him after Clea&amp;rsquo;s birth. Naturally, Clea is a bit taken aback by this when Strange informs her of the news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the rebels decide to storm one of Umar&amp;rsquo;s caravans (which looks &lt;em&gt;hilarious&lt;/em&gt; as an Oregon Trail-style wagon train with giant lizard beasts of burden and moving along on a Ditkoesque floating pathway), Clea frees her father to have a conversation with him as parent and child. He promptly beats the hell out of her, or so we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to assume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, there is an &lt;strong&gt;awesome&lt;/strong&gt; mystical moment where a caravan guard throws a canvas that, as it unfurls, opens a &amp;ldquo;portable warp&amp;rdquo; through which emerges a creature&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m guessing the monster from the cover&amp;ndash;that has a sharp beak and looks a lot like the alien from &lt;em&gt;Watchmen&lt;/em&gt; sans eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Doctor Strange tries to intervene and help the rebels, he is pulled &amp;hellip; somewhere else (it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say, since the background is all black) &amp;hellip; by &amp;ldquo;the outcasts,&amp;rdquo; creatures of various species, or so I gather (they have different hands/limbs, but we can&amp;rsquo;t see any of their facial features), who want to keep themselves hidden from Umar. When Strange says he wants to help regardless, they let him know it&amp;rsquo;s too late&amp;ndash;the rebels have fallen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a second cliffhanger moment, Orini arrives at Umar&amp;rsquo;s palace, bringing an unconscious Clea to his former lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story was dope, and is packed with some essential Doctor Strange plot tropes as well as moving along some character development for Clea and the residents of the Dark Dimension in general. I really wish Doctor Strange grew his hair out this way in the comics&amp;ndash;it really adds some metal/punk aesthetic to a character that is so often depicted as being very conservative in personal style, even despite the focus of his life&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demon 002</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Demon-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:35:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Demon-002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gone, gone, o form of man!
Rise the demon Etrigan!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etrigan the demon is a great character, even if Jack Kirby wasn&amp;rsquo;t really into it. Arthurian knight Jason Blood, cursed to inhabit the same body/space as Etrigan, a demon bound into Merlin&amp;rsquo;s service, has been developed as an incredibly cornerstone of DC&amp;rsquo;s supernatural/horror sphere of comics. (This was made most obvious in Alan Moore&amp;rsquo;s run on &lt;em&gt;Saga of the Swap Thing&lt;/em&gt;, where Etrigan&amp;rsquo;s rhyming was excellently elevated to a characteristic of Hell&amp;rsquo;s lieutenants.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;The Demon&lt;/em&gt; issue 002 shows Etrigan crouched on a stone archway, which is dripping water, in a town with a medieval aesthetic or a castle square at nighttime (as the moon is visible on the horizon), ready to pounce on a group of torch-wielding citizens and a uniformed inspector. The colors are muted grays save for Etrigan&amp;rsquo;s bold yellow and red as well as the group&amp;rsquo;s orange torch light. One of the citizens says, &amp;ldquo;See&amp;ndash;no one is here&amp;ndash;Inspector!&amp;rdquo; to which the inspector replies, &amp;ldquo;But I heard something!&amp;rdquo; Above the comic&amp;rsquo;s logo reads the following: &amp;ldquo;Part man&amp;ndash;part elemental fury! He stalks the dark of night in search of fearful enemies!&amp;rdquo; Finally, a caption at the bottom of the page reads, &amp;ldquo;In the den of witches lies the fate of man! Read BATH of FIRE!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Demon-002.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to The Demon issue 002, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Demon issue 002&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I am an unabashed Kirby fan, although this may be the least revelatory comment by a superhero comic book fan, ever. His dynamic poses, sprawling epic scenes, and incredible character designs are all fantastic in every way. While &lt;em&gt;The Demon&lt;/em&gt; as a series doesn&amp;rsquo;t come close to the full-blown opera of his Fourth World story (and I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed I don&amp;rsquo;t have the full &lt;em&gt;New Gods&lt;/em&gt; series), it nonetheless blows open some really intriguing doors in regards to telling mythical/chivalric/superhero stories&amp;ndash;with characters like Klarion the Witch-boy (first appearing in issue 7) being the perfect demonstration of that potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this issue begins with a trio of explorers looking for Merlin&amp;rsquo;s long-lost crypt at a place called Castle Branek, but the trio is immediately set upon by the armored henchment of Morgaine le Fey. Etrigan happens to be nearby and joins the fight, where he promptly wrecks shop until Morgaine herself hexes him so that he cannot intervene with her plans (to steal a spell from Merlin&amp;rsquo;s tomb so that she can regain vitality).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morgain transforms Etrigan back into his human form by reciting the proper incantation (&amp;ldquo;Vanish, vanish Etrigan! Return again in form of man!&amp;rdquo;), where Jason Blood is left to die &amp;hellip; except, of course, that he has an ace up his sleeve: Randu, a friend (who appears to be Sikh, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about this) with ESP. Randu sits at Blood&amp;rsquo;s house with two other colleagues admiring Blood&amp;rsquo;s portraits of his &amp;ldquo;ancestors&amp;rdquo; (obviously they&amp;rsquo;re all him in different historical eras).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Jason comes to, with the aid of the inspector trio from the first few pages, and he realizes Merlin&amp;rsquo;s tomb is itself the &amp;ldquo;Eternity Book&amp;rdquo; that contains his spells and secrets. Merlin&amp;rsquo;s magic activates some stone gargoyle guardians, but then Merlin himself appears in a kind of astral form to try and help him remember his fight against Morgaine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Morgaine prepares a ritual to rejuvenate herself, surrounded by dancing witches, Jason and the inspector storm in on horses to disrupt the proceedings. Morgaine summons a creature called the &amp;ldquo;Gorla,&amp;rdquo; a monster with the strength of ten men, who begins whipping Jason&amp;rsquo;s ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in his apartment, Randu is compelled to read the inscription on a painting of a knight that looks like Jason, summoning Etrigan to appear and take down the Gorla &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Morgaine&amp;rsquo;s servants. (She, of course, continues her ritual despite Etrigan blasting at her with hellfire-based explosions.) There&amp;rsquo;s a page of denouement but &amp;hellip; holy crap, all of that happened in under twenty-four pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comic is &lt;em&gt;AMAZING!&lt;/em&gt; There are so many questions I have, and the series as a whole only answers some of them. Kirby is clearly interested so much more in high-concept experimentation than with a Tolkienesque complete mythos, and&amp;ndash;at least as this sort of comic&amp;ndash;things work &lt;em&gt;so much better&lt;/em&gt; this way. How unique is Etrigan? What happens when he decides to fight back against Merlin? Exactly how much do Etrigan and Jason know about one another&amp;rsquo;s activities? (Hint: Etrigan knows much more than Jason does about the other.) Why does the token POC in this comic have psychic powers, and what does that tell us about this comic, or about Kirby (similarly: see &amp;ldquo;Vykin the Black&amp;rdquo; from &lt;em&gt;The Forever People&lt;/em&gt; for another case of racist POC usage/representation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, this comic could be awful and I&amp;rsquo;d still adore it because of how Kirby set it all up. Luckily, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about having made such a compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Comics Presents 072</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 17:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Comics Presents&lt;/em&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt;) is a series that interested me for the longest time: it was an anthology comic that tended to have four stories (each 8 pages) of varying length, by which I mean that one story might have 8-10 parts, another might have 4-6, another might only be a single 8-page story, and so on. So a reader was likely to get some really fascinating story turnover in any given collection of issues. When I was young, &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; introduced me to some characters that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever would have checked out otherwise, most notably (for me) Shang-Chi, but also minor characters like Stingray or the Collective Man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary story of many &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; issues featured Wolverine&amp;ndash;unsurprising, given his ability to sell pretty much any comic where he appeared on the cover. &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; 072, however, is important because it begins the tale of an incredibly significant part of Wolverine&amp;rsquo;s backstory, written &amp;amp; drawn by Barry Windsor-Smith: the Weapon X experiments that bonded adamantium to his skeleton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover for issue 072, like all of the &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; covers, is wraparound, with the primary (Wolverine) story featured on the front and the characters of the other three stories&amp;ndash;Daredevil, Shanna the She-Devil, and Red Wolf&amp;ndash;on the back. On the front half, Wolverine stands, the right half of his body covered by his classic brown-and-yellow suit, and his left half naked with a number of protruding spikes in preparation for his adamantium injections. Behind him is a large skull (likely his own), with similar spikes. Flames beneath a blank blue canvas comprise the background, layered (from top down) yellow, orange, and red. At the top of the page, below the comic&amp;rsquo;s title/logo, are the words: &amp;ldquo;Before Wolverine there was Weapon X.&amp;rdquo; On the back half of the cover, Shanna is posed crouching (with a caption box that declares &amp;ldquo;Her &lt;strong&gt;jungle&lt;/strong&gt; reeks of &lt;strong&gt;evil&lt;/strong&gt;, and SHANNA must &lt;strong&gt;confront&lt;/strong&gt; it.&amp;ldquo;), while Red Wolf leaps behind her, up and to her left (captioned &amp;ldquo;RED WOLF &lt;strong&gt;faces&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;death&lt;/strong&gt; of his &lt;strong&gt;partner Lobo&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;ldquo;). Behind her, down and to the right, Daredevil similarly jumps forward, swinging his billy club (caption: &amp;ldquo;DAREDEVIL is &lt;strong&gt;helpless&lt;/strong&gt; when things come to a &lt;strong&gt;head&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;New York&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;). What appears to be the back side of the large skull from the front cover looms behind the figures.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Marvel Comics Presents 072, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Marvel Comics Presents issue 072&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Weapon X&amp;rdquo; story in this issue must have been &lt;em&gt;ridiculously&lt;/em&gt; confusing to everyone when it initially came out, since it consists of three threads: (1) Wolverine down on his luck in the Yukon, drinking and getting in fights; (2) flashes of the Weapon X experiments themselves, provided without explanation/context; (3) panels of a scientist performing some sort of experiment that may or may not be (but almost certainly is) related to the Weapon X project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually pick up this issue until last year, but I already knew the general beats to this story. I have to say, in its serialized form, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed since there&amp;rsquo;s no real room for anything to breathe here (although I get that BWS is trying to let things unfold in a somewhat-similar manner to Logan&amp;rsquo;s ability to comprehend what happened to him). The art style and the narration is solid&amp;ndash;it does its job of leaving me wanting more. I&amp;rsquo;m just torn in both wanting more and not feeling like I really had &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; in this portion to really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shanna comic provided is part 5 of its story. I&amp;rsquo;m stoked going in because there&amp;rsquo;s Paul Gulacy art&amp;ndash;which I know is not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea but he is great at &amp;ldquo;realistic&amp;rdquo; comic stories (such as his run on &lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt;) so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting strong work here. Shanna and some others are tracking diamond smugglers and poachers through/near Tanzania. This part of the story does a really successful job at showing the violence and tragedy that accompanies such acts, and the cliffhanger&amp;ndash;where Shanna discovers someone (a local?) buried up to his neck amid massive anthills&amp;ndash;is creepy and suspenseful. Unlike with the Wolverine story, I have a clear sense of where this is going (without bringing in retrospective knowledge of the overall plot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to explain the Daredevil component (it&amp;rsquo;s part 4 and the final part, apparently, of a story). There&amp;rsquo;s apparently been a heat weave, and tensions are running high as people get frustrated. A woman named Ms. Pinkwater, whose defining feature is a Carmen Sandiego hat, is doing &amp;hellip; something? I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure it out. Anyway, apparently a bunch of people hold hands and sing or something, and it causes rain to fall and all tensions in the city to relax. Daredevil doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do anything other than read a handwritten note that asks him not to do anything. What the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Red Wolf story&amp;ndash;which I think is a standalone story&amp;ndash;is equally weak. Red Wolf begins in a lodge, ruminating on the loss of his wolf partner Lobo, while a truck full of drunks look for something to hunt. They eventually discover a mother wolf feeding her cubs and proceed to kill almost all of them (save one), when Red Wolf finally acts. Even then, he&amp;rsquo;s nearly taken out until one of the hunters decides they&amp;rsquo;ve gone too far and has a standoff with his buddy. Red Wolf, meanwhile, takes the surviving cub (presumably to raise himself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this issue is a decent representative for &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; in general: there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting experimentation happening and some solid, compelling story work &amp;hellip; but there are also stinkers that don&amp;rsquo;t feel really worthwhile or well-realized. Does the former cancel out the latter? Yes and no&amp;ndash;certainly enough, for me, to not absolutely hate the series, but not so much that I forget nostalgia is a big part of my enjoyment of this series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namor, The Sub-Mariner 014</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Namor-014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:58:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Namor-014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Namor, The Sub-Mariner&lt;/em&gt; was the first comic for which I ever had a subscription (my subscription was from issue 18-29). I don&amp;rsquo;t recall all the details about this, but I know that we had some sort of postal issue that prevented me from getting an issue or two initially, so my dad and I called Marvel. It turned out that they were having a Christmas party at the time, and Stan Lee himself picked up the phone. He very kindly took our info to get things sorted out, and I got my twelve issues of &lt;em&gt;Namor&lt;/em&gt; and the appropriate annual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comic &amp;hellip; Namor has always been a super-interesting character to me (Marvel&amp;rsquo;s first &amp;ldquo;mutant,&amp;rdquo; a Golden Age character, a potential voice for ecological issues, the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest eyebrows, etc.) but I cannot &lt;strong&gt;stand&lt;/strong&gt; John Bryne&amp;rsquo;s art. Everyone has the same face. Everyone has the same body. (I feel the same way about Mark Bagley&amp;rsquo;s art, as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover for issue 014 shows Namor, a woman, and a small child in a living room or den, from the over-the-shoulder perspective of a creature we only see from the back. It has a golden mane, a spiked collar, large hands with claws, and a pair of wings. There&amp;rsquo;s broken glass on the floor under Namor et al.&amp;rsquo;s feet.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Namor-014.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Namor, The Sub-Mariner 014, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Namor, The Sub-Mariner issue 014&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue begins with Phoebe Marrs, jerk CEO, chewing out her board during a meeting and then firing her assistant when said assistant makes an under-the-breath comment about Phoebe being a &amp;ldquo;lucky girl&amp;rdquo; when Namor comes to visit her. Not really the best way to win over a reader, since we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be interested in Namor&amp;rsquo;s romantic relationship with Phoebe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Phoebe and Namor go to visit her son, whose existence is a secret and who lives in a house that &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; knows about. What the hell, Phoebe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a quick interlude in Atlantis, where we learn that Namor&amp;rsquo;s former (and dead) wife, the Lady Dorma, has turned out to be alive! (Spoiler: in a later issue, it turns out she&amp;rsquo;s actually one of many clones that a crazy Atlantean scientist created.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s a scene with Danny Rand (who&amp;rsquo;s supposedly dead, if I recall, from the end of the &lt;em&gt;Power Man and Iron Fist&lt;/em&gt; series) and also Ka-Zar (and Zabu, his sabretooth tiger). They&amp;rsquo;re up to something obviously sinister&amp;ndash;maybe destroying the environment in the Savage Land or something?&amp;ndash;but I find myself completely uninterested in this story. (We&amp;rsquo;re only at the halfway point here, too. Not good.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Phoebe&amp;rsquo;s secret house, Phoebe tells Namor about how she came to have a secret son. But then a giant griffin flies in out of the air. (I think it&amp;rsquo;s actually a manticore.) Apparently, Namor and the griffin have fought before, but I seriously do not remember this character &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Namor and the griffin tussle, and then Namor domesticates it somehow and Phoebe declares her love for Namor, kissing him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue was a &lt;em&gt;slog&lt;/em&gt;. Unfortunately, from what I remember of my subscription to this series, the next dozen or so issues aren&amp;rsquo;t any better &amp;hellip; which is a shame, because Namor the character is fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal Man 076</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 23:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first Vertigo post for this blog is also the first &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, Animal Man. Such a great character raised out of mediocre beginnings. Without getting &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; mired in details, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to say that Buddy Baker&amp;ndash;Animal Man&amp;ndash;can tap into the abilities of animals and make use thereof to fight injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, unlike most superheroes, he has a family (a wife, Ellen, and two children, Cliff and Maxine). This is important, because the central conflict in Buddy&amp;rsquo;s life is the tug-of-war that &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt; occurs between his desire to live a normal life with his family and his desire to use his powers in the best and most effective way possible (often to try and raise awareness about animal rights and ecological issues). This tug-of-war has led Buddy to some interesting places (for the reader, at least; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much ruined his life over and over again). At least, this is what happened to the character in the first volume of his own series; Grant Morrison set up this model and pretty much every author working on &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; since has followed suit, although they may have tweaked some specifics here and there, like looking at how Ellen deals with her completely absurd life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, Buddy went through a significant metamorphosis that left him in the body of a chimerical creature with the attributes of all kinds of animals, and he decided to use his new appearance to help found a church that would worship his daughter Maxine and her even-more-powerful animal-related powers&amp;ndash;the church is even called &amp;ldquo;The Life-Power Church of Maxine&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;set up half-seriously and half-deceptively by the Bakers and their closest friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to issue 076, then, shows Buddy in his animal-avatar form flying through a red sky over what appears to be the upraised arms/hands of an angry mob, given the tools and guns held aloft by those arms.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Animal-Man-076.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Animal Man 076, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Animal Man issue 076&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story begins with several pages narrated via in-universe comics drawn by budding cartoonist Cliff Baker, who lets us know that the Life-Power Church is on its way to Montana in search of some promised land where people and animals can live in harmony. They&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with some hunters and other critics along the way, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cartoon has been mailed to Ellen, who&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; with her family but instead with a small group of lesbian activists (that&amp;rsquo;s not a snarky, bigoted comment by me&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s how the characters were introduced and how they continue to be portrayed; a few issues before this one, Ellen notes to Buddy that she&amp;rsquo;s felt a connection growing between her and Sarah, one of the activists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the Life-Power Church is facing off against the National Guard in Nebraska (there&amp;rsquo;s references to a &amp;ldquo;plague&amp;rdquo; that has affected a number of people across the country, where they dream of themselves as animals running wild on human society), and Ellen&amp;rsquo;s conflicted between staying put with Sarah and being there in Nebraska for her family; the conversation in this scene does a pretty solid job of demonstrating various characters&amp;rsquo; takes on the situation so that no one seems to have the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;most correct&amp;rdquo; answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an equally intriguing scene between Maxine and a follower of the LFC (Ray, given the Church name &amp;ldquo;Manta Ray&amp;rdquo;) who&amp;rsquo;s secretly a government agent awaiting the order to assassinate Maxine, Buddy, or both. But she finds herself questioning her ability to murder a child if so commanded when she takes an impromptu romp/bath in a nearby river with Maxine and a throng of animal companions/guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray&amp;rsquo;s plot intertwines with that of an older man named Jack who&amp;rsquo;s looking to save his son from the LFC cult. Ray ends up getting caught by some locals who decide to rape her in the corn fields. Jack saves her, figuring that she can&amp;rsquo;t have made any poor decisions (that is, it&amp;rsquo;s not her fault she was caught and is being tortured, it&amp;rsquo;s the Church&amp;rsquo;s) that his own son didn&amp;rsquo;t make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly(?), there&amp;rsquo;s very little Buddy himself in this issue &amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t find myself disappointed by that fact. The overall story is really well fleshed out by the focus on these peripheral characters impacted by his actions from earlier issues. It really makes the world come alive in a way that you don&amp;rsquo;t get with close examinations of only a comic&amp;rsquo;s core characters. For example: we don&amp;rsquo;t ever really have that many opportunities for the development of peripheral characters in &lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;/em&gt; whose lives were affected by the actions of Batman or his rogues&amp;rsquo; gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice League Europe 008</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:10:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JUSTICE LEAGUE EUROPE! Possibly the greatest Europe-based superhero team from one of the big two comics companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Justice League Europe&lt;/em&gt; / &lt;em&gt;Justice League International&lt;/em&gt; were incredible series in the late 80s/early 90s that really embraced the goofiness of shining a spotlight on a band of B- and C-list heroes. Keith Giffen and Bart Sears worked so well together to make the comic so believable and staunchly ridiculous at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JLE featured two of my favorite DC characters: Animal Man and Metamorpho. Ralph Dibny is also great (and his partnership with his wife really should be emulated more, in terms of having a hero in a healthy committed relationship).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to this issue is suitably dramatic and goofy: members of the JLE and JLI (from left to right, at varying distances from the &amp;ldquo;camera&amp;rdquo;: Batman, Rocket Red, Captain Atom, Booster Gold, Mister Miracle, Fire, Metamorpho, Guy Gardner, Animal Man, Flash, Martian Manhunter, Power Girl, and Blue Beetle) stand, with their backs to the viewer, in the middle of a small town square, with moutnains looming in the background. There&amp;rsquo;s a large and ominous dark shadow spreading in the space between the mountains and the town. Blue Beetle says, &amp;ldquo;Uh oh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Justice-League-Europe-008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Justice League Europe #008, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Justice League Europe issue 008&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first page is a perfect demonstration of Keith Giffen&amp;rsquo;s strengths: Linda Strauss, a short-term Doctor Fate, is engaged in self-reflective exposition about her fears &amp;amp; doubts regarding taking on the Doctor Fate mantle. It&amp;rsquo;s engaging, interesting, and ends with a joke, as Giffen tends to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Order &lt;strong&gt;created&lt;/strong&gt; him [the Grey Man, antagonist for this story] &amp;hellip; Order&amp;rsquo;s responsible for the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s gone &lt;strong&gt;berserk&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;abusing&lt;/strong&gt; his power&amp;ndash;but if &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t do anything to &lt;strong&gt;stop&lt;/strong&gt; him&amp;ndash;then I guess the job&amp;rsquo;s fallen to &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;. (quietly) I think I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be sick.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the JLE and JLI stand off in a Stagg-owned compound against a horde of, and I&amp;rsquo;m serious, &amp;ldquo;zombie-vampires.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Zombie-vampires.&lt;/em&gt; This story would probably be absolutely terrible if everyone involved didn&amp;rsquo;t wholly embrace the ridiculous nature of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they finally decide to storm the compound, the zombie-vampires somehow grant energy to the Grey Man, a character who looks like a creepy uncle but manages to grow larger than the building when fueled somehow by the zombie-vampires. I remember nothing about the Grey Man while I reread this, but he has a vendetta against the forces of Order and Chaos (I assume he&amp;rsquo;s taking the &amp;ldquo;grey&amp;rdquo; middle ground between the two).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the Spectre shows up &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the embodied agents of Order and Chaos&amp;mdash;who are now united against their common foe. They promptly lobotomize him, and he&amp;rsquo;s left to wander mindlessly through the world. According to the Spectre: &amp;ldquo;[H]e will walk this world, collecting &lt;strong&gt;dream-essence&lt;/strong&gt; from the dead &amp;hellip; empty-headed, empty-hearted &amp;hellip; beyond pain &amp;hellip; beyond even &lt;strong&gt;loneliness&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; (Seriously?) The Grey Man is last seen just wandering off through an electrical fence and into the wilderness. I guess he doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to eat or anything. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad there&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;two entire super-hero teams&lt;/em&gt; nearby who could try and help him get super-institutionalized for everyone&amp;rsquo;s safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I forget what a given artist&amp;rsquo;s art style is like until I have the comic in front of me. At no point in my life have I forgotten Bart Sears&amp;rsquo; penchant to make everyone top-heavy musclemen with a billion points of light/shadow dynamic to demonstrate textures and contours. I have nostalgic love for it in &lt;em&gt;JLE&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;JLI&lt;/em&gt;, but I would not be able to abide it in probably any other comic (Sears&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;X-O Manowar&lt;/em&gt; art, for example, is so off-putting to me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, everyone who appears on the cover manages to get at least one line of dialogue, probably to keep this comic from being 96 pages long every month. I love that Grant Morrison busts on this balancing act in the pages of &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; when Buddy is asked to recognize the fact that he really only ever shows up in &lt;em&gt;JLE&lt;/em&gt; to say/do one or two things in any given adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I want to read more of my Giffen-era &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt; back issues to enjoy the best friendly relationship DC&amp;rsquo;s ever had: Blue Beetle &amp;amp; Booster Gold. (Sorry, it&amp;rsquo;s superior to Batman &amp;amp; Superman&amp;rsquo;s longtime partnership.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cable 011</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 19:58:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s review features Cable, a character that, along with Deadpool, has somehow managed to survive the &amp;lsquo;90s boom that spawned him. I was never fully sold on the &lt;strong&gt;extreme&lt;/strong&gt; nature of the Liefeld X-Force, but I suppose I get why Cable remains interesting to many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was, for some time, the consummate 1980s action hero ideal, a &amp;ldquo;mystery man&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;tactical badass&amp;rdquo; that speaks directly to the fantasies of the stereotypical superhero comic consumer. Plus, he has a cool eye scar and a metal arm! (Ironically, I think the Magog design for &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt;, meant to play on all the Cable-era tropes that Waid &amp;amp; Ross hated, is much more awesome.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since his introduction, Cable&amp;rsquo;s been fleshed out a lot more, and the &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; series that this issue (discussed more below) comes from has a really interesting initial story premise: Cable has to flee to the future with a special infant girl, who is supposed to one day be the mutant messiah, and he tries to keep her alive while mutant cop/ethnic cleanser Bishop chases them both through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; #011 features an image of young Hope Summers in front of a white background, where she is dressed in an adorably ill-fitting X-Men uniform resembling Cable&amp;rsquo;s outfit (complete with giant shoulder pads) and wielding an oversized gun of some sort &amp;hellip; maybe a sawed-off gatling gun or something?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Cable-011.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Cable 011, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cable issue 011&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Okay, so when this issue begins, Cable has taken Hope (although in the comic Hope does not yet have a name) to an oasis-like settlement in a post-apocalyptic hellscape populated by vicious insectoid beings (called &amp;ldquo;the cockroach army&amp;rdquo; by Cable). Cable has a wife named Hope, met during one of the time-jumps made by Cable and the child he&amp;rsquo;s protecting, who ends up dying during a bandit attack, and so he names the child Hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining humans devise a bomb or gas or something to destroy the cockroaches, but Cable worries they&amp;rsquo;ll kill the humans too. So, he and Hope jump a hundred years into the future, surrounded by salt flats and human skeletons. The image (a two-page spread) is actually pretty incredible, the clean art style juxtaposed with the apocalyptic horror and Hope&amp;rsquo;s vomiting from the experience of sliding through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: this issue, more than many before it in this series, really calls to mind the Futurama episode where Fry, Professor Farnsworth, and Bender use a time machine and witness the end of the universe. (Like the Futurama crew, Cable can only jump into the future.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I enjoyed this series (picking up the first twenty or so issues from a dollar bin) in part because Cable is depicted stylistically so far from his Liefeld origins: no ludicrous thigh pouches, consistent realistic proportions, and his relationship with the child Hope is really believable: he&amp;rsquo;s clearly come around from seeing this as a duty put upon him to a genuine parental concern for her well-being. It&amp;rsquo;s like an X-Men version of &lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt;, and I mean that as a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one page, there&amp;rsquo;s a moment that &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be a reference to Philip K. Dick&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Second Variety&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Cable hunts a wolf that turns out to be a machine with a wolf&amp;rsquo;s external appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, the focus on Cable and Hope is really quite enjoyable. The conflict is almost entirely on Cable trying to decide what sorts of details to tell Hope about the past and her potential destiny (along with details about child development and puberty) rather than on forcing gunfights and explosions and whatnot into the mix. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of characterization here, and maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the sheer lack of possible distractions that has made it possible or my interest in depressing apocalyptic wasteland stories, but &amp;hellip; yeah, I dig this issue. This Cable is so much more interesting than when he was a mix of Kyle Reese and the Terminator but with no real backstory to lean on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of Kung Fu 071</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 23:21:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shang-Chi, the master of kung fu, is one of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s greatest martial arts characters, and one who was born during the company&amp;rsquo;s 1970s-era efforts to exploit the martial arts movie craze (although I admit I&amp;rsquo;m a bigger fan of Shang-Chi frenemy Shen Kuei, &amp;ldquo;the Cat&amp;rdquo;). This series is definitely a reflection of that time, and it&amp;rsquo;s Doug Moench&amp;rsquo;s magnum opus (although, sadly, this particular issue doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature Paul Gulacy, whose work meshed excellently with Moench, although the artist here, Mike Zeck, also does a solid job with the kung fu/espionage style the book goes for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the character&amp;rsquo;s world even more incredible, it&amp;rsquo;s filled with a cast of pulp homages: Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s father is Fu Manchu (although Marvel lost the rights to the character, so he&amp;rsquo;s not actually called that&amp;mdash;or any other&amp;mdash;name any more, instead referred to by vague descriptions), and Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s super-spy BFF, MI-6 agent Clive Reston, is &lt;em&gt;heavily implied&lt;/em&gt; to be the son of James Bond, while his mentor Sir Denis Nayland-Smith (an enemy of Fu Manchu&amp;rsquo;s) is suggested to be a relative of Sherlock Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so &lt;em&gt;MoKF&lt;/em&gt; 071. This issue has an incredible cover&amp;mdash;Shang-Chi is posed ready for a fight, barefoot and clad only in his red pants and bandana, in front of a giant yin-yang symbol. The background is also a massive jigsaw puzzle whose pieces begin to fall apart near the bottom of the image. (There&amp;rsquo;s a jigsaw motif running through this issue, just FYI.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Master of Kung Fu 071, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Master of Kung Fu issue 071&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue opens with a fantastic two-page spread wherein Shang-Chi recaps a bunch of recent storylines, all laid out as interlocking jigsaw pieces. The next several pages explore Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s coming to terms with various close relationships (a love interest, Juliette; even more intense and long-term love interest, Leiko Wu; and BFF Clive Reston) and the changes that had occurred in regards to each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, this issue then segues into a conversation scene while Shang-Chi and Leiko (who&amp;rsquo;s been putting together a jigsaw puzzle of a yin-yang symbol) share a pizza. After they eat, they visit a martial arts studio and engage in a friendly bout to exercise &amp;amp; train, making an impressive enough showing that all the other individuals present stop to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After they go to a movie and return home, the comic ends on a cliffhanger where a battered Sir Denis bursts into their home, seeking help with supposed corruption in the MI-6 agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not a tremendous amount of action in this comic, but that&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing. Shang-Chi has always been depicted as an extremely introspective character who seeks a path to enlightenment and peace with every action he takes and every phenomenon he witnesses. That he reflects on a number of the major plots in the comic so far is a totally human move (in addition to having the practical effect of catching up newer readers to the series&amp;rsquo; progression). I found myself nodding along, persuaded by Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s line of reasoning as he attempted to make sense of the insanity that is life in a pulp comic book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt; is a series that I try to collect through dollar bins; I know that Marvel has recently begun reprinting the series in massive omnibus form, but, given its content and focus, the comic really seems best experienced when one is exposed to the feel and smell of crappy older comic paper. It just seems appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Into Mystery 646</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 16:09:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; was the comic in which Thor first appeared, and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome that Marvel revived this title in order to make space for Asgard tales (the &amp;ldquo;Tales from Asgard&amp;rdquo; in the back of older &lt;em&gt;Thor&lt;/em&gt; comics were great, but wayyyyy too short to enjoy thoroughly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember buying this comic from a dollar bin in 2014 or maybe 2015. The cover alone made it worth the price: Lady Sif looks totally badass, striding directly toward the viewer in a suit of battle armor&amp;mdash;mostly practical, too! only a bit of naked thigh that could be armored further, beneath her Greek-style skirt&amp;mdash;and wielding a sword in each hand. The use of color here (mostly grayscale except for the red of Sif&amp;rsquo;s cape, armor, and highlighting in the &lt;em&gt;JIM&lt;/em&gt; logo) helps make it stand out; there&amp;rsquo;s a similar phenomenon happening with the cover design to the current &lt;em&gt;Scarlet Witch&lt;/em&gt; series, and I really wish I could get the covers to those issues as prints.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Journey-Into-Mystery-646.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Journey Into Mystery 646, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Journey Into Mystery issue 646&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Inside, the indicia page has a hilarious narration accompanying a large, similarly red-toned, image of Sif that rips off an exchange from &lt;em&gt;Shaft&lt;/em&gt; (and does so less skillfully, since the initial question is so wordy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s the sword-wielding woman who&amp;rsquo;s a soldier on the battlefield and a lady in Asgardia, but no one understands her but her thunder god?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;SIF!&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Verily. Can you dig it?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;We can dig it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This certainly sets the stage for an entertaining reading experience. Turning the page, I find myself wondering what, exactly is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asgard is in ruins and Sif is helping with some sort of rescue/relief effort. I think that this story probably takes place after&amp;mdash;or, more likely, during&amp;mdash;Ragnarok (which, if I recall, had occurred in the Thor comics around this time); Sif suggests as much when she notes that the demon Surtur had come to wreck shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif rescues a child, says she&amp;rsquo;s had enough child-minding for the day after turning the child over to other helpers, and then promptly(? there&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Days Hence&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; caption, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell just how much time has passed) goes to dinner at the child&amp;rsquo;s house, visiting an entire home &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with children. There are some interesting conversations about the best way to fight (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Fighting&amp;rsquo;s for &lt;strong&gt;kids&lt;/strong&gt;. You should use your &lt;strong&gt;words&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;ldquo;) and about 1950s-era &lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; comics, which apparently exist and populate care packages given to Asgardians by the Red Cross (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, Sif travels to Niffleheim to find a sleeping dragon who might have information for her about some ancient warriors of legend, as she has &amp;ldquo;a record of a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; battle with &lt;strong&gt;greater&lt;/strong&gt; warriors still who fought so fiercely those who saw them said they seemed &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to be men at &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; She says this while sitting on the shoulder of a &lt;em&gt;giant dragon&lt;/em&gt; that she reached only after taking down a bunch of Niffleheim&amp;rsquo;s resident predators. I can only imagine how incredible these other warriors she&amp;rsquo;s looking for must have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif eventually gets the info she needs and casts a spell to talk to the warriors&amp;rsquo; teacher &amp;hellip; supposedly to learn the &amp;ldquo;berserker incantation&amp;rdquo; and, I assume, save Asgard? I think I&amp;rsquo;m right, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really invested in this story&amp;mdash;and I say that as someone who &lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Asgardian characters and tales. I do, however, dig that Sif is apparently willing to compromise all over the place in order to save her home, and the idea of Sif becoming an uncontrollable berserker seems excellent at face value (I mean, literally the first thing she does is kill the person who just taught her the berserker incantation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story ends (technically, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) with her in a tavern in &amp;ldquo;the unluckiest town in Midgard&amp;rdquo; with a bloody bag (presumably the teacher&amp;rsquo;s head) on a stool next to her while she asks for another drink. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a serious &lt;em&gt;Superman III&lt;/em&gt; vibe here and I love it. Now this is a story I&amp;rsquo;m interested in continuing! Unfortunately, I can&amp;rsquo;t recall offhand if I bought any more issues in this storyline, which at the moment is a shame, because I was definitely brought around from a plot I initially didn&amp;rsquo;t find that interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doom Patrol 041 (1987)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doom-Patrol-041/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 23:51:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doom-Patrol-041/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite expect an issue of &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; to appear so soon, but here we are. Possibly the single greatest comic run I own, by the author whose work(s) I try to follow more than any other (Grant Morrison). (As an aside, I had the help of a friend in completing this run some time ago, and I am reminded that I still need to pay her back for her help in doing so.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doom Patrol, as characters, have always fascinated me in the way that the X-Men tend to for most readers. They&amp;rsquo;re outcasts who fight against the banality of the status quo and champion individuals and groups on the margins of society. Of course, the original Doom Patrol team managed to out-hero the X-Men by giving their lives for a small fishing village. And the characters stayed dead for some time! (This is unheard of in comics, unless you were Ben Parker or Bucky Barnes &amp;hellip; at least until the early 2000s.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, having Grant Morrison provide his take on the Doom Patrol is/was positively awesome, especially since this take involves surrealism, dada, comics deconstructionism, and a fundamental plot-line later ripped off by M. Night Shyamalan for his movie &lt;em&gt;Unbreakable&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; 041, by Simon Bisley (I think? I feel pretty sure about this, since he loves to do hyper-detailed elbows), is suitable for the comic: there&amp;rsquo;s a naked, faceless woman (a character named Rhea, who appears within the issue) floating above a naked, muscular humanoid with a tail and visible spine nearly protruding through its skin. To the right of these figures are various skulls and skeletal limbs; at least one of the skulls appears to be screwed or bolted to some mechanical/industrial apparatus.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doom-Patrol-041.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doom Patrol 041, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doom Patrol issue 041&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, the issue begins in a typically cryptic Morrison way, with a woman visiting &amp;ldquo;one of the five&amp;rdquo; lost and found offices that are special in some way. They contain lost memories, confidences, innocence, etc. The woman visiting the office is looking for Flex Mentallo, a comic character lost since the 1950s. I love Flex Mentallo, so I&amp;rsquo;m stoked to see if he makes an appearance in this issue, although his &amp;ldquo;first appearance&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually occur until the next issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robotman is in his &amp;ldquo;spider legs&amp;rdquo; phase in this issue, which was another neat twist on the character&amp;mdash;I liked this aesthetic more than his giant shoulder-pads during this run. I always appreciated Robotman for his sleek look; the shoulders scream &amp;lsquo;90s and it&amp;rsquo;s just not a great look. That said, I do appreciate that it&amp;rsquo;s a kind of expression of his efforts to find a personal style, since he&amp;rsquo;s basically a disembodied brain in a mobile tin can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot of this issue is a climax to a multi-issue storyline. Here, the anathematicians face off against the agent of the kaleidoscope in a battle of &lt;em&gt;potlatch&lt;/em&gt; (having had the concept introduced to them by the Negative Man) wherein they take turns destroying more and more important &amp;amp; valuable symbols of their ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Robotman, on the advice of Rhea, plants a flower and a giant angel (in the form of a massive rock with three or more human faces on which sits a city) comes to life and is apparently named Balzizras. It had created a world devoid of creativity, being able to imagine only simple conflict between those warring ideologies. Now, the flower allows for free imagination: &amp;ldquo;The creator&amp;rsquo;s come down &lt;strong&gt;among&lt;/strong&gt; you, not as a &lt;strong&gt;judge&lt;/strong&gt;, but as a sort of imaginative energy. Pretty neat, huh?&amp;rdquo; When Robotman asks if it&amp;rsquo;s really an angel, Rhea replies: &amp;ldquo;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s either &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; or the psychic projection of a woman called &lt;strong&gt;Ilse Krauss&lt;/strong&gt; who&amp;rsquo;s lying in a hospital bed in &lt;strong&gt;Bremen&lt;/strong&gt;, dying of brain cancer. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to be sure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of concept that I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; reading about in comics. Morrison knows exactly how to tap into the part of my brain that drinks in the most incredible high-concept ideas spitballed in half-formed states, since they allow the reader the opportunity to imagine how the ideas might be realized. The conflict is resolved by heroes who are willing to consider completely absurd and seemingly unrelated solutions, and the payoffs are frequently not returns to the status quo but radical paradigm shifts in which the characters (and the reader, hopefully?) develop further via the enlightenment they&amp;rsquo;ve gained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much every storyline in Morrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; run achieves this without disappointing; the same can be said of his &lt;em&gt;JLA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;All-Star Superman&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;New X-Men&lt;/em&gt; runs (maybe not quite to this extent with &lt;em&gt;New X-Men&lt;/em&gt;, perhaps). It&amp;rsquo;s this desire to use the superhero mythos as a way to promote internal philosophical development on the part of the reader that makes me appreciate Morrison&amp;rsquo;s writing. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting when superheroes are taken seriously (a la &lt;em&gt;Watchmen&lt;/em&gt;), but it&amp;rsquo;s even more interesting to me when the concept of the superhero is taken philosophically and explored as a potential humanist value system (or at least the vehicle for one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yeah. I love the Doom Patrol and I love this issue&amp;rsquo;s story as an awe-inspiring demonstration of superheroes through those characters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shazam 018 (1973)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:31:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just by looking at the title, I can tell that issue 18 from the 1973 run of &lt;em&gt;Shazam!&lt;/em&gt; (the first DC title with Captain Marvel/Shazam after acquiring Fawcett&amp;rsquo;s characters) is going to be amazing: Captain Marvel is lifting up part of a house while asking, &amp;ldquo;Who called &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt; for help?&amp;rdquo; In response, a frog&amp;mdash;held in someone&amp;rsquo;s hand&amp;mdash;replies, &amp;ldquo;*Ribit* I did!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in a note at the bottom right corner, we get a hint of what the issue will involve: &amp;ldquo;The celebrated talking frog of Blackstone Forest!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sold.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Shazam-018.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Shazam 018, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Shazam! issue 018&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also worth noting that, like Doctor Strange (covered briefly in &lt;a href=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016&#34;&gt;my previous review&lt;/a&gt;, I am a big fan of Captain Marvel&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for me to refer to him as Shazam, even if DC has since retconned the character&amp;rsquo;s name. Grant Morrison, in his book &lt;em&gt;Supergods&lt;/em&gt;, describes the appeal in this way: &amp;ldquo;Captain Marvels power came not from years in the gym or from his alien biology or his royal blood. His power came from a spell. He was a magician&amp;rdquo; (from ch. 2). That is, it&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely the average comic reader is secretly an orphan from an alien world or heir to a billion-dollar empire. But anyone, anyone at all, can turn down the wrong street corner and discover a magic word that will transform them into Captain Marvel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, it may be unsurprising that the depiction of Captain Marvel in &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt; speaks powerfully to me, as grownup Billy Batson has never really emotionally matured (although he never got the chance to, in this story), has been lied to/corrupted/twisted by dark forces, but who nonetheless redeems himself to help everyone when it&amp;rsquo;s necessary. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the former Catholic in me speaking, but &amp;hellip; how is that not an incredible fate towards which to aspire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s open this issue up and check out the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Page 1 reminds me that I forgot about one of the greatest comic characters ever: TAWKY TAWNY, a talking bipedal tiger who wears suits (in the &amp;lsquo;70s, these were terrible plaid suits with floral ties) and hangs out with the Marvel family. He has no super-powers or remarkable skills, other than possessing opposable thumbs so as to get dressed. No one bats an eye at his existence. This is the greatness of comic books distilled into a character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A related demonstration of comics greatness is in Dr. Kilowatt&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Brain-o-meter,&amp;rdquo; an intelligence-measuring device employed to check the smarts of the talking frog found by Tawny in the woods. (Of course, the frog &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; talks to Tawny, in a move that&amp;rsquo;s a clear ripoff of both the racist Warner Bros. dancing &amp;amp; singing frog cartoon and the fairy tale about the frog prince.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, we&amp;rsquo;re only &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; into this comic. Luckily, the plot amps up as RUSSIAN SPIES are brought in to &amp;ldquo;frog-nap&amp;rdquo; the talking frog to learn how they might improve human intelligence. When the spy tries to abscond with the frog, Captain Marvel destroys his helicopter&amp;rsquo;s rotors &amp;hellip; only to take the place of the rotos as a &amp;ldquo;marvel-copter.&amp;rdquo; The illustration of this feat is easily the single best moment of the comic, and now I&amp;rsquo;m only &lt;em&gt;halfway&lt;/em&gt; through this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, there&amp;rsquo;s an equally amazing moment two pages later when the frog transforms back into a prince and he looks like a froggish human&amp;mdash;so much so that other characters comment on it. Harsh! (This is also the end of the first story, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect, although I&amp;rsquo;m stoked to see a Captain Marvel Jr. story as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I totally forgot about the existence of Sivana Jr., the son of Dr. Sivana. It makes sense that Captain Marvel and Sivana would have a feud spanning generations&amp;mdash;so, naturally, to fight the teenage Captain Marvel Jr. (aka &amp;ldquo;CM3&amp;rdquo;), Sivana Jr. appears to be in his 60s. In this backup story, he has the technology to blow &lt;em&gt;square bubbles&lt;/em&gt; that can trap CM3 in their &amp;ldquo;elastic plastic&amp;rdquo; after Sivana Jr.&amp;rsquo;s first effort (a super-strong bed-spring coil) fails. Of course, the &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; plan involves mind-control devices that resemble half-dollars, and Sivana Jr. turns an initial failure into an ingenious plan when he realizes he can convince/hypnotize Freddie Freeman not to say the magic words that transform him (&amp;ldquo;Captain Marvel,&amp;rdquo; the name of his hero).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In even more ingenious comic logic, Freddie realizes he can&amp;rsquo;t say his own alter-ego&amp;rsquo;s name. Of course, this semantic nuance is the center of many CM3 plots, since he can&amp;rsquo;t technically provide his own name (when Captain Marvel Jr.) to authorities or fellow super-heroes, since that would transform him back into Freddie Freeman. Poor CM3. As an aside, I wonder if he may be the first superhero&amp;mdash;definitely one of the first superheroes&amp;mdash;to have a visible disability that&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;blindness but can see in the dark&amp;rdquo; like Dr. Midnight or the Black Bat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I could ever dislike a golden/silver/bronze-age Shazam story, because they&amp;rsquo;re so optimistic and fun and take for granted that a comic book world doesn&amp;rsquo;t and can&amp;rsquo;t make sense realistically. Billy, Freddie, and Mary are all kids who represent the fun of superheroes, and the kids themselves are always central to the story, with the hero identities there to solve problems when they have no other means of doing so themselves. Of course, I similarly love the Moore &amp;amp; Gaiman &lt;em&gt;Marvelman&lt;/em&gt; stories that take these character ideas in new directions (including a take on CM3&amp;rsquo;s more likely approach to being a hero by &lt;em&gt;staying in that identity forever if possible&lt;/em&gt;), but I&amp;rsquo;ve never really felt the need to check out the more recent (2000s) DC Comics take(s) on Shazam and family. I guess I should, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be incredibly disappointed by a move away from what I see as one of the greatest characters ever. Although I suppose, at least, I should check out the Morrison &lt;em&gt;Multiversity: Thunderworld&lt;/em&gt; comic to see what he&amp;rsquo;d do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme 016 (1988)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 23:04:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps fitting that the first comic randomly selected to serve as a review post is a &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comic, since I have long adored the character. (I used to have more comics featuring Doctor Strange than any other, but I&amp;rsquo;ve since collected far more Green Lantern-related comics &amp;hellip; so expect a few of those to make appearances.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover, shown below, is suitably interesting: Baron Blood has thrown(?) or is otherwise causing Doctor Strange to be flung upside-down through the night sky, off of some jungle or forest cliff, with a large, full moon illuminating everything from the background. Baron Blood has some seriously long underarm wings here, like he learned about Batman&amp;rsquo;s cape or something.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue, titled &amp;ldquo;Love and Haiti&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (classic Marvel pun?). There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love: Roy Thomas (partially) on writing duties. A cast that includes Morbius, Marie LaVeau the &amp;ldquo;Voodoo Queen,&amp;rdquo; Baron Blood, and Brother Voodoo. It is, unfortunately, the middle point of a five-issue arc, so there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; backstory to catch up readers, but other details are left unstated&amp;ndash;although I never felt like I was really lost at any point. This issue (from 1990) is well before the era of plot decompression for the sake of publishing an eventual TPB collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art by Jackson Guice seems very &amp;ldquo;workhorse&amp;rdquo; in comparison to the early &amp;lsquo;90s Image style explosion, but I appreciate it now in a way that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could have at age 9 (not that I owned it then&amp;ndash;I think I picked up this issue in a lot of &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comics around 2001). Stephen Strange looks like an older doctor. Poses seem relatively realistic, save for when characters/phenomena suggest they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be (like someone floating upside-down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awkward moment: during a fight with vampires&amp;ndash;in an alley in Port-au-Prince, of course&amp;ndash;Morgana Blessing calls out both to &amp;ldquo;Mr. Drumm&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dr. Morbius&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; poor Brother Voodoo getting &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; credit for his educational credentials until he took up the mantle of Sorcerer Supreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome moment: Dracula making a &lt;em&gt;phone call&lt;/em&gt; in order to set up an attack on an enemy. This is easily the best dialogue of the issue (the panel art is similarly wonderful):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dracula: &amp;ldquo;I want you to set a &lt;strong&gt;trap&lt;/strong&gt; for my accursed descendant, &lt;strong&gt;Frank Drake&lt;/strong&gt;, upon his arrival in Brazil. You will be richly rewarded.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danny Summers: &amp;ldquo;You bet your bat I will, Drac! &lt;strong&gt;Danny Summers&lt;/strong&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t do &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, I found myself really annoyed that Baron Blood, despite having an absolutely fantastic character name, has a pretty weak schtick&amp;ndash;or, at least, they really play up his weaknesses in this issue. If he changed up his costume&amp;rsquo;s color scheme, he might seem more intimidating. If he seemed like more of a mastermind, he might seem more dangerous. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t know: has Baron Blood ever been the big threat in a horror-oriented story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I think Doctor Strange casts a total of three spells in this issue, and none of them really plays up the surreal trip that Ditko originally demonstrated could (and &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;) be at the center of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s arcane/occult aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with luck my future reviews will become more coherent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>