<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 16:09:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Into Mystery 646</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 16:09:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; was the comic in which Thor first appeared, and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome that Marvel revived this title in order to make space for Asgard tales (the &amp;ldquo;Tales from Asgard&amp;rdquo; in the back of older &lt;em&gt;Thor&lt;/em&gt; comics were great, but wayyyyy too short to enjoy thoroughly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember buying this comic from a dollar bin in 2014 or maybe 2015. The cover alone made it worth the price: Lady Sif looks totally badass, striding directly toward the viewer in a suit of battle armor&amp;mdash;mostly practical, too! only a bit of naked thigh that could be armored further, beneath her Greek-style skirt&amp;mdash;and wielding a sword in each hand. The use of color here (mostly grayscale except for the red of Sif&amp;rsquo;s cape, armor, and highlighting in the &lt;em&gt;JIM&lt;/em&gt; logo) helps make it stand out; there&amp;rsquo;s a similar phenomenon happening with the cover design to the current &lt;em&gt;Scarlet Witch&lt;/em&gt; series, and I really wish I could get the covers to those issues as prints.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Journey-Into-Mystery-646.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Journey Into Mystery 646, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Journey Into Mystery issue 646&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Inside, the indicia page has a hilarious narration accompanying a large, similarly red-toned, image of Sif that rips off an exchange from &lt;em&gt;Shaft&lt;/em&gt; (and does so less skillfully, since the initial question is so wordy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s the sword-wielding woman who&amp;rsquo;s a soldier on the battlefield and a lady in Asgardia, but no one understands her but her thunder god?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;SIF!&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Verily. Can you dig it?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;We can dig it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This certainly sets the stage for an entertaining reading experience. Turning the page, I find myself wondering what, exactly is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asgard is in ruins and Sif is helping with some sort of rescue/relief effort. I think that this story probably takes place after&amp;mdash;or, more likely, during&amp;mdash;Ragnarok (which, if I recall, had occurred in the Thor comics around this time); Sif suggests as much when she notes that the demon Surtur had come to wreck shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif rescues a child, says she&amp;rsquo;s had enough child-minding for the day after turning the child over to other helpers, and then promptly(? there&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Days Hence&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; caption, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell just how much time has passed) goes to dinner at the child&amp;rsquo;s house, visiting an entire home &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with children. There are some interesting conversations about the best way to fight (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Fighting&amp;rsquo;s for &lt;strong&gt;kids&lt;/strong&gt;. You should use your &lt;strong&gt;words&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;ldquo;) and about 1950s-era &lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; comics, which apparently exist and populate care packages given to Asgardians by the Red Cross (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, Sif travels to Niffleheim to find a sleeping dragon who might have information for her about some ancient warriors of legend, as she has &amp;ldquo;a record of a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; battle with &lt;strong&gt;greater&lt;/strong&gt; warriors still who fought so fiercely those who saw them said they seemed &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to be men at &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; She says this while sitting on the shoulder of a &lt;em&gt;giant dragon&lt;/em&gt; that she reached only after taking down a bunch of Niffleheim&amp;rsquo;s resident predators. I can only imagine how incredible these other warriors she&amp;rsquo;s looking for must have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif eventually gets the info she needs and casts a spell to talk to the warriors&amp;rsquo; teacher &amp;hellip; supposedly to learn the &amp;ldquo;berserker incantation&amp;rdquo; and, I assume, save Asgard? I think I&amp;rsquo;m right, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really invested in this story&amp;mdash;and I say that as someone who &lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Asgardian characters and tales. I do, however, dig that Sif is apparently willing to compromise all over the place in order to save her home, and the idea of Sif becoming an uncontrollable berserker seems excellent at face value (I mean, literally the first thing she does is kill the person who just taught her the berserker incantation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story ends (technically, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) with her in a tavern in &amp;ldquo;the unluckiest town in Midgard&amp;rdquo; with a bloody bag (presumably the teacher&amp;rsquo;s head) on a stool next to her while she asks for another drink. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a serious &lt;em&gt;Superman III&lt;/em&gt; vibe here and I love it. Now this is a story I&amp;rsquo;m interested in continuing! Unfortunately, I can&amp;rsquo;t recall offhand if I bought any more issues in this storyline, which at the moment is a shame, because I was definitely brought around from a plot I initially didn&amp;rsquo;t find that interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doom Patrol 041 (1987)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doom-Patrol-041/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 23:51:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doom-Patrol-041/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite expect an issue of &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; to appear so soon, but here we are. Possibly the single greatest comic run I own, by the author whose work(s) I try to follow more than any other (Grant Morrison). (As an aside, I had the help of a friend in completing this run some time ago, and I am reminded that I still need to pay her back for her help in doing so.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doom Patrol, as characters, have always fascinated me in the way that the X-Men tend to for most readers. They&amp;rsquo;re outcasts who fight against the banality of the status quo and champion individuals and groups on the margins of society. Of course, the original Doom Patrol team managed to out-hero the X-Men by giving their lives for a small fishing village. And the characters stayed dead for some time! (This is unheard of in comics, unless you were Ben Parker or Bucky Barnes &amp;hellip; at least until the early 2000s.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, having Grant Morrison provide his take on the Doom Patrol is/was positively awesome, especially since this take involves surrealism, dada, comics deconstructionism, and a fundamental plot-line later ripped off by M. Night Shyamalan for his movie &lt;em&gt;Unbreakable&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; 041, by Simon Bisley (I think? I feel pretty sure about this, since he loves to do hyper-detailed elbows), is suitable for the comic: there&amp;rsquo;s a naked, faceless woman (a character named Rhea, who appears within the issue) floating above a naked, muscular humanoid with a tail and visible spine nearly protruding through its skin. To the right of these figures are various skulls and skeletal limbs; at least one of the skulls appears to be screwed or bolted to some mechanical/industrial apparatus.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doom-Patrol-041.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doom Patrol 041, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doom Patrol issue 041&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, the issue begins in a typically cryptic Morrison way, with a woman visiting &amp;ldquo;one of the five&amp;rdquo; lost and found offices that are special in some way. They contain lost memories, confidences, innocence, etc. The woman visiting the office is looking for Flex Mentallo, a comic character lost since the 1950s. I love Flex Mentallo, so I&amp;rsquo;m stoked to see if he makes an appearance in this issue, although his &amp;ldquo;first appearance&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually occur until the next issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robotman is in his &amp;ldquo;spider legs&amp;rdquo; phase in this issue, which was another neat twist on the character&amp;mdash;I liked this aesthetic more than his giant shoulder-pads during this run. I always appreciated Robotman for his sleek look; the shoulders scream &amp;lsquo;90s and it&amp;rsquo;s just not a great look. That said, I do appreciate that it&amp;rsquo;s a kind of expression of his efforts to find a personal style, since he&amp;rsquo;s basically a disembodied brain in a mobile tin can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot of this issue is a climax to a multi-issue storyline. Here, the anathematicians face off against the agent of the kaleidoscope in a battle of &lt;em&gt;potlatch&lt;/em&gt; (having had the concept introduced to them by the Negative Man) wherein they take turns destroying more and more important &amp;amp; valuable symbols of their ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Robotman, on the advice of Rhea, plants a flower and a giant angel (in the form of a massive rock with three or more human faces on which sits a city) comes to life and is apparently named Balzizras. It had created a world devoid of creativity, being able to imagine only simple conflict between those warring ideologies. Now, the flower allows for free imagination: &amp;ldquo;The creator&amp;rsquo;s come down &lt;strong&gt;among&lt;/strong&gt; you, not as a &lt;strong&gt;judge&lt;/strong&gt;, but as a sort of imaginative energy. Pretty neat, huh?&amp;rdquo; When Robotman asks if it&amp;rsquo;s really an angel, Rhea replies: &amp;ldquo;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s either &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; or the psychic projection of a woman called &lt;strong&gt;Ilse Krauss&lt;/strong&gt; who&amp;rsquo;s lying in a hospital bed in &lt;strong&gt;Bremen&lt;/strong&gt;, dying of brain cancer. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to be sure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of concept that I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; reading about in comics. Morrison knows exactly how to tap into the part of my brain that drinks in the most incredible high-concept ideas spitballed in half-formed states, since they allow the reader the opportunity to imagine how the ideas might be realized. The conflict is resolved by heroes who are willing to consider completely absurd and seemingly unrelated solutions, and the payoffs are frequently not returns to the status quo but radical paradigm shifts in which the characters (and the reader, hopefully?) develop further via the enlightenment they&amp;rsquo;ve gained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much every storyline in Morrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol&lt;/em&gt; run achieves this without disappointing; the same can be said of his &lt;em&gt;JLA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;All-Star Superman&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;New X-Men&lt;/em&gt; runs (maybe not quite to this extent with &lt;em&gt;New X-Men&lt;/em&gt;, perhaps). It&amp;rsquo;s this desire to use the superhero mythos as a way to promote internal philosophical development on the part of the reader that makes me appreciate Morrison&amp;rsquo;s writing. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting when superheroes are taken seriously (a la &lt;em&gt;Watchmen&lt;/em&gt;), but it&amp;rsquo;s even more interesting to me when the concept of the superhero is taken philosophically and explored as a potential humanist value system (or at least the vehicle for one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yeah. I love the Doom Patrol and I love this issue&amp;rsquo;s story as an awe-inspiring demonstration of superheroes through those characters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shazam 018 (1973)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:31:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just by looking at the title, I can tell that issue 18 from the 1973 run of &lt;em&gt;Shazam!&lt;/em&gt; (the first DC title with Captain Marvel/Shazam after acquiring Fawcett&amp;rsquo;s characters) is going to be amazing: Captain Marvel is lifting up part of a house while asking, &amp;ldquo;Who called &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt; for help?&amp;rdquo; In response, a frog&amp;mdash;held in someone&amp;rsquo;s hand&amp;mdash;replies, &amp;ldquo;*Ribit* I did!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in a note at the bottom right corner, we get a hint of what the issue will involve: &amp;ldquo;The celebrated talking frog of Blackstone Forest!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sold.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Shazam-018.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Shazam 018, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Shazam! issue 018&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also worth noting that, like Doctor Strange (covered briefly in &lt;a href=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016&#34;&gt;my previous review&lt;/a&gt;, I am a big fan of Captain Marvel&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for me to refer to him as Shazam, even if DC has since retconned the character&amp;rsquo;s name. Grant Morrison, in his book &lt;em&gt;Supergods&lt;/em&gt;, describes the appeal in this way: &amp;ldquo;Captain Marvel’s power came not from years in the gym or from his alien biology or his royal blood. His power came from a spell. He was a magician&amp;rdquo; (from ch. 2). That is, it&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely the average comic reader is secretly an orphan from an alien world or heir to a billion-dollar empire. But anyone, anyone at all, can turn down the wrong street corner and discover a magic word that will transform them into Captain Marvel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, it may be unsurprising that the depiction of Captain Marvel in &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt; speaks powerfully to me, as grownup Billy Batson has never really emotionally matured (although he never got the chance to, in this story), has been lied to/corrupted/twisted by dark forces, but who nonetheless redeems himself to help everyone when it&amp;rsquo;s necessary. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the former Catholic in me speaking, but &amp;hellip; how is that not an incredible fate towards which to aspire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s open this issue up and check out the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Page 1 reminds me that I forgot about one of the greatest comic characters ever: TAWKY TAWNY, a talking bipedal tiger who wears suits (in the &amp;lsquo;70s, these were terrible plaid suits with floral ties) and hangs out with the Marvel family. He has no super-powers or remarkable skills, other than possessing opposable thumbs so as to get dressed. No one bats an eye at his existence. This is the greatness of comic books distilled into a character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A related demonstration of comics greatness is in Dr. Kilowatt&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Brain-o-meter,&amp;rdquo; an intelligence-measuring device employed to check the smarts of the talking frog found by Tawny in the woods. (Of course, the frog &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; talks to Tawny, in a move that&amp;rsquo;s a clear ripoff of both the racist Warner Bros. dancing &amp;amp; singing frog cartoon and the fairy tale about the frog prince.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, we&amp;rsquo;re only &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; into this comic. Luckily, the plot amps up as RUSSIAN SPIES are brought in to &amp;ldquo;frog-nap&amp;rdquo; the talking frog to learn how they might improve human intelligence. When the spy tries to abscond with the frog, Captain Marvel destroys his helicopter&amp;rsquo;s rotors &amp;hellip; only to take the place of the rotos as a &amp;ldquo;marvel-copter.&amp;rdquo; The illustration of this feat is easily the single best moment of the comic, and now I&amp;rsquo;m only &lt;em&gt;halfway&lt;/em&gt; through this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, there&amp;rsquo;s an equally amazing moment two pages later when the frog transforms back into a prince and he looks like a froggish human&amp;mdash;so much so that other characters comment on it. Harsh! (This is also the end of the first story, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect, although I&amp;rsquo;m stoked to see a Captain Marvel Jr. story as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I totally forgot about the existence of Sivana Jr., the son of Dr. Sivana. It makes sense that Captain Marvel and Sivana would have a feud spanning generations&amp;mdash;so, naturally, to fight the teenage Captain Marvel Jr. (aka &amp;ldquo;CM3&amp;rdquo;), Sivana Jr. appears to be in his 60s. In this backup story, he has the technology to blow &lt;em&gt;square bubbles&lt;/em&gt; that can trap CM3 in their &amp;ldquo;elastic plastic&amp;rdquo; after Sivana Jr.&amp;rsquo;s first effort (a super-strong bed-spring coil) fails. Of course, the &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; plan involves mind-control devices that resemble half-dollars, and Sivana Jr. turns an initial failure into an ingenious plan when he realizes he can convince/hypnotize Freddie Freeman not to say the magic words that transform him (&amp;ldquo;Captain Marvel,&amp;rdquo; the name of his hero).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In even more ingenious comic logic, Freddie realizes he can&amp;rsquo;t say his own alter-ego&amp;rsquo;s name. Of course, this semantic nuance is the center of many CM3 plots, since he can&amp;rsquo;t technically provide his own name (when Captain Marvel Jr.) to authorities or fellow super-heroes, since that would transform him back into Freddie Freeman. Poor CM3. As an aside, I wonder if he may be the first superhero&amp;mdash;definitely one of the first superheroes&amp;mdash;to have a visible disability that&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;blindness but can see in the dark&amp;rdquo; like Dr. Midnight or the Black Bat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I could ever dislike a golden/silver/bronze-age Shazam story, because they&amp;rsquo;re so optimistic and fun and take for granted that a comic book world doesn&amp;rsquo;t and can&amp;rsquo;t make sense realistically. Billy, Freddie, and Mary are all kids who represent the fun of superheroes, and the kids themselves are always central to the story, with the hero identities there to solve problems when they have no other means of doing so themselves. Of course, I similarly love the Moore &amp;amp; Gaiman &lt;em&gt;Marvelman&lt;/em&gt; stories that take these character ideas in new directions (including a take on CM3&amp;rsquo;s more likely approach to being a hero by &lt;em&gt;staying in that identity forever if possible&lt;/em&gt;), but I&amp;rsquo;ve never really felt the need to check out the more recent (2000s) DC Comics take(s) on Shazam and family. I guess I should, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be incredibly disappointed by a move away from what I see as one of the greatest characters ever. Although I suppose, at least, I should check out the Morrison &lt;em&gt;Multiversity: Thunderworld&lt;/em&gt; comic to see what he&amp;rsquo;d do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme 016 (1988)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 23:04:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps fitting that the first comic randomly selected to serve as a review post is a &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comic, since I have long adored the character. (I used to have more comics featuring Doctor Strange than any other, but I&amp;rsquo;ve since collected far more Green Lantern-related comics &amp;hellip; so expect a few of those to make appearances.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover, shown below, is suitably interesting: Baron Blood has thrown(?) or is otherwise causing Doctor Strange to be flung upside-down through the night sky, off of some jungle or forest cliff, with a large, full moon illuminating everything from the background. Baron Blood has some seriously long underarm wings here, like he learned about Batman&amp;rsquo;s cape or something.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue, titled &amp;ldquo;Love and Haiti&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (classic Marvel pun?). There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love: Roy Thomas (partially) on writing duties. A cast that includes Morbius, Marie LaVeau the &amp;ldquo;Voodoo Queen,&amp;rdquo; Baron Blood, and Brother Voodoo. It is, unfortunately, the middle point of a five-issue arc, so there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; backstory to catch up readers, but other details are left unstated&amp;ndash;although I never felt like I was really lost at any point. This issue (from 1990) is well before the era of plot decompression for the sake of publishing an eventual TPB collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art by Jackson Guice seems very &amp;ldquo;workhorse&amp;rdquo; in comparison to the early &amp;lsquo;90s Image style explosion, but I appreciate it now in a way that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could have at age 9 (not that I owned it then&amp;ndash;I think I picked up this issue in a lot of &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comics around 2001). Stephen Strange looks like an older doctor. Poses seem relatively realistic, save for when characters/phenomena suggest they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be (like someone floating upside-down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awkward moment: during a fight with vampires&amp;ndash;in an alley in Port-au-Prince, of course&amp;ndash;Morgana Blessing calls out both to &amp;ldquo;Mr. Drumm&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dr. Morbius&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; poor Brother Voodoo getting &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; credit for his educational credentials until he took up the mantle of Sorcerer Supreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome moment: Dracula making a &lt;em&gt;phone call&lt;/em&gt; in order to set up an attack on an enemy. This is easily the best dialogue of the issue (the panel art is similarly wonderful):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dracula: &amp;ldquo;I want you to set a &lt;strong&gt;trap&lt;/strong&gt; for my accursed descendant, &lt;strong&gt;Frank Drake&lt;/strong&gt;, upon his arrival in Brazil. You will be richly rewarded.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danny Summers: &amp;ldquo;You bet your bat I will, Drac! &lt;strong&gt;Danny Summers&lt;/strong&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t do &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, I found myself really annoyed that Baron Blood, despite having an absolutely fantastic character name, has a pretty weak schtick&amp;ndash;or, at least, they really play up his weaknesses in this issue. If he changed up his costume&amp;rsquo;s color scheme, he might seem more intimidating. If he seemed like more of a mastermind, he might seem more dangerous. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t know: has Baron Blood ever been the big threat in a horror-oriented story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I think Doctor Strange casts a total of three spells in this issue, and none of them really plays up the surreal trip that Ditko originally demonstrated could (and &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;) be at the center of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s arcane/occult aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with luck my future reviews will become more coherent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>