<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dc on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/dc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dc on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 23:13:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/dc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal Man 076</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 23:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first Vertigo post for this blog is also the first &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, Animal Man. Such a great character raised out of mediocre beginnings. Without getting &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; mired in details, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to say that Buddy Baker&amp;ndash;Animal Man&amp;ndash;can tap into the abilities of animals and make use thereof to fight injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, unlike most superheroes, he has a family (a wife, Ellen, and two children, Cliff and Maxine). This is important, because the central conflict in Buddy&amp;rsquo;s life is the tug-of-war that &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt; occurs between his desire to live a normal life with his family and his desire to use his powers in the best and most effective way possible (often to try and raise awareness about animal rights and ecological issues). This tug-of-war has led Buddy to some interesting places (for the reader, at least; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much ruined his life over and over again). At least, this is what happened to the character in the first volume of his own series; Grant Morrison set up this model and pretty much every author working on &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; since has followed suit, although they may have tweaked some specifics here and there, like looking at how Ellen deals with her completely absurd life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, Buddy went through a significant metamorphosis that left him in the body of a chimerical creature with the attributes of all kinds of animals, and he decided to use his new appearance to help found a church that would worship his daughter Maxine and her even-more-powerful animal-related powers&amp;ndash;the church is even called &amp;ldquo;The Life-Power Church of Maxine&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;set up half-seriously and half-deceptively by the Bakers and their closest friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to issue 076, then, shows Buddy in his animal-avatar form flying through a red sky over what appears to be the upraised arms/hands of an angry mob, given the tools and guns held aloft by those arms.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Animal-Man-076.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Animal Man 076, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Animal Man issue 076&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story begins with several pages narrated via in-universe comics drawn by budding cartoonist Cliff Baker, who lets us know that the Life-Power Church is on its way to Montana in search of some promised land where people and animals can live in harmony. They&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with some hunters and other critics along the way, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cartoon has been mailed to Ellen, who&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; with her family but instead with a small group of lesbian activists (that&amp;rsquo;s not a snarky, bigoted comment by me&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s how the characters were introduced and how they continue to be portrayed; a few issues before this one, Ellen notes to Buddy that she&amp;rsquo;s felt a connection growing between her and Sarah, one of the activists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the Life-Power Church is facing off against the National Guard in Nebraska (there&amp;rsquo;s references to a &amp;ldquo;plague&amp;rdquo; that has affected a number of people across the country, where they dream of themselves as animals running wild on human society), and Ellen&amp;rsquo;s conflicted between staying put with Sarah and being there in Nebraska for her family; the conversation in this scene does a pretty solid job of demonstrating various characters&amp;rsquo; takes on the situation so that no one seems to have the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;most correct&amp;rdquo; answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an equally intriguing scene between Maxine and a follower of the LFC (Ray, given the Church name &amp;ldquo;Manta Ray&amp;rdquo;) who&amp;rsquo;s secretly a government agent awaiting the order to assassinate Maxine, Buddy, or both. But she finds herself questioning her ability to murder a child if so commanded when she takes an impromptu romp/bath in a nearby river with Maxine and a throng of animal companions/guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray&amp;rsquo;s plot intertwines with that of an older man named Jack who&amp;rsquo;s looking to save his son from the LFC cult. Ray ends up getting caught by some locals who decide to rape her in the corn fields. Jack saves her, figuring that she can&amp;rsquo;t have made any poor decisions (that is, it&amp;rsquo;s not her fault she was caught and is being tortured, it&amp;rsquo;s the Church&amp;rsquo;s) that his own son didn&amp;rsquo;t make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly(?), there&amp;rsquo;s very little Buddy himself in this issue &amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t find myself disappointed by that fact. The overall story is really well fleshed out by the focus on these peripheral characters impacted by his actions from earlier issues. It really makes the world come alive in a way that you don&amp;rsquo;t get with close examinations of only a comic&amp;rsquo;s core characters. For example: we don&amp;rsquo;t ever really have that many opportunities for the development of peripheral characters in &lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;/em&gt; whose lives were affected by the actions of Batman or his rogues&amp;rsquo; gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice League Europe 008</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:10:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JUSTICE LEAGUE EUROPE! Possibly the greatest Europe-based superhero team from one of the big two comics companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Justice League Europe&lt;/em&gt; / &lt;em&gt;Justice League International&lt;/em&gt; were incredible series in the late 80s/early 90s that really embraced the goofiness of shining a spotlight on a band of B- and C-list heroes. Keith Giffen and Bart Sears worked so well together to make the comic so believable and staunchly ridiculous at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JLE featured two of my favorite DC characters: Animal Man and Metamorpho. Ralph Dibny is also great (and his partnership with his wife really should be emulated more, in terms of having a hero in a healthy committed relationship).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to this issue is suitably dramatic and goofy: members of the JLE and JLI (from left to right, at varying distances from the &amp;ldquo;camera&amp;rdquo;: Batman, Rocket Red, Captain Atom, Booster Gold, Mister Miracle, Fire, Metamorpho, Guy Gardner, Animal Man, Flash, Martian Manhunter, Power Girl, and Blue Beetle) stand, with their backs to the viewer, in the middle of a small town square, with moutnains looming in the background. There&amp;rsquo;s a large and ominous dark shadow spreading in the space between the mountains and the town. Blue Beetle says, &amp;ldquo;Uh oh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Justice-League-Europe-008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Justice League Europe #008, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Justice League Europe issue 008&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first page is a perfect demonstration of Keith Giffen&amp;rsquo;s strengths: Linda Strauss, a short-term Doctor Fate, is engaged in self-reflective exposition about her fears &amp;amp; doubts regarding taking on the Doctor Fate mantle. It&amp;rsquo;s engaging, interesting, and ends with a joke, as Giffen tends to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Order &lt;strong&gt;created&lt;/strong&gt; him [the Grey Man, antagonist for this story] &amp;hellip; Order&amp;rsquo;s responsible for the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s gone &lt;strong&gt;berserk&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;abusing&lt;/strong&gt; his power&amp;ndash;but if &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t do anything to &lt;strong&gt;stop&lt;/strong&gt; him&amp;ndash;then I guess the job&amp;rsquo;s fallen to &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;. (quietly) I think I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be sick.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the JLE and JLI stand off in a Stagg-owned compound against a horde of, and I&amp;rsquo;m serious, &amp;ldquo;zombie-vampires.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Zombie-vampires.&lt;/em&gt; This story would probably be absolutely terrible if everyone involved didn&amp;rsquo;t wholly embrace the ridiculous nature of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they finally decide to storm the compound, the zombie-vampires somehow grant energy to the Grey Man, a character who looks like a creepy uncle but manages to grow larger than the building when fueled somehow by the zombie-vampires. I remember nothing about the Grey Man while I reread this, but he has a vendetta against the forces of Order and Chaos (I assume he&amp;rsquo;s taking the &amp;ldquo;grey&amp;rdquo; middle ground between the two).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the Spectre shows up &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the embodied agents of Order and Chaos&amp;mdash;who are now united against their common foe. They promptly lobotomize him, and he&amp;rsquo;s left to wander mindlessly through the world. According to the Spectre: &amp;ldquo;[H]e will walk this world, collecting &lt;strong&gt;dream-essence&lt;/strong&gt; from the dead &amp;hellip; empty-headed, empty-hearted &amp;hellip; beyond pain &amp;hellip; beyond even &lt;strong&gt;loneliness&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; (Seriously?) The Grey Man is last seen just wandering off through an electrical fence and into the wilderness. I guess he doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to eat or anything. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad there&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;two entire super-hero teams&lt;/em&gt; nearby who could try and help him get super-institutionalized for everyone&amp;rsquo;s safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I forget what a given artist&amp;rsquo;s art style is like until I have the comic in front of me. At no point in my life have I forgotten Bart Sears&amp;rsquo; penchant to make everyone top-heavy musclemen with a billion points of light/shadow dynamic to demonstrate textures and contours. I have nostalgic love for it in &lt;em&gt;JLE&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;JLI&lt;/em&gt;, but I would not be able to abide it in probably any other comic (Sears&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;X-O Manowar&lt;/em&gt; art, for example, is so off-putting to me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, everyone who appears on the cover manages to get at least one line of dialogue, probably to keep this comic from being 96 pages long every month. I love that Grant Morrison busts on this balancing act in the pages of &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; when Buddy is asked to recognize the fact that he really only ever shows up in &lt;em&gt;JLE&lt;/em&gt; to say/do one or two things in any given adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I want to read more of my Giffen-era &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt; back issues to enjoy the best friendly relationship DC&amp;rsquo;s ever had: Blue Beetle &amp;amp; Booster Gold. (Sorry, it&amp;rsquo;s superior to Batman &amp;amp; Superman&amp;rsquo;s longtime partnership.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shazam 018 (1973)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:31:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just by looking at the title, I can tell that issue 18 from the 1973 run of &lt;em&gt;Shazam!&lt;/em&gt; (the first DC title with Captain Marvel/Shazam after acquiring Fawcett&amp;rsquo;s characters) is going to be amazing: Captain Marvel is lifting up part of a house while asking, &amp;ldquo;Who called &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt; for help?&amp;rdquo; In response, a frog&amp;mdash;held in someone&amp;rsquo;s hand&amp;mdash;replies, &amp;ldquo;*Ribit* I did!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in a note at the bottom right corner, we get a hint of what the issue will involve: &amp;ldquo;The celebrated talking frog of Blackstone Forest!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sold.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Shazam-018.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Shazam 018, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Shazam! issue 018&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also worth noting that, like Doctor Strange (covered briefly in &lt;a href=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016&#34;&gt;my previous review&lt;/a&gt;, I am a big fan of Captain Marvel&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for me to refer to him as Shazam, even if DC has since retconned the character&amp;rsquo;s name. Grant Morrison, in his book &lt;em&gt;Supergods&lt;/em&gt;, describes the appeal in this way: &amp;ldquo;Captain Marvel’s power came not from years in the gym or from his alien biology or his royal blood. His power came from a spell. He was a magician&amp;rdquo; (from ch. 2). That is, it&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely the average comic reader is secretly an orphan from an alien world or heir to a billion-dollar empire. But anyone, anyone at all, can turn down the wrong street corner and discover a magic word that will transform them into Captain Marvel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, it may be unsurprising that the depiction of Captain Marvel in &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt; speaks powerfully to me, as grownup Billy Batson has never really emotionally matured (although he never got the chance to, in this story), has been lied to/corrupted/twisted by dark forces, but who nonetheless redeems himself to help everyone when it&amp;rsquo;s necessary. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the former Catholic in me speaking, but &amp;hellip; how is that not an incredible fate towards which to aspire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s open this issue up and check out the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Page 1 reminds me that I forgot about one of the greatest comic characters ever: TAWKY TAWNY, a talking bipedal tiger who wears suits (in the &amp;lsquo;70s, these were terrible plaid suits with floral ties) and hangs out with the Marvel family. He has no super-powers or remarkable skills, other than possessing opposable thumbs so as to get dressed. No one bats an eye at his existence. This is the greatness of comic books distilled into a character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A related demonstration of comics greatness is in Dr. Kilowatt&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Brain-o-meter,&amp;rdquo; an intelligence-measuring device employed to check the smarts of the talking frog found by Tawny in the woods. (Of course, the frog &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; talks to Tawny, in a move that&amp;rsquo;s a clear ripoff of both the racist Warner Bros. dancing &amp;amp; singing frog cartoon and the fairy tale about the frog prince.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, we&amp;rsquo;re only &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; into this comic. Luckily, the plot amps up as RUSSIAN SPIES are brought in to &amp;ldquo;frog-nap&amp;rdquo; the talking frog to learn how they might improve human intelligence. When the spy tries to abscond with the frog, Captain Marvel destroys his helicopter&amp;rsquo;s rotors &amp;hellip; only to take the place of the rotos as a &amp;ldquo;marvel-copter.&amp;rdquo; The illustration of this feat is easily the single best moment of the comic, and now I&amp;rsquo;m only &lt;em&gt;halfway&lt;/em&gt; through this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, there&amp;rsquo;s an equally amazing moment two pages later when the frog transforms back into a prince and he looks like a froggish human&amp;mdash;so much so that other characters comment on it. Harsh! (This is also the end of the first story, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect, although I&amp;rsquo;m stoked to see a Captain Marvel Jr. story as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I totally forgot about the existence of Sivana Jr., the son of Dr. Sivana. It makes sense that Captain Marvel and Sivana would have a feud spanning generations&amp;mdash;so, naturally, to fight the teenage Captain Marvel Jr. (aka &amp;ldquo;CM3&amp;rdquo;), Sivana Jr. appears to be in his 60s. In this backup story, he has the technology to blow &lt;em&gt;square bubbles&lt;/em&gt; that can trap CM3 in their &amp;ldquo;elastic plastic&amp;rdquo; after Sivana Jr.&amp;rsquo;s first effort (a super-strong bed-spring coil) fails. Of course, the &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; plan involves mind-control devices that resemble half-dollars, and Sivana Jr. turns an initial failure into an ingenious plan when he realizes he can convince/hypnotize Freddie Freeman not to say the magic words that transform him (&amp;ldquo;Captain Marvel,&amp;rdquo; the name of his hero).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In even more ingenious comic logic, Freddie realizes he can&amp;rsquo;t say his own alter-ego&amp;rsquo;s name. Of course, this semantic nuance is the center of many CM3 plots, since he can&amp;rsquo;t technically provide his own name (when Captain Marvel Jr.) to authorities or fellow super-heroes, since that would transform him back into Freddie Freeman. Poor CM3. As an aside, I wonder if he may be the first superhero&amp;mdash;definitely one of the first superheroes&amp;mdash;to have a visible disability that&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;blindness but can see in the dark&amp;rdquo; like Dr. Midnight or the Black Bat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I could ever dislike a golden/silver/bronze-age Shazam story, because they&amp;rsquo;re so optimistic and fun and take for granted that a comic book world doesn&amp;rsquo;t and can&amp;rsquo;t make sense realistically. Billy, Freddie, and Mary are all kids who represent the fun of superheroes, and the kids themselves are always central to the story, with the hero identities there to solve problems when they have no other means of doing so themselves. Of course, I similarly love the Moore &amp;amp; Gaiman &lt;em&gt;Marvelman&lt;/em&gt; stories that take these character ideas in new directions (including a take on CM3&amp;rsquo;s more likely approach to being a hero by &lt;em&gt;staying in that identity forever if possible&lt;/em&gt;), but I&amp;rsquo;ve never really felt the need to check out the more recent (2000s) DC Comics take(s) on Shazam and family. I guess I should, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be incredibly disappointed by a move away from what I see as one of the greatest characters ever. Although I suppose, at least, I should check out the Morrison &lt;em&gt;Multiversity: Thunderworld&lt;/em&gt; comic to see what he&amp;rsquo;d do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>