<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dc on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/dc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dc on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:16:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/dc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Lanterns 007</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lanterns-007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:16:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lanterns-007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think that this might be the newest of all the comics I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; is a series starring Simon Baz and Jessica Cruz, two novice members of the Green Lantern Corps, each saddled with their own hang-ups about being a hero. They were paired up by Hal Jordan and tasked with protecting Earth while he went out into outer space to locate the rest of the Green Lantern Corps (as they had gone missing at the time). Also, like any good buddy cop story, the two despise each other at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first arc of &lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; does a pretty respectable job of following Simon and Jessica through their trials of overcoming self-doubt, an irritating partner, and a potential invasion of earth by the Red Lanterns. This issue marks the beginning of a new story arc (and the denouement to the previous arc), so we get to see what the next phase of the protagonists&amp;rsquo; relationship looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; 007 features Simon and Jessica standing next to one another, in their uniforms, in front of a series of floating GL insignias. Simon holds his ring hand in front of him while Jessica raises hers high above her head.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Green-Lanterns-007.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Green Lanterns 007, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Green Lanterns issue 007&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue, set on Halloween, begins with a focus on Jessica&amp;rsquo;s perspective, coming to grips with being a GL and having to spend time with Simon&amp;rsquo;s family. In a pretty funny move, she bails out of family activities (readying treats for Halloween), claiming to herself that she&amp;rsquo;s not a people person, and instead tries to &amp;ldquo;find Darkseid and see what he&amp;rsquo;s doing for dinner,&amp;rdquo; even going so far as to ask her ring to call him (the ring: &amp;ldquo;Call sent to voice mail.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Simon catches her and begs for her help dealing with his family&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s clear that they have that much in common&amp;ndash;and the two do some baking as a way to contribute to the household and get to know one another better. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice chiasmus where Simon decides to bail on the baking (it&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; the way his mother makes it), and it becomes Jessica&amp;rsquo;s turn to talk her partner down from doing something stupid. After Simon explains his relationship with his mother to Jessica, the two have an epiphany to cook with the aid of their power rings (allowing them to multitask much more easily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: after revealing himself as a GL to his mom, Simon convinces her to try a cookie &amp;hellip; and she doesn&amp;rsquo;t hate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all of this, Farid (Simon&amp;rsquo;s nephew) has been screwing around with Rami, a Guardian of Oa hiding out in the family&amp;rsquo;s attic. Rami senses that some threat (revealed to be the Dominators) is coming, and &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; bails from the house. The two GLs recognize they need to go after him, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this issue is pretty solid in terms of character development. Action-wise, it&amp;rsquo;s very &amp;ldquo;boring,&amp;rdquo; but in the context of the preceding six issues, it&amp;rsquo;s a really enjoyable moment of rest. There had been a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of action in those issues focusing on the problems that Jessica and Simon each felt about their ability to be a hero, and the interaction between them&amp;ndash;and the rest of Simon&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;ndash;here becomes a useful and satisfying progression from their overcoming some of those problems in their fight against the Red Lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was not initially sold on Simon Baz as a GL (because he used a gun! which I still think is kind of a lame early gimmick), I have come to really enjoy the presentation of his character in this series. I think that he works well with Jessica&amp;ndash;a character I wasn&amp;rsquo;t well-versed in before this series&amp;ndash;to give the GL franchise a pairing that feels fresh and innovative. (I mean, as iconic as Hal Jordan is, it&amp;rsquo;s not really that fascinating to watch a guy who believes, and often proves, he can do anything he wants.) Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just the longtime Marvel fan in me, but the relatability of Simon &amp;amp; Jessica as heroes-who-don&amp;rsquo;t-always-think-they-live-up-to-the-role really do a lot to make this series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astro City 024</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 18:50:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Green Lantern remains perhaps my favorite character-specific franchise, &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt; is far and away my single favorite series, ever. It is superhero comics world-building done expertly, pulling together and twisting tropes in a way that has not been done as fully, consistently, or enjoyably by anyone else. Kurt Busiek has it all together here and presents it in full force with Alex Ross covers and (usually) Brent Anderson art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt; is a comic whose stories focus on the titular city (located on the west coast, standing in the place of San Francisco or Seattle), which is populated by more than a century of superhero history. There&amp;rsquo;s an homage or parody to pretty much every superhero type; the very first issue provides an incredible Superman tale via the stand-in Samaritan, the greatest storyline in the title involves a Batman and Robin pair, there&amp;rsquo;s a wisecracking acrobat who annoys &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; he runs into or teams up with, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue, in the third (current) volume, focuses on a talking gorilla from the fabled antarctic Gorilla Mountain. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. What does the gorilla&amp;ndash;who goes by the name &amp;ldquo;Sticks&amp;rdquo; (a nickname for his drumming and because his original name was apparently &amp;ldquo;Stekk&amp;rdquo;)&amp;ndash;want to do with his life? Play music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous issue detailed his initial arrival in Astro City, trying out for a band, and getting caught up in the world of superheroics (after all, he&amp;rsquo;s a talking gorilla! and he has some military training from the Gorilla Mountain forces).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover features Sticks in action, fangs bared, arms raised, and drumsticks in hand(s) as he&amp;rsquo;s in the middle of &lt;em&gt;pounding&lt;/em&gt; on a drum set (whose bass drum features the iconic Astro City &amp;ldquo;rocket&amp;rdquo; icon). An explosion of purple and green motion lines suggest this is a snapshot of an incredibly wild performance.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Astro-City-024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Astro City 024, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Astro City issue 024&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In this issue, we learn about Sticks&amp;rsquo; past&amp;ndash;why he left Gorilla Mountain and how it&amp;rsquo;s impacted his decision to try being a superhero, since he fits in more easily with them than with the average Astro City resident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the while, Sticks struggles with doing the right thing and &lt;em&gt;wanting&lt;/em&gt; to do the right thing, namely whether or not he should be a superhero just because he can, or if it&amp;rsquo;s better left to those with the drive to pursue it. As he states in a thought/narrative caption: &amp;ldquo;It takes the right kind of &lt;strong&gt;person&lt;/strong&gt; to do this kind of thing. To make it their life, their &lt;strong&gt;mission&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, he quits and reconnects with his old bandmates. Unfortunately, they don&amp;rsquo;t all agree on whether or not to keep associating with Sticks; after all, as a talking gorilla, he draws attention by super-villains and that could be dangerous for his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he&amp;rsquo;s understandable about it, Sticks is nonetheless hurt, and it shows (there&amp;rsquo;s something a bit astounding about feeling a sympathetic connection to a gorilla in a t-shirt). While he sits on a roof at night, Samaritan comes to visit and offers the sort of advice that the best Superman stories always allow him to provide: genuine empathy and consideration that lead toward an optimistic future always left in the listener&amp;rsquo;s hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samaritan acknowledges Sticks doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to be a superhero and doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to convince him otherwise. Instead, he demonstrates that he believes &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a way. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; a way. I &lt;strong&gt;believe&lt;/strong&gt; that. Don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;give up&lt;/strong&gt;. Find a way to do what you love. If I can help, you can call on me. I&amp;rsquo;ll give you an alert code. But find a &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much more of a &lt;em&gt;samaritan&lt;/em&gt; can one be, if not to help lift up another and assist them toward their goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sticks decides to take on the temporary identity of &amp;ldquo;Tuxedo Gorilla&amp;rdquo; in order to make a few higher-profile busts to draw the press so that he can make an announcement: he&amp;rsquo;s having auditions for a super-powered band. His superhero contacts provide security so that no one can disrupt the proceedings (including blocking any sensors attempting to learn the secret identities of auditioners), and he manages to get together a group that have music-oriented abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a record contract ready, Sticks and company decide to record some tricks and &amp;ldquo;fight a little crime along the way&amp;rdquo; as the group &lt;em&gt;Powerchord&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that I love every issue of &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt;, and this is no different. Sticks&amp;rsquo; story is a fantastic origin tale and an accessible jumping-on point for new readers (well, assuming they read issue 023 first). There are so many clear nods to existing comic characters and ideas&amp;ndash;most obviously being Gorilla Mountain&amp;rsquo;s debt to Gorilla City from &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ndash;and they&amp;rsquo;re all taken in really interesting and new directions while feeling familiar or comfortable in the best way(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could only read one comic series from this point forward, it would be &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt;, without question. And I would stand by that decision happily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demon 002</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Demon-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:35:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Demon-002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gone, gone, o form of man!
Rise the demon Etrigan!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etrigan the demon is a great character, even if Jack Kirby wasn&amp;rsquo;t really into it. Arthurian knight Jason Blood, cursed to inhabit the same body/space as Etrigan, a demon bound into Merlin&amp;rsquo;s service, has been developed as an incredibly cornerstone of DC&amp;rsquo;s supernatural/horror sphere of comics. (This was made most obvious in Alan Moore&amp;rsquo;s run on &lt;em&gt;Saga of the Swap Thing&lt;/em&gt;, where Etrigan&amp;rsquo;s rhyming was excellently elevated to a characteristic of Hell&amp;rsquo;s lieutenants.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;The Demon&lt;/em&gt; issue 002 shows Etrigan crouched on a stone archway, which is dripping water, in a town with a medieval aesthetic or a castle square at nighttime (as the moon is visible on the horizon), ready to pounce on a group of torch-wielding citizens and a uniformed inspector. The colors are muted grays save for Etrigan&amp;rsquo;s bold yellow and red as well as the group&amp;rsquo;s orange torch light. One of the citizens says, &amp;ldquo;See&amp;ndash;no one is here&amp;ndash;Inspector!&amp;rdquo; to which the inspector replies, &amp;ldquo;But I heard something!&amp;rdquo; Above the comic&amp;rsquo;s logo reads the following: &amp;ldquo;Part man&amp;ndash;part elemental fury! He stalks the dark of night in search of fearful enemies!&amp;rdquo; Finally, a caption at the bottom of the page reads, &amp;ldquo;In the den of witches lies the fate of man! Read BATH of FIRE!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Demon-002.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to The Demon issue 002, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Demon issue 002&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I am an unabashed Kirby fan, although this may be the least revelatory comment by a superhero comic book fan, ever. His dynamic poses, sprawling epic scenes, and incredible character designs are all fantastic in every way. While &lt;em&gt;The Demon&lt;/em&gt; as a series doesn&amp;rsquo;t come close to the full-blown opera of his Fourth World story (and I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed I don&amp;rsquo;t have the full &lt;em&gt;New Gods&lt;/em&gt; series), it nonetheless blows open some really intriguing doors in regards to telling mythical/chivalric/superhero stories&amp;ndash;with characters like Klarion the Witch-boy (first appearing in issue 7) being the perfect demonstration of that potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this issue begins with a trio of explorers looking for Merlin&amp;rsquo;s long-lost crypt at a place called Castle Branek, but the trio is immediately set upon by the armored henchment of Morgaine le Fey. Etrigan happens to be nearby and joins the fight, where he promptly wrecks shop until Morgaine herself hexes him so that he cannot intervene with her plans (to steal a spell from Merlin&amp;rsquo;s tomb so that she can regain vitality).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morgain transforms Etrigan back into his human form by reciting the proper incantation (&amp;ldquo;Vanish, vanish Etrigan! Return again in form of man!&amp;rdquo;), where Jason Blood is left to die &amp;hellip; except, of course, that he has an ace up his sleeve: Randu, a friend (who appears to be Sikh, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about this) with ESP. Randu sits at Blood&amp;rsquo;s house with two other colleagues admiring Blood&amp;rsquo;s portraits of his &amp;ldquo;ancestors&amp;rdquo; (obviously they&amp;rsquo;re all him in different historical eras).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Jason comes to, with the aid of the inspector trio from the first few pages, and he realizes Merlin&amp;rsquo;s tomb is itself the &amp;ldquo;Eternity Book&amp;rdquo; that contains his spells and secrets. Merlin&amp;rsquo;s magic activates some stone gargoyle guardians, but then Merlin himself appears in a kind of astral form to try and help him remember his fight against Morgaine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Morgaine prepares a ritual to rejuvenate herself, surrounded by dancing witches, Jason and the inspector storm in on horses to disrupt the proceedings. Morgaine summons a creature called the &amp;ldquo;Gorla,&amp;rdquo; a monster with the strength of ten men, who begins whipping Jason&amp;rsquo;s ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in his apartment, Randu is compelled to read the inscription on a painting of a knight that looks like Jason, summoning Etrigan to appear and take down the Gorla &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Morgaine&amp;rsquo;s servants. (She, of course, continues her ritual despite Etrigan blasting at her with hellfire-based explosions.) There&amp;rsquo;s a page of denouement but &amp;hellip; holy crap, all of that happened in under twenty-four pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comic is &lt;em&gt;AMAZING!&lt;/em&gt; There are so many questions I have, and the series as a whole only answers some of them. Kirby is clearly interested so much more in high-concept experimentation than with a Tolkienesque complete mythos, and&amp;ndash;at least as this sort of comic&amp;ndash;things work &lt;em&gt;so much better&lt;/em&gt; this way. How unique is Etrigan? What happens when he decides to fight back against Merlin? Exactly how much do Etrigan and Jason know about one another&amp;rsquo;s activities? (Hint: Etrigan knows much more than Jason does about the other.) Why does the token POC in this comic have psychic powers, and what does that tell us about this comic, or about Kirby (similarly: see &amp;ldquo;Vykin the Black&amp;rdquo; from &lt;em&gt;The Forever People&lt;/em&gt; for another case of racist POC usage/representation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, this comic could be awful and I&amp;rsquo;d still adore it because of how Kirby set it all up. Luckily, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about having made such a compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal Man 076</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 23:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Animal-Man-076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first Vertigo post for this blog is also the first &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, Animal Man. Such a great character raised out of mediocre beginnings. Without getting &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; mired in details, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to say that Buddy Baker&amp;ndash;Animal Man&amp;ndash;can tap into the abilities of animals and make use thereof to fight injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, unlike most superheroes, he has a family (a wife, Ellen, and two children, Cliff and Maxine). This is important, because the central conflict in Buddy&amp;rsquo;s life is the tug-of-war that &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt; occurs between his desire to live a normal life with his family and his desire to use his powers in the best and most effective way possible (often to try and raise awareness about animal rights and ecological issues). This tug-of-war has led Buddy to some interesting places (for the reader, at least; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much ruined his life over and over again). At least, this is what happened to the character in the first volume of his own series; Grant Morrison set up this model and pretty much every author working on &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; since has followed suit, although they may have tweaked some specifics here and there, like looking at how Ellen deals with her completely absurd life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, Buddy went through a significant metamorphosis that left him in the body of a chimerical creature with the attributes of all kinds of animals, and he decided to use his new appearance to help found a church that would worship his daughter Maxine and her even-more-powerful animal-related powers&amp;ndash;the church is even called &amp;ldquo;The Life-Power Church of Maxine&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;set up half-seriously and half-deceptively by the Bakers and their closest friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to issue 076, then, shows Buddy in his animal-avatar form flying through a red sky over what appears to be the upraised arms/hands of an angry mob, given the tools and guns held aloft by those arms.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Animal-Man-076.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Animal Man 076, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Animal Man issue 076&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story begins with several pages narrated via in-universe comics drawn by budding cartoonist Cliff Baker, who lets us know that the Life-Power Church is on its way to Montana in search of some promised land where people and animals can live in harmony. They&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with some hunters and other critics along the way, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cartoon has been mailed to Ellen, who&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; with her family but instead with a small group of lesbian activists (that&amp;rsquo;s not a snarky, bigoted comment by me&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s how the characters were introduced and how they continue to be portrayed; a few issues before this one, Ellen notes to Buddy that she&amp;rsquo;s felt a connection growing between her and Sarah, one of the activists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the Life-Power Church is facing off against the National Guard in Nebraska (there&amp;rsquo;s references to a &amp;ldquo;plague&amp;rdquo; that has affected a number of people across the country, where they dream of themselves as animals running wild on human society), and Ellen&amp;rsquo;s conflicted between staying put with Sarah and being there in Nebraska for her family; the conversation in this scene does a pretty solid job of demonstrating various characters&amp;rsquo; takes on the situation so that no one seems to have the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;most correct&amp;rdquo; answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an equally intriguing scene between Maxine and a follower of the LFC (Ray, given the Church name &amp;ldquo;Manta Ray&amp;rdquo;) who&amp;rsquo;s secretly a government agent awaiting the order to assassinate Maxine, Buddy, or both. But she finds herself questioning her ability to murder a child if so commanded when she takes an impromptu romp/bath in a nearby river with Maxine and a throng of animal companions/guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray&amp;rsquo;s plot intertwines with that of an older man named Jack who&amp;rsquo;s looking to save his son from the LFC cult. Ray ends up getting caught by some locals who decide to rape her in the corn fields. Jack saves her, figuring that she can&amp;rsquo;t have made any poor decisions (that is, it&amp;rsquo;s not her fault she was caught and is being tortured, it&amp;rsquo;s the Church&amp;rsquo;s) that his own son didn&amp;rsquo;t make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly(?), there&amp;rsquo;s very little Buddy himself in this issue &amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t find myself disappointed by that fact. The overall story is really well fleshed out by the focus on these peripheral characters impacted by his actions from earlier issues. It really makes the world come alive in a way that you don&amp;rsquo;t get with close examinations of only a comic&amp;rsquo;s core characters. For example: we don&amp;rsquo;t ever really have that many opportunities for the development of peripheral characters in &lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;/em&gt; whose lives were affected by the actions of Batman or his rogues&amp;rsquo; gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice League Europe 008</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:10:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JUSTICE LEAGUE EUROPE! Possibly the greatest Europe-based superhero team from one of the big two comics companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Justice League Europe&lt;/em&gt; / &lt;em&gt;Justice League International&lt;/em&gt; were incredible series in the late 80s/early 90s that really embraced the goofiness of shining a spotlight on a band of B- and C-list heroes. Keith Giffen and Bart Sears worked so well together to make the comic so believable and staunchly ridiculous at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JLE featured two of my favorite DC characters: Animal Man and Metamorpho. Ralph Dibny is also great (and his partnership with his wife really should be emulated more, in terms of having a hero in a healthy committed relationship).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to this issue is suitably dramatic and goofy: members of the JLE and JLI (from left to right, at varying distances from the &amp;ldquo;camera&amp;rdquo;: Batman, Rocket Red, Captain Atom, Booster Gold, Mister Miracle, Fire, Metamorpho, Guy Gardner, Animal Man, Flash, Martian Manhunter, Power Girl, and Blue Beetle) stand, with their backs to the viewer, in the middle of a small town square, with moutnains looming in the background. There&amp;rsquo;s a large and ominous dark shadow spreading in the space between the mountains and the town. Blue Beetle says, &amp;ldquo;Uh oh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Justice-League-Europe-008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Justice League Europe #008, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Justice League Europe issue 008&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first page is a perfect demonstration of Keith Giffen&amp;rsquo;s strengths: Linda Strauss, a short-term Doctor Fate, is engaged in self-reflective exposition about her fears &amp;amp; doubts regarding taking on the Doctor Fate mantle. It&amp;rsquo;s engaging, interesting, and ends with a joke, as Giffen tends to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Order &lt;strong&gt;created&lt;/strong&gt; him [the Grey Man, antagonist for this story] &amp;hellip; Order&amp;rsquo;s responsible for the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s gone &lt;strong&gt;berserk&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;abusing&lt;/strong&gt; his power&amp;ndash;but if &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t do anything to &lt;strong&gt;stop&lt;/strong&gt; him&amp;ndash;then I guess the job&amp;rsquo;s fallen to &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;. (quietly) I think I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be sick.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the JLE and JLI stand off in a Stagg-owned compound against a horde of, and I&amp;rsquo;m serious, &amp;ldquo;zombie-vampires.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Zombie-vampires.&lt;/em&gt; This story would probably be absolutely terrible if everyone involved didn&amp;rsquo;t wholly embrace the ridiculous nature of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they finally decide to storm the compound, the zombie-vampires somehow grant energy to the Grey Man, a character who looks like a creepy uncle but manages to grow larger than the building when fueled somehow by the zombie-vampires. I remember nothing about the Grey Man while I reread this, but he has a vendetta against the forces of Order and Chaos (I assume he&amp;rsquo;s taking the &amp;ldquo;grey&amp;rdquo; middle ground between the two).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the Spectre shows up &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the embodied agents of Order and Chaos&amp;mdash;who are now united against their common foe. They promptly lobotomize him, and he&amp;rsquo;s left to wander mindlessly through the world. According to the Spectre: &amp;ldquo;[H]e will walk this world, collecting &lt;strong&gt;dream-essence&lt;/strong&gt; from the dead &amp;hellip; empty-headed, empty-hearted &amp;hellip; beyond pain &amp;hellip; beyond even &lt;strong&gt;loneliness&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; (Seriously?) The Grey Man is last seen just wandering off through an electrical fence and into the wilderness. I guess he doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to eat or anything. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad there&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;two entire super-hero teams&lt;/em&gt; nearby who could try and help him get super-institutionalized for everyone&amp;rsquo;s safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I forget what a given artist&amp;rsquo;s art style is like until I have the comic in front of me. At no point in my life have I forgotten Bart Sears&amp;rsquo; penchant to make everyone top-heavy musclemen with a billion points of light/shadow dynamic to demonstrate textures and contours. I have nostalgic love for it in &lt;em&gt;JLE&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;JLI&lt;/em&gt;, but I would not be able to abide it in probably any other comic (Sears&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;X-O Manowar&lt;/em&gt; art, for example, is so off-putting to me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, everyone who appears on the cover manages to get at least one line of dialogue, probably to keep this comic from being 96 pages long every month. I love that Grant Morrison busts on this balancing act in the pages of &lt;em&gt;Animal Man&lt;/em&gt; when Buddy is asked to recognize the fact that he really only ever shows up in &lt;em&gt;JLE&lt;/em&gt; to say/do one or two things in any given adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I want to read more of my Giffen-era &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt; back issues to enjoy the best friendly relationship DC&amp;rsquo;s ever had: Blue Beetle &amp;amp; Booster Gold. (Sorry, it&amp;rsquo;s superior to Batman &amp;amp; Superman&amp;rsquo;s longtime partnership.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shazam 018 (1973)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:31:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Shazam-018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just by looking at the title, I can tell that issue 18 from the 1973 run of &lt;em&gt;Shazam!&lt;/em&gt; (the first DC title with Captain Marvel/Shazam after acquiring Fawcett&amp;rsquo;s characters) is going to be amazing: Captain Marvel is lifting up part of a house while asking, &amp;ldquo;Who called &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt; for help?&amp;rdquo; In response, a frog&amp;mdash;held in someone&amp;rsquo;s hand&amp;mdash;replies, &amp;ldquo;*Ribit* I did!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in a note at the bottom right corner, we get a hint of what the issue will involve: &amp;ldquo;The celebrated talking frog of Blackstone Forest!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sold.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Shazam-018.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Shazam 018, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Shazam! issue 018&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also worth noting that, like Doctor Strange (covered briefly in &lt;a href=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016&#34;&gt;my previous review&lt;/a&gt;, I am a big fan of Captain Marvel&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for me to refer to him as Shazam, even if DC has since retconned the character&amp;rsquo;s name. Grant Morrison, in his book &lt;em&gt;Supergods&lt;/em&gt;, describes the appeal in this way: &amp;ldquo;Captain Marvel’s power came not from years in the gym or from his alien biology or his royal blood. His power came from a spell. He was a magician&amp;rdquo; (from ch. 2). That is, it&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely the average comic reader is secretly an orphan from an alien world or heir to a billion-dollar empire. But anyone, anyone at all, can turn down the wrong street corner and discover a magic word that will transform them into Captain Marvel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, it may be unsurprising that the depiction of Captain Marvel in &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt; speaks powerfully to me, as grownup Billy Batson has never really emotionally matured (although he never got the chance to, in this story), has been lied to/corrupted/twisted by dark forces, but who nonetheless redeems himself to help everyone when it&amp;rsquo;s necessary. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the former Catholic in me speaking, but &amp;hellip; how is that not an incredible fate towards which to aspire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s open this issue up and check out the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Page 1 reminds me that I forgot about one of the greatest comic characters ever: TAWKY TAWNY, a talking bipedal tiger who wears suits (in the &amp;lsquo;70s, these were terrible plaid suits with floral ties) and hangs out with the Marvel family. He has no super-powers or remarkable skills, other than possessing opposable thumbs so as to get dressed. No one bats an eye at his existence. This is the greatness of comic books distilled into a character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A related demonstration of comics greatness is in Dr. Kilowatt&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Brain-o-meter,&amp;rdquo; an intelligence-measuring device employed to check the smarts of the talking frog found by Tawny in the woods. (Of course, the frog &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; talks to Tawny, in a move that&amp;rsquo;s a clear ripoff of both the racist Warner Bros. dancing &amp;amp; singing frog cartoon and the fairy tale about the frog prince.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, we&amp;rsquo;re only &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; into this comic. Luckily, the plot amps up as RUSSIAN SPIES are brought in to &amp;ldquo;frog-nap&amp;rdquo; the talking frog to learn how they might improve human intelligence. When the spy tries to abscond with the frog, Captain Marvel destroys his helicopter&amp;rsquo;s rotors &amp;hellip; only to take the place of the rotos as a &amp;ldquo;marvel-copter.&amp;rdquo; The illustration of this feat is easily the single best moment of the comic, and now I&amp;rsquo;m only &lt;em&gt;halfway&lt;/em&gt; through this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, there&amp;rsquo;s an equally amazing moment two pages later when the frog transforms back into a prince and he looks like a froggish human&amp;mdash;so much so that other characters comment on it. Harsh! (This is also the end of the first story, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect, although I&amp;rsquo;m stoked to see a Captain Marvel Jr. story as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I totally forgot about the existence of Sivana Jr., the son of Dr. Sivana. It makes sense that Captain Marvel and Sivana would have a feud spanning generations&amp;mdash;so, naturally, to fight the teenage Captain Marvel Jr. (aka &amp;ldquo;CM3&amp;rdquo;), Sivana Jr. appears to be in his 60s. In this backup story, he has the technology to blow &lt;em&gt;square bubbles&lt;/em&gt; that can trap CM3 in their &amp;ldquo;elastic plastic&amp;rdquo; after Sivana Jr.&amp;rsquo;s first effort (a super-strong bed-spring coil) fails. Of course, the &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; plan involves mind-control devices that resemble half-dollars, and Sivana Jr. turns an initial failure into an ingenious plan when he realizes he can convince/hypnotize Freddie Freeman not to say the magic words that transform him (&amp;ldquo;Captain Marvel,&amp;rdquo; the name of his hero).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In even more ingenious comic logic, Freddie realizes he can&amp;rsquo;t say his own alter-ego&amp;rsquo;s name. Of course, this semantic nuance is the center of many CM3 plots, since he can&amp;rsquo;t technically provide his own name (when Captain Marvel Jr.) to authorities or fellow super-heroes, since that would transform him back into Freddie Freeman. Poor CM3. As an aside, I wonder if he may be the first superhero&amp;mdash;definitely one of the first superheroes&amp;mdash;to have a visible disability that&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;blindness but can see in the dark&amp;rdquo; like Dr. Midnight or the Black Bat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I could ever dislike a golden/silver/bronze-age Shazam story, because they&amp;rsquo;re so optimistic and fun and take for granted that a comic book world doesn&amp;rsquo;t and can&amp;rsquo;t make sense realistically. Billy, Freddie, and Mary are all kids who represent the fun of superheroes, and the kids themselves are always central to the story, with the hero identities there to solve problems when they have no other means of doing so themselves. Of course, I similarly love the Moore &amp;amp; Gaiman &lt;em&gt;Marvelman&lt;/em&gt; stories that take these character ideas in new directions (including a take on CM3&amp;rsquo;s more likely approach to being a hero by &lt;em&gt;staying in that identity forever if possible&lt;/em&gt;), but I&amp;rsquo;ve never really felt the need to check out the more recent (2000s) DC Comics take(s) on Shazam and family. I guess I should, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be incredibly disappointed by a move away from what I see as one of the greatest characters ever. Although I suppose, at least, I should check out the Morrison &lt;em&gt;Multiversity: Thunderworld&lt;/em&gt; comic to see what he&amp;rsquo;d do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>