<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/marvel/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/marvel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cable 011</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 19:58:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s review features Cable, a character that, along with Deadpool, has somehow managed to survive the &amp;lsquo;90s boom that spawned him. I was never fully sold on the &lt;strong&gt;extreme&lt;/strong&gt; nature of the Liefeld X-Force, but I suppose I get why Cable remains interesting to many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was, for some time, the consummate 1980s action hero ideal, a &amp;ldquo;mystery man&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;tactical badass&amp;rdquo; that speaks directly to the fantasies of the stereotypical superhero comic consumer. Plus, he has a cool eye scar and a metal arm! (Ironically, I think the Magog design for &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt;, meant to play on all the Cable-era tropes that Waid &amp;amp; Ross hated, is much more awesome.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since his introduction, Cable&amp;rsquo;s been fleshed out a lot more, and the &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; series that this issue (discussed more below) comes from has a really interesting initial story premise: Cable has to flee to the future with a special infant girl, who is supposed to one day be the mutant messiah, and he tries to keep her alive while mutant cop/ethnic cleanser Bishop chases them both through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; #011 features an image of young Hope Summers in front of a white background, where she is dressed in an adorably ill-fitting X-Men uniform resembling Cable&amp;rsquo;s outfit (complete with giant shoulder pads) and wielding an oversized gun of some sort &amp;hellip; maybe a sawed-off gatling gun or something?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Cable-011.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Cable 011, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cable issue 011&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Okay, so when this issue begins, Cable has taken Hope (although in the comic Hope does not yet have a name) to an oasis-like settlement in a post-apocalyptic hellscape populated by vicious insectoid beings (called &amp;ldquo;the cockroach army&amp;rdquo; by Cable). Cable has a wife named Hope, met during one of the time-jumps made by Cable and the child he&amp;rsquo;s protecting, who ends up dying during a bandit attack, and so he names the child Hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining humans devise a bomb or gas or something to destroy the cockroaches, but Cable worries they&amp;rsquo;ll kill the humans too. So, he and Hope jump a hundred years into the future, surrounded by salt flats and human skeletons. The image (a two-page spread) is actually pretty incredible, the clean art style juxtaposed with the apocalyptic horror and Hope&amp;rsquo;s vomiting from the experience of sliding through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: this issue, more than many before it in this series, really calls to mind the Futurama episode where Fry, Professor Farnsworth, and Bender use a time machine and witness the end of the universe. (Like the Futurama crew, Cable can only jump into the future.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I enjoyed this series (picking up the first twenty or so issues from a dollar bin) in part because Cable is depicted stylistically so far from his Liefeld origins: no ludicrous thigh pouches, consistent realistic proportions, and his relationship with the child Hope is really believable: he&amp;rsquo;s clearly come around from seeing this as a duty put upon him to a genuine parental concern for her well-being. It&amp;rsquo;s like an X-Men version of &lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt;, and I mean that as a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one page, there&amp;rsquo;s a moment that &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be a reference to Philip K. Dick&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Second Variety&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Cable hunts a wolf that turns out to be a machine with a wolf&amp;rsquo;s external appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, the focus on Cable and Hope is really quite enjoyable. The conflict is almost entirely on Cable trying to decide what sorts of details to tell Hope about the past and her potential destiny (along with details about child development and puberty) rather than on forcing gunfights and explosions and whatnot into the mix. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of characterization here, and maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the sheer lack of possible distractions that has made it possible or my interest in depressing apocalyptic wasteland stories, but &amp;hellip; yeah, I dig this issue. This Cable is so much more interesting than when he was a mix of Kyle Reese and the Terminator but with no real backstory to lean on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of Kung Fu 071</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 23:21:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shang-Chi, the master of kung fu, is one of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s greatest martial arts characters, and one who was born during the company&amp;rsquo;s 1970s-era efforts to exploit the martial arts movie craze (although I admit I&amp;rsquo;m a bigger fan of Shang-Chi frenemy Shen Kuei, &amp;ldquo;the Cat&amp;rdquo;). This series is definitely a reflection of that time, and it&amp;rsquo;s Doug Moench&amp;rsquo;s magnum opus (although, sadly, this particular issue doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature Paul Gulacy, whose work meshed excellently with Moench, although the artist here, Mike Zeck, also does a solid job with the kung fu/espionage style the book goes for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the character&amp;rsquo;s world even more incredible, it&amp;rsquo;s filled with a cast of pulp homages: Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s father is Fu Manchu (although Marvel lost the rights to the character, so he&amp;rsquo;s not actually called that&amp;mdash;or any other&amp;mdash;name any more, instead referred to by vague descriptions), and Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s super-spy BFF, MI-6 agent Clive Reston, is &lt;em&gt;heavily implied&lt;/em&gt; to be the son of James Bond, while his mentor Sir Denis Nayland-Smith (an enemy of Fu Manchu&amp;rsquo;s) is suggested to be a relative of Sherlock Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so &lt;em&gt;MoKF&lt;/em&gt; 071. This issue has an incredible cover&amp;mdash;Shang-Chi is posed ready for a fight, barefoot and clad only in his red pants and bandana, in front of a giant yin-yang symbol. The background is also a massive jigsaw puzzle whose pieces begin to fall apart near the bottom of the image. (There&amp;rsquo;s a jigsaw motif running through this issue, just FYI.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Master of Kung Fu 071, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Master of Kung Fu issue 071&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue opens with a fantastic two-page spread wherein Shang-Chi recaps a bunch of recent storylines, all laid out as interlocking jigsaw pieces. The next several pages explore Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s coming to terms with various close relationships (a love interest, Juliette; even more intense and long-term love interest, Leiko Wu; and BFF Clive Reston) and the changes that had occurred in regards to each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, this issue then segues into a conversation scene while Shang-Chi and Leiko (who&amp;rsquo;s been putting together a jigsaw puzzle of a yin-yang symbol) share a pizza. After they eat, they visit a martial arts studio and engage in a friendly bout to exercise &amp;amp; train, making an impressive enough showing that all the other individuals present stop to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After they go to a movie and return home, the comic ends on a cliffhanger where a battered Sir Denis bursts into their home, seeking help with supposed corruption in the MI-6 agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not a tremendous amount of action in this comic, but that&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing. Shang-Chi has always been depicted as an extremely introspective character who seeks a path to enlightenment and peace with every action he takes and every phenomenon he witnesses. That he reflects on a number of the major plots in the comic so far is a totally human move (in addition to having the practical effect of catching up newer readers to the series&amp;rsquo; progression). I found myself nodding along, persuaded by Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s line of reasoning as he attempted to make sense of the insanity that is life in a pulp comic book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt; is a series that I try to collect through dollar bins; I know that Marvel has recently begun reprinting the series in massive omnibus form, but, given its content and focus, the comic really seems best experienced when one is exposed to the feel and smell of crappy older comic paper. It just seems appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Into Mystery 646</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 16:09:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; was the comic in which Thor first appeared, and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome that Marvel revived this title in order to make space for Asgard tales (the &amp;ldquo;Tales from Asgard&amp;rdquo; in the back of older &lt;em&gt;Thor&lt;/em&gt; comics were great, but wayyyyy too short to enjoy thoroughly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember buying this comic from a dollar bin in 2014 or maybe 2015. The cover alone made it worth the price: Lady Sif looks totally badass, striding directly toward the viewer in a suit of battle armor&amp;mdash;mostly practical, too! only a bit of naked thigh that could be armored further, beneath her Greek-style skirt&amp;mdash;and wielding a sword in each hand. The use of color here (mostly grayscale except for the red of Sif&amp;rsquo;s cape, armor, and highlighting in the &lt;em&gt;JIM&lt;/em&gt; logo) helps make it stand out; there&amp;rsquo;s a similar phenomenon happening with the cover design to the current &lt;em&gt;Scarlet Witch&lt;/em&gt; series, and I really wish I could get the covers to those issues as prints.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Journey-Into-Mystery-646.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Journey Into Mystery 646, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Journey Into Mystery issue 646&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Inside, the indicia page has a hilarious narration accompanying a large, similarly red-toned, image of Sif that rips off an exchange from &lt;em&gt;Shaft&lt;/em&gt; (and does so less skillfully, since the initial question is so wordy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s the sword-wielding woman who&amp;rsquo;s a soldier on the battlefield and a lady in Asgardia, but no one understands her but her thunder god?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;SIF!&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Verily. Can you dig it?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;We can dig it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This certainly sets the stage for an entertaining reading experience. Turning the page, I find myself wondering what, exactly is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asgard is in ruins and Sif is helping with some sort of rescue/relief effort. I think that this story probably takes place after&amp;mdash;or, more likely, during&amp;mdash;Ragnarok (which, if I recall, had occurred in the Thor comics around this time); Sif suggests as much when she notes that the demon Surtur had come to wreck shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif rescues a child, says she&amp;rsquo;s had enough child-minding for the day after turning the child over to other helpers, and then promptly(? there&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Days Hence&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; caption, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell just how much time has passed) goes to dinner at the child&amp;rsquo;s house, visiting an entire home &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with children. There are some interesting conversations about the best way to fight (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Fighting&amp;rsquo;s for &lt;strong&gt;kids&lt;/strong&gt;. You should use your &lt;strong&gt;words&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;ldquo;) and about 1950s-era &lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; comics, which apparently exist and populate care packages given to Asgardians by the Red Cross (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, Sif travels to Niffleheim to find a sleeping dragon who might have information for her about some ancient warriors of legend, as she has &amp;ldquo;a record of a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; battle with &lt;strong&gt;greater&lt;/strong&gt; warriors still who fought so fiercely those who saw them said they seemed &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to be men at &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; She says this while sitting on the shoulder of a &lt;em&gt;giant dragon&lt;/em&gt; that she reached only after taking down a bunch of Niffleheim&amp;rsquo;s resident predators. I can only imagine how incredible these other warriors she&amp;rsquo;s looking for must have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif eventually gets the info she needs and casts a spell to talk to the warriors&amp;rsquo; teacher &amp;hellip; supposedly to learn the &amp;ldquo;berserker incantation&amp;rdquo; and, I assume, save Asgard? I think I&amp;rsquo;m right, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really invested in this story&amp;mdash;and I say that as someone who &lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Asgardian characters and tales. I do, however, dig that Sif is apparently willing to compromise all over the place in order to save her home, and the idea of Sif becoming an uncontrollable berserker seems excellent at face value (I mean, literally the first thing she does is kill the person who just taught her the berserker incantation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story ends (technically, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) with her in a tavern in &amp;ldquo;the unluckiest town in Midgard&amp;rdquo; with a bloody bag (presumably the teacher&amp;rsquo;s head) on a stool next to her while she asks for another drink. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a serious &lt;em&gt;Superman III&lt;/em&gt; vibe here and I love it. Now this is a story I&amp;rsquo;m interested in continuing! Unfortunately, I can&amp;rsquo;t recall offhand if I bought any more issues in this storyline, which at the moment is a shame, because I was definitely brought around from a plot I initially didn&amp;rsquo;t find that interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme 016 (1988)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 23:04:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps fitting that the first comic randomly selected to serve as a review post is a &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comic, since I have long adored the character. (I used to have more comics featuring Doctor Strange than any other, but I&amp;rsquo;ve since collected far more Green Lantern-related comics &amp;hellip; so expect a few of those to make appearances.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover, shown below, is suitably interesting: Baron Blood has thrown(?) or is otherwise causing Doctor Strange to be flung upside-down through the night sky, off of some jungle or forest cliff, with a large, full moon illuminating everything from the background. Baron Blood has some seriously long underarm wings here, like he learned about Batman&amp;rsquo;s cape or something.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue, titled &amp;ldquo;Love and Haiti&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (classic Marvel pun?). There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love: Roy Thomas (partially) on writing duties. A cast that includes Morbius, Marie LaVeau the &amp;ldquo;Voodoo Queen,&amp;rdquo; Baron Blood, and Brother Voodoo. It is, unfortunately, the middle point of a five-issue arc, so there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; backstory to catch up readers, but other details are left unstated&amp;ndash;although I never felt like I was really lost at any point. This issue (from 1990) is well before the era of plot decompression for the sake of publishing an eventual TPB collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art by Jackson Guice seems very &amp;ldquo;workhorse&amp;rdquo; in comparison to the early &amp;lsquo;90s Image style explosion, but I appreciate it now in a way that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could have at age 9 (not that I owned it then&amp;ndash;I think I picked up this issue in a lot of &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comics around 2001). Stephen Strange looks like an older doctor. Poses seem relatively realistic, save for when characters/phenomena suggest they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be (like someone floating upside-down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awkward moment: during a fight with vampires&amp;ndash;in an alley in Port-au-Prince, of course&amp;ndash;Morgana Blessing calls out both to &amp;ldquo;Mr. Drumm&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dr. Morbius&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; poor Brother Voodoo getting &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; credit for his educational credentials until he took up the mantle of Sorcerer Supreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome moment: Dracula making a &lt;em&gt;phone call&lt;/em&gt; in order to set up an attack on an enemy. This is easily the best dialogue of the issue (the panel art is similarly wonderful):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dracula: &amp;ldquo;I want you to set a &lt;strong&gt;trap&lt;/strong&gt; for my accursed descendant, &lt;strong&gt;Frank Drake&lt;/strong&gt;, upon his arrival in Brazil. You will be richly rewarded.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danny Summers: &amp;ldquo;You bet your bat I will, Drac! &lt;strong&gt;Danny Summers&lt;/strong&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t do &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, I found myself really annoyed that Baron Blood, despite having an absolutely fantastic character name, has a pretty weak schtick&amp;ndash;or, at least, they really play up his weaknesses in this issue. If he changed up his costume&amp;rsquo;s color scheme, he might seem more intimidating. If he seemed like more of a mastermind, he might seem more dangerous. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t know: has Baron Blood ever been the big threat in a horror-oriented story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I think Doctor Strange casts a total of three spells in this issue, and none of them really plays up the surreal trip that Ditko originally demonstrated could (and &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;) be at the center of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s arcane/occult aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with luck my future reviews will become more coherent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>