<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marvel on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/marvel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marvel on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 21:20:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/marvel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Avengers (1998) 062</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Avengers-062/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 21:20:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Avengers-062/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I am a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; fan of Kurt Busiek&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt; comic, I never really found myself getting into his run on &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; (the second or third volume) while it happened. (I think at the time I was really into Bendis&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt; and Morrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;New X-Men&lt;/em&gt; instead, since they were more blatantly and fully pushing back against some of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s status quo.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, in retrospect, this issue is fantastic, but not because it&amp;rsquo;s an &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; comic. It&amp;rsquo;s fantastic because it very clearly and precisely sets up a parallel narrative for Ant-Man (Scott Lang) and Jack of Hearts (Jack Hart &amp;hellip; yeah).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover features the two squaring off in a scene from the story&amp;rsquo;s climax: Ant-Man stands on the left, helmet off and in one hand, the other pointed at Jack of Hearts; Ant-Man grits his teeth tensely. Similarly, Jack of Hearts, who&amp;rsquo;s on the right, stares back angrily and grits his teeth too. The background is comprised of speed/motion lines that keep the focus on the two heroes&amp;rsquo; faces.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Avengers-062.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Avengers 062, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Avengers issue 062&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story reflects Busiek&amp;rsquo;s best work: explorations of character that keep the best and most important dramatic points centered on the protagonist(s) of a given tale. In this case, Jack of Hearts struggles with the problems he faces&amp;ndash;namely, that every day he has to spend so many hours in a cell with seven-foot-thick walls because he eventually discharges a daily burst of energy not unlike a nuclear bomb going off. During this story, Iron Man tells him that each day&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;cell time&amp;rdquo; will need to increase from 10 to 14 hours. As you might imagine, Jack doesn&amp;rsquo;t take this well &amp;hellip; and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that it turns out his father, who died during an accident connected to Jack, had been trying to save him (Jack thought he&amp;rsquo;d been focused on work instead of family).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Ant-Man is called to court to attend a custody hearing for his daughter Cassie (who would later become the hero Stature), because his ex-wife argues that his life is too dangerous to have his daughter around. The judge agrees, taking into consideration the Avengers&amp;rsquo; nigh-constant efforts to deal with global emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having lost his daughter, Ant-Man heads to the Avengers mansion to see about joining up with them officially (as he&amp;rsquo;d performed some &amp;ldquo;unofficial&amp;rdquo; or &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; teamup work with them before this point). Jack of Hearts shows up and is angry that Ant-Man is offered a spot on the team freely, since he felt he&amp;rsquo;d had to struggle to join. The two butt heads but Iron Man and the Wasp manage to defuse the situation. Each of the combatants heads to his room (or cell) and is left alone with his thoughts, having nothing else really to build a life around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty brutal story, but I mean that in a good way. I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought Jack of Hearts was a lame character, but he&amp;rsquo;s given some significant depth here&amp;ndash;I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s not like the &lt;em&gt;character&lt;/em&gt; ever had any say about possessing such a lame origin&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s juxtaposed very interestingly against Ant-Man&amp;rsquo;s problems. The tragedy, of course, is that Ant-Man and Jack of Hearts could very easily find friendship and solace in one another, but they&amp;rsquo;re so caught up in their individual drama that they can&amp;rsquo;t&amp;ndash;or won&amp;rsquo;t&amp;ndash;acknowledge the other&amp;rsquo;s issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recognize this is also the kind of story that can&amp;rsquo;t be told all the time in a flagship series like &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt;, especially now in an era following the runaway success of the Marvel Cinematic Universe (and it&amp;rsquo;s at least in part because of the lack of such a franchise connection that allows this kind of story to flourish regularly in &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt;) &amp;hellip; but I really am glad I picked this up back when it was released. Even if it did take me over a decade to really find solid enjoyment in it. What can I say? I should have paid better attention back in the early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daredevil 075</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Daredevil-075/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 23:23:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Daredevil-075/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daredevil is a character I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought was great, and this volume (running from roughly 1998-2011 or so?) is absolutely &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt;. A blind superhero whose existence is anathema to his sworn profession as a lawyer? Sign me up. Oh, he&amp;rsquo;s also a Catholic? and wants to protect his &lt;em&gt;neighborhood&lt;/em&gt; rather than the world? Yeah, this is the recipe for an amazing comic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to begin picking up this particular series when Brian Bendis took over on issue 26, and I followed it for several years (until the mid-60s issues) and have been trying to complete the run since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bendis&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt; run is arguably the best that the character&amp;rsquo;s ever had. I know a lot of people point to Frank Miller, who really did do an admirable job shifting the focus of the comic toward gritty crime and personal angst, but Bendis cranked that shit up to 11 and broke off the knob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bendis has always been best when writing crime or street-level action, and his pairing with Alex Maleev through this run hit all the high notes one might expect: the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s life is ruined in a number of baffling and suspenseful ways (with the FBI coloring in a Daredevil mask over a photo of Matt&amp;rsquo;s face successfully blowing my mind the first time I read it), there are numerous brutal brawls depicted, and everyone engages in believable&amp;ndash;if somewhat abundant&amp;ndash;dialogue. (The biggest downside to Bendis&amp;rsquo; approach to this comic is that it paved the way for significant &amp;ldquo;decompression&amp;rdquo; of story arcs stretched across numerous comic issues in anticipation of eventual trade collections.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to issue 075 is mostly stark white, with a rough cross shape painted in black and red (making the silhouette of Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s mask and eye slots visible in its form) next to a black-and-red phrase that also displays the silhouette in its space: &amp;ldquo;Thou shall not KILL&amp;rdquo; it reads, with the first three words in type and &amp;ldquo;KILL&amp;rdquo; in scrawled or brushed script. Along the top of the page, just under the &lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt; logo, are the words &amp;ldquo;Decalogue Part V.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Daredevil-075.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Daredevil 075, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Daredevil issue 075&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This issue serves as the finale to the &amp;ldquo;Decalogue&amp;rdquo; storyline, which involves a church support group meeting to discuss the impact Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s had on their lives&amp;ndash;as well as their potential interaction with some seemingly demonic entity. In the previous issues, everyone goes around the room, alternating between telling their stories and arguing about the relevance or significance of their experiences. At the end of issue 74, one of the group members&amp;ndash;the slimiest and most obviously suspicious one&amp;ndash;points out that Matt Murdock has been sitting among them, seemingly able to mask his presence from everyone. They all freak out, naturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to mention that, at this point in the overall run, Matt&amp;rsquo;s identity as Daredevil is &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; in the sense that the press&amp;ndash;via an FBI agent contact&amp;ndash;claimed he was Daredevil, and he prepared for the case. It was dropped, however, when the Kingpin murdered the newspaper&amp;rsquo;s owner. Not long afterward, Daredevil savagely beat up the Kingpin in public and declared &lt;em&gt;himself&lt;/em&gt; the new kingpin of Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen while standing over the Kingpin&amp;rsquo;s unconscious body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year or so has passed in-story since that happened. One might imagine that the residents of Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen would be a little freaked out about such an individual in their midst. One would be correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt reveals that he&amp;rsquo;s been tracking a presence of some kind that he first encountered when fighting laughable rogue The Jester, who acted strangely and vomited out a weird being that resembled a fetus with an ugly monster face. (Despite how disgusting it is, the shot of the Jester vomiting out the creature is top-notch.) This being would later find and inhabit another individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suspicious member of the church group, a man named Lawrence, supposedly sold the being to the Jester as a source of mystical power, having learned the trick from some martial arts school that had fallen far out of favor. It turns out that now &lt;em&gt;he&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; the one with the being inside him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt chased down Lawrence, who fled the group, but he was unable to stop Lawrence from killing himself&amp;ndash;and the being&amp;ndash;with a gun. Returning to the group, Matt let them know what had happened and that now they all had the closure they sought. He also noted that he was not so concerned about his identity being revealed because he figured he would die before completing the work he wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visually, this comic is so ridiculously impressive. I have loved every bit of art from Alex Maleev I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, and he has a knack for interpreting Bendis&amp;rsquo; scripts to really successful effect. Some people hate the technique he and other artists use to repeat certain images to suggest someone has been talking for a long time, but for Bendis&amp;rsquo; dialogue it works so well. (There&amp;rsquo;s just a lot of it!) Further, his representations of Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s fights look real and nasty and painful to engage in. Matt&amp;rsquo;s fighting style looks like the style of someone who grew up learning boxing, even if it&amp;rsquo;s mixed now with a lot of eastern martial arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Decalogue&amp;rdquo; is the penultimate arc, I think, for Bendis&amp;rsquo; run, and the whole thing is an absurdly enjoyable and suspenseful roller coaster. No one has turned Matt&amp;rsquo;s life upside-down more fully (and yes, I have not forgotten Miller&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Born Again&amp;rdquo; arc) and put him in increasingly worse/shitty situations where he acts out to realize the worst possible outcome of these situations. It&amp;rsquo;s long form cinematic drama in the best sense, and I make sure to re-read this run once or twice a year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange 072</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 22:44:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, a note: my random number generator seems to keep pointing me to issues numbering in the 70s. An interesting trend so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so, more Doctor Strange! And this time, it&amp;rsquo;s from the 1970s-80s series (a predecessor to the series discussed in my earlier Doctor Strange review).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; #072 shows Doctor Strange, with an absolutely &lt;em&gt;metal&lt;/em&gt; beard, wrapped in the tentacles of some green Lovecraftian creature whose limbs and cilia are writhing about. Doctor Strange gestures with one hand to fire some pink energy at his opponent.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-072.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange 072, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange issue 072&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The story apparently starts in the Dark Dimension, or some related dimension, as we learn that Umar (Dormammu&amp;rsquo;s sister) is extracting tribute (aka taxes) in the form of mystic energy from her subjects. Technically, her tax collectors are doing this, on a platform in a public square that looks like it doubles as a French Revolution-era guillotine stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Strange has the best cloak/robe I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen him in (as he&amp;rsquo;s undercover or otherwise incognito, it appears), and&amp;ndash;again&amp;ndash;his hair looks &lt;em&gt;dope as hell&lt;/em&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to understate this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Doctor Strange and a handful of rebels storm the tax collector&amp;rsquo;s stage and collect the paid tributes (which have been condensed into small orbs or coins). Naturally, the citizens are a little pissed. There&amp;rsquo;s a really disturbing coincidental parallel to recent affairs, I think. Consider this exchange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Your rebellion&amp;rsquo;s public support is still somewhat lacking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rahl (a rebel)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;I know. The problem is that Umar has made herself appear benevolent and gracious to the people of the Dark Dimension. And after her brother&amp;rsquo;s reign of terror, there&amp;rsquo;s an illusion of good feeling in the realm. Things seem better to those who enjoy full citizenship, and so they&amp;rsquo;re afraid to support us. They fear that things might go back to the way they were!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Then your most urgent goal is to get the people to see Umar for what she really is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this goal is punctuated by an immediate need to fight some Mindless Ones, so at least there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of magical combat for the reader uninterested in interdimensional politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: the password chosen by Clea for entry into the rebels&amp;rsquo; stronghold is &amp;ldquo;Yo, Adriene &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s me, Rocky!&amp;rdquo; because&amp;ndash;according to Clea&amp;ndash;she chose an Earth-based pop culture reference (&amp;ldquo;things I remembered from your television, Stephen&amp;rdquo;) with the assumption that Umar&amp;rsquo;s subjects would never be able to guess it. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I&amp;rsquo;m shocked Doctor Strange has a television. I mean, he seems the type who&amp;rsquo;d be just snobby enough to pride himself in not watching TV and instead getting news updates and whatever from benevolent imp messengers or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, back on Earth, apparently Wong has to shut down the advances of Sara, an attractive girl who appears to be trying her best to engage Wong in a genuine relationship despite his unnerving dedication to being Doctor Strange&amp;rsquo;s manservant. (I mean, surely the good doctor would &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; his closest friend and companion to seek out intimate companionship, right?!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we&amp;rsquo;re only halfway through this story, and I have no clue what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Umar does her best, and fails, to spy on Strange through scrying magics. She does at least have a minor epiphany that he may be &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt;, including in her own dimension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Strange and Rahl go to visit the prisoner Orini&amp;ndash;Clea&amp;rsquo;s father, and Umar loyalist? I admit I am unfamiliar with this character&amp;ndash;and Strange uses the Eye of Agamotto to magically coerce Orini to give up the secrets of Umar&amp;rsquo;s army. Also, we learn the shocking revelation that Clea&amp;rsquo;s mother is Umar herself, having slept with Orini and abandoned the baby with him after Clea&amp;rsquo;s birth. Naturally, Clea is a bit taken aback by this when Strange informs her of the news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the rebels decide to storm one of Umar&amp;rsquo;s caravans (which looks &lt;em&gt;hilarious&lt;/em&gt; as an Oregon Trail-style wagon train with giant lizard beasts of burden and moving along on a Ditkoesque floating pathway), Clea frees her father to have a conversation with him as parent and child. He promptly beats the hell out of her, or so we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to assume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, there is an &lt;strong&gt;awesome&lt;/strong&gt; mystical moment where a caravan guard throws a canvas that, as it unfurls, opens a &amp;ldquo;portable warp&amp;rdquo; through which emerges a creature&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m guessing the monster from the cover&amp;ndash;that has a sharp beak and looks a lot like the alien from &lt;em&gt;Watchmen&lt;/em&gt; sans eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Doctor Strange tries to intervene and help the rebels, he is pulled &amp;hellip; somewhere else (it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say, since the background is all black) &amp;hellip; by &amp;ldquo;the outcasts,&amp;rdquo; creatures of various species, or so I gather (they have different hands/limbs, but we can&amp;rsquo;t see any of their facial features), who want to keep themselves hidden from Umar. When Strange says he wants to help regardless, they let him know it&amp;rsquo;s too late&amp;ndash;the rebels have fallen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a second cliffhanger moment, Orini arrives at Umar&amp;rsquo;s palace, bringing an unconscious Clea to his former lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story was dope, and is packed with some essential Doctor Strange plot tropes as well as moving along some character development for Clea and the residents of the Dark Dimension in general. I really wish Doctor Strange grew his hair out this way in the comics&amp;ndash;it really adds some metal/punk aesthetic to a character that is so often depicted as being very conservative in personal style, even despite the focus of his life&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Comics Presents 072</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 17:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Comics Presents&lt;/em&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt;) is a series that interested me for the longest time: it was an anthology comic that tended to have four stories (each 8 pages) of varying length, by which I mean that one story might have 8-10 parts, another might have 4-6, another might only be a single 8-page story, and so on. So a reader was likely to get some really fascinating story turnover in any given collection of issues. When I was young, &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; introduced me to some characters that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever would have checked out otherwise, most notably (for me) Shang-Chi, but also minor characters like Stingray or the Collective Man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary story of many &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; issues featured Wolverine&amp;ndash;unsurprising, given his ability to sell pretty much any comic where he appeared on the cover. &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; 072, however, is important because it begins the tale of an incredibly significant part of Wolverine&amp;rsquo;s backstory, written &amp;amp; drawn by Barry Windsor-Smith: the Weapon X experiments that bonded adamantium to his skeleton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover for issue 072, like all of the &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; covers, is wraparound, with the primary (Wolverine) story featured on the front and the characters of the other three stories&amp;ndash;Daredevil, Shanna the She-Devil, and Red Wolf&amp;ndash;on the back. On the front half, Wolverine stands, the right half of his body covered by his classic brown-and-yellow suit, and his left half naked with a number of protruding spikes in preparation for his adamantium injections. Behind him is a large skull (likely his own), with similar spikes. Flames beneath a blank blue canvas comprise the background, layered (from top down) yellow, orange, and red. At the top of the page, below the comic&amp;rsquo;s title/logo, are the words: &amp;ldquo;Before Wolverine there was Weapon X.&amp;rdquo; On the back half of the cover, Shanna is posed crouching (with a caption box that declares &amp;ldquo;Her &lt;strong&gt;jungle&lt;/strong&gt; reeks of &lt;strong&gt;evil&lt;/strong&gt;, and SHANNA must &lt;strong&gt;confront&lt;/strong&gt; it.&amp;ldquo;), while Red Wolf leaps behind her, up and to her left (captioned &amp;ldquo;RED WOLF &lt;strong&gt;faces&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;death&lt;/strong&gt; of his &lt;strong&gt;partner Lobo&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;ldquo;). Behind her, down and to the right, Daredevil similarly jumps forward, swinging his billy club (caption: &amp;ldquo;DAREDEVIL is &lt;strong&gt;helpless&lt;/strong&gt; when things come to a &lt;strong&gt;head&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;New York&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;). What appears to be the back side of the large skull from the front cover looms behind the figures.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Marvel Comics Presents 072, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Marvel Comics Presents issue 072&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Weapon X&amp;rdquo; story in this issue must have been &lt;em&gt;ridiculously&lt;/em&gt; confusing to everyone when it initially came out, since it consists of three threads: (1) Wolverine down on his luck in the Yukon, drinking and getting in fights; (2) flashes of the Weapon X experiments themselves, provided without explanation/context; (3) panels of a scientist performing some sort of experiment that may or may not be (but almost certainly is) related to the Weapon X project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually pick up this issue until last year, but I already knew the general beats to this story. I have to say, in its serialized form, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed since there&amp;rsquo;s no real room for anything to breathe here (although I get that BWS is trying to let things unfold in a somewhat-similar manner to Logan&amp;rsquo;s ability to comprehend what happened to him). The art style and the narration is solid&amp;ndash;it does its job of leaving me wanting more. I&amp;rsquo;m just torn in both wanting more and not feeling like I really had &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; in this portion to really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shanna comic provided is part 5 of its story. I&amp;rsquo;m stoked going in because there&amp;rsquo;s Paul Gulacy art&amp;ndash;which I know is not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea but he is great at &amp;ldquo;realistic&amp;rdquo; comic stories (such as his run on &lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt;) so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting strong work here. Shanna and some others are tracking diamond smugglers and poachers through/near Tanzania. This part of the story does a really successful job at showing the violence and tragedy that accompanies such acts, and the cliffhanger&amp;ndash;where Shanna discovers someone (a local?) buried up to his neck amid massive anthills&amp;ndash;is creepy and suspenseful. Unlike with the Wolverine story, I have a clear sense of where this is going (without bringing in retrospective knowledge of the overall plot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to explain the Daredevil component (it&amp;rsquo;s part 4 and the final part, apparently, of a story). There&amp;rsquo;s apparently been a heat weave, and tensions are running high as people get frustrated. A woman named Ms. Pinkwater, whose defining feature is a Carmen Sandiego hat, is doing &amp;hellip; something? I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure it out. Anyway, apparently a bunch of people hold hands and sing or something, and it causes rain to fall and all tensions in the city to relax. Daredevil doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do anything other than read a handwritten note that asks him not to do anything. What the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Red Wolf story&amp;ndash;which I think is a standalone story&amp;ndash;is equally weak. Red Wolf begins in a lodge, ruminating on the loss of his wolf partner Lobo, while a truck full of drunks look for something to hunt. They eventually discover a mother wolf feeding her cubs and proceed to kill almost all of them (save one), when Red Wolf finally acts. Even then, he&amp;rsquo;s nearly taken out until one of the hunters decides they&amp;rsquo;ve gone too far and has a standoff with his buddy. Red Wolf, meanwhile, takes the surviving cub (presumably to raise himself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this issue is a decent representative for &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; in general: there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting experimentation happening and some solid, compelling story work &amp;hellip; but there are also stinkers that don&amp;rsquo;t feel really worthwhile or well-realized. Does the former cancel out the latter? Yes and no&amp;ndash;certainly enough, for me, to not absolutely hate the series, but not so much that I forget nostalgia is a big part of my enjoyment of this series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namor, The Sub-Mariner 014</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Namor-014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:58:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Namor-014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Namor, The Sub-Mariner&lt;/em&gt; was the first comic for which I ever had a subscription (my subscription was from issue 18-29). I don&amp;rsquo;t recall all the details about this, but I know that we had some sort of postal issue that prevented me from getting an issue or two initially, so my dad and I called Marvel. It turned out that they were having a Christmas party at the time, and Stan Lee himself picked up the phone. He very kindly took our info to get things sorted out, and I got my twelve issues of &lt;em&gt;Namor&lt;/em&gt; and the appropriate annual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comic &amp;hellip; Namor has always been a super-interesting character to me (Marvel&amp;rsquo;s first &amp;ldquo;mutant,&amp;rdquo; a Golden Age character, a potential voice for ecological issues, the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest eyebrows, etc.) but I cannot &lt;strong&gt;stand&lt;/strong&gt; John Bryne&amp;rsquo;s art. Everyone has the same face. Everyone has the same body. (I feel the same way about Mark Bagley&amp;rsquo;s art, as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover for issue 014 shows Namor, a woman, and a small child in a living room or den, from the over-the-shoulder perspective of a creature we only see from the back. It has a golden mane, a spiked collar, large hands with claws, and a pair of wings. There&amp;rsquo;s broken glass on the floor under Namor et al.&amp;rsquo;s feet.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Namor-014.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Namor, The Sub-Mariner 014, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Namor, The Sub-Mariner issue 014&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue begins with Phoebe Marrs, jerk CEO, chewing out her board during a meeting and then firing her assistant when said assistant makes an under-the-breath comment about Phoebe being a &amp;ldquo;lucky girl&amp;rdquo; when Namor comes to visit her. Not really the best way to win over a reader, since we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be interested in Namor&amp;rsquo;s romantic relationship with Phoebe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Phoebe and Namor go to visit her son, whose existence is a secret and who lives in a house that &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; knows about. What the hell, Phoebe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a quick interlude in Atlantis, where we learn that Namor&amp;rsquo;s former (and dead) wife, the Lady Dorma, has turned out to be alive! (Spoiler: in a later issue, it turns out she&amp;rsquo;s actually one of many clones that a crazy Atlantean scientist created.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s a scene with Danny Rand (who&amp;rsquo;s supposedly dead, if I recall, from the end of the &lt;em&gt;Power Man and Iron Fist&lt;/em&gt; series) and also Ka-Zar (and Zabu, his sabretooth tiger). They&amp;rsquo;re up to something obviously sinister&amp;ndash;maybe destroying the environment in the Savage Land or something?&amp;ndash;but I find myself completely uninterested in this story. (We&amp;rsquo;re only at the halfway point here, too. Not good.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Phoebe&amp;rsquo;s secret house, Phoebe tells Namor about how she came to have a secret son. But then a giant griffin flies in out of the air. (I think it&amp;rsquo;s actually a manticore.) Apparently, Namor and the griffin have fought before, but I seriously do not remember this character &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Namor and the griffin tussle, and then Namor domesticates it somehow and Phoebe declares her love for Namor, kissing him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue was a &lt;em&gt;slog&lt;/em&gt;. Unfortunately, from what I remember of my subscription to this series, the next dozen or so issues aren&amp;rsquo;t any better &amp;hellip; which is a shame, because Namor the character is fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cable 011</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 19:58:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Cable-011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s review features Cable, a character that, along with Deadpool, has somehow managed to survive the &amp;lsquo;90s boom that spawned him. I was never fully sold on the &lt;strong&gt;extreme&lt;/strong&gt; nature of the Liefeld X-Force, but I suppose I get why Cable remains interesting to many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was, for some time, the consummate 1980s action hero ideal, a &amp;ldquo;mystery man&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;tactical badass&amp;rdquo; that speaks directly to the fantasies of the stereotypical superhero comic consumer. Plus, he has a cool eye scar and a metal arm! (Ironically, I think the Magog design for &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Come&lt;/em&gt;, meant to play on all the Cable-era tropes that Waid &amp;amp; Ross hated, is much more awesome.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since his introduction, Cable&amp;rsquo;s been fleshed out a lot more, and the &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; series that this issue (discussed more below) comes from has a really interesting initial story premise: Cable has to flee to the future with a special infant girl, who is supposed to one day be the mutant messiah, and he tries to keep her alive while mutant cop/ethnic cleanser Bishop chases them both through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Cable&lt;/em&gt; #011 features an image of young Hope Summers in front of a white background, where she is dressed in an adorably ill-fitting X-Men uniform resembling Cable&amp;rsquo;s outfit (complete with giant shoulder pads) and wielding an oversized gun of some sort &amp;hellip; maybe a sawed-off gatling gun or something?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Cable-011.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Cable 011, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cable issue 011&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Okay, so when this issue begins, Cable has taken Hope (although in the comic Hope does not yet have a name) to an oasis-like settlement in a post-apocalyptic hellscape populated by vicious insectoid beings (called &amp;ldquo;the cockroach army&amp;rdquo; by Cable). Cable has a wife named Hope, met during one of the time-jumps made by Cable and the child he&amp;rsquo;s protecting, who ends up dying during a bandit attack, and so he names the child Hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining humans devise a bomb or gas or something to destroy the cockroaches, but Cable worries they&amp;rsquo;ll kill the humans too. So, he and Hope jump a hundred years into the future, surrounded by salt flats and human skeletons. The image (a two-page spread) is actually pretty incredible, the clean art style juxtaposed with the apocalyptic horror and Hope&amp;rsquo;s vomiting from the experience of sliding through time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: this issue, more than many before it in this series, really calls to mind the Futurama episode where Fry, Professor Farnsworth, and Bender use a time machine and witness the end of the universe. (Like the Futurama crew, Cable can only jump into the future.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I enjoyed this series (picking up the first twenty or so issues from a dollar bin) in part because Cable is depicted stylistically so far from his Liefeld origins: no ludicrous thigh pouches, consistent realistic proportions, and his relationship with the child Hope is really believable: he&amp;rsquo;s clearly come around from seeing this as a duty put upon him to a genuine parental concern for her well-being. It&amp;rsquo;s like an X-Men version of &lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt;, and I mean that as a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one page, there&amp;rsquo;s a moment that &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be a reference to Philip K. Dick&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Second Variety&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Cable hunts a wolf that turns out to be a machine with a wolf&amp;rsquo;s external appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, the focus on Cable and Hope is really quite enjoyable. The conflict is almost entirely on Cable trying to decide what sorts of details to tell Hope about the past and her potential destiny (along with details about child development and puberty) rather than on forcing gunfights and explosions and whatnot into the mix. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of characterization here, and maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the sheer lack of possible distractions that has made it possible or my interest in depressing apocalyptic wasteland stories, but &amp;hellip; yeah, I dig this issue. This Cable is so much more interesting than when he was a mix of Kyle Reese and the Terminator but with no real backstory to lean on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of Kung Fu 071</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 23:21:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shang-Chi, the master of kung fu, is one of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s greatest martial arts characters, and one who was born during the company&amp;rsquo;s 1970s-era efforts to exploit the martial arts movie craze (although I admit I&amp;rsquo;m a bigger fan of Shang-Chi frenemy Shen Kuei, &amp;ldquo;the Cat&amp;rdquo;). This series is definitely a reflection of that time, and it&amp;rsquo;s Doug Moench&amp;rsquo;s magnum opus (although, sadly, this particular issue doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature Paul Gulacy, whose work meshed excellently with Moench, although the artist here, Mike Zeck, also does a solid job with the kung fu/espionage style the book goes for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the character&amp;rsquo;s world even more incredible, it&amp;rsquo;s filled with a cast of pulp homages: Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s father is Fu Manchu (although Marvel lost the rights to the character, so he&amp;rsquo;s not actually called that&amp;mdash;or any other&amp;mdash;name any more, instead referred to by vague descriptions), and Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s super-spy BFF, MI-6 agent Clive Reston, is &lt;em&gt;heavily implied&lt;/em&gt; to be the son of James Bond, while his mentor Sir Denis Nayland-Smith (an enemy of Fu Manchu&amp;rsquo;s) is suggested to be a relative of Sherlock Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so &lt;em&gt;MoKF&lt;/em&gt; 071. This issue has an incredible cover&amp;mdash;Shang-Chi is posed ready for a fight, barefoot and clad only in his red pants and bandana, in front of a giant yin-yang symbol. The background is also a massive jigsaw puzzle whose pieces begin to fall apart near the bottom of the image. (There&amp;rsquo;s a jigsaw motif running through this issue, just FYI.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Master-of-Kung-Fu-071.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Master of Kung Fu 071, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Master of Kung Fu issue 071&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue opens with a fantastic two-page spread wherein Shang-Chi recaps a bunch of recent storylines, all laid out as interlocking jigsaw pieces. The next several pages explore Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s coming to terms with various close relationships (a love interest, Juliette; even more intense and long-term love interest, Leiko Wu; and BFF Clive Reston) and the changes that had occurred in regards to each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, this issue then segues into a conversation scene while Shang-Chi and Leiko (who&amp;rsquo;s been putting together a jigsaw puzzle of a yin-yang symbol) share a pizza. After they eat, they visit a martial arts studio and engage in a friendly bout to exercise &amp;amp; train, making an impressive enough showing that all the other individuals present stop to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After they go to a movie and return home, the comic ends on a cliffhanger where a battered Sir Denis bursts into their home, seeking help with supposed corruption in the MI-6 agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not a tremendous amount of action in this comic, but that&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing. Shang-Chi has always been depicted as an extremely introspective character who seeks a path to enlightenment and peace with every action he takes and every phenomenon he witnesses. That he reflects on a number of the major plots in the comic so far is a totally human move (in addition to having the practical effect of catching up newer readers to the series&amp;rsquo; progression). I found myself nodding along, persuaded by Shang-Chi&amp;rsquo;s line of reasoning as he attempted to make sense of the insanity that is life in a pulp comic book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt; is a series that I try to collect through dollar bins; I know that Marvel has recently begun reprinting the series in massive omnibus form, but, given its content and focus, the comic really seems best experienced when one is exposed to the feel and smell of crappy older comic paper. It just seems appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Into Mystery 646</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 16:09:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Journey-Into-Mystery-646/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; was the comic in which Thor first appeared, and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome that Marvel revived this title in order to make space for Asgard tales (the &amp;ldquo;Tales from Asgard&amp;rdquo; in the back of older &lt;em&gt;Thor&lt;/em&gt; comics were great, but wayyyyy too short to enjoy thoroughly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember buying this comic from a dollar bin in 2014 or maybe 2015. The cover alone made it worth the price: Lady Sif looks totally badass, striding directly toward the viewer in a suit of battle armor&amp;mdash;mostly practical, too! only a bit of naked thigh that could be armored further, beneath her Greek-style skirt&amp;mdash;and wielding a sword in each hand. The use of color here (mostly grayscale except for the red of Sif&amp;rsquo;s cape, armor, and highlighting in the &lt;em&gt;JIM&lt;/em&gt; logo) helps make it stand out; there&amp;rsquo;s a similar phenomenon happening with the cover design to the current &lt;em&gt;Scarlet Witch&lt;/em&gt; series, and I really wish I could get the covers to those issues as prints.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Journey-Into-Mystery-646.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Journey Into Mystery 646, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Journey Into Mystery issue 646&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Inside, the indicia page has a hilarious narration accompanying a large, similarly red-toned, image of Sif that rips off an exchange from &lt;em&gt;Shaft&lt;/em&gt; (and does so less skillfully, since the initial question is so wordy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s the sword-wielding woman who&amp;rsquo;s a soldier on the battlefield and a lady in Asgardia, but no one understands her but her thunder god?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;SIF!&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Verily. Can you dig it?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;We can dig it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This certainly sets the stage for an entertaining reading experience. Turning the page, I find myself wondering what, exactly is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asgard is in ruins and Sif is helping with some sort of rescue/relief effort. I think that this story probably takes place after&amp;mdash;or, more likely, during&amp;mdash;Ragnarok (which, if I recall, had occurred in the Thor comics around this time); Sif suggests as much when she notes that the demon Surtur had come to wreck shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif rescues a child, says she&amp;rsquo;s had enough child-minding for the day after turning the child over to other helpers, and then promptly(? there&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Days Hence&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; caption, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell just how much time has passed) goes to dinner at the child&amp;rsquo;s house, visiting an entire home &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with children. There are some interesting conversations about the best way to fight (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Fighting&amp;rsquo;s for &lt;strong&gt;kids&lt;/strong&gt;. You should use your &lt;strong&gt;words&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;ldquo;) and about 1950s-era &lt;em&gt;Journey Into Mystery&lt;/em&gt; comics, which apparently exist and populate care packages given to Asgardians by the Red Cross (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, Sif travels to Niffleheim to find a sleeping dragon who might have information for her about some ancient warriors of legend, as she has &amp;ldquo;a record of a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; battle with &lt;strong&gt;greater&lt;/strong&gt; warriors still who fought so fiercely those who saw them said they seemed &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to be men at &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; She says this while sitting on the shoulder of a &lt;em&gt;giant dragon&lt;/em&gt; that she reached only after taking down a bunch of Niffleheim&amp;rsquo;s resident predators. I can only imagine how incredible these other warriors she&amp;rsquo;s looking for must have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sif eventually gets the info she needs and casts a spell to talk to the warriors&amp;rsquo; teacher &amp;hellip; supposedly to learn the &amp;ldquo;berserker incantation&amp;rdquo; and, I assume, save Asgard? I think I&amp;rsquo;m right, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really invested in this story&amp;mdash;and I say that as someone who &lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Asgardian characters and tales. I do, however, dig that Sif is apparently willing to compromise all over the place in order to save her home, and the idea of Sif becoming an uncontrollable berserker seems excellent at face value (I mean, literally the first thing she does is kill the person who just taught her the berserker incantation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story ends (technically, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) with her in a tavern in &amp;ldquo;the unluckiest town in Midgard&amp;rdquo; with a bloody bag (presumably the teacher&amp;rsquo;s head) on a stool next to her while she asks for another drink. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a serious &lt;em&gt;Superman III&lt;/em&gt; vibe here and I love it. Now this is a story I&amp;rsquo;m interested in continuing! Unfortunately, I can&amp;rsquo;t recall offhand if I bought any more issues in this storyline, which at the moment is a shame, because I was definitely brought around from a plot I initially didn&amp;rsquo;t find that interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme 016 (1988)</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 23:04:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps fitting that the first comic randomly selected to serve as a review post is a &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comic, since I have long adored the character. (I used to have more comics featuring Doctor Strange than any other, but I&amp;rsquo;ve since collected far more Green Lantern-related comics &amp;hellip; so expect a few of those to make appearances.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover, shown below, is suitably interesting: Baron Blood has thrown(?) or is otherwise causing Doctor Strange to be flung upside-down through the night sky, off of some jungle or forest cliff, with a large, full moon illuminating everything from the background. Baron Blood has some seriously long underarm wings here, like he learned about Batman&amp;rsquo;s cape or something.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Doctor-Strange-Sorcerer-Supreme-016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doctor Strange: Sorcerer Supreme, issue 016&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, this issue, titled &amp;ldquo;Love and Haiti&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (classic Marvel pun?). There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love: Roy Thomas (partially) on writing duties. A cast that includes Morbius, Marie LaVeau the &amp;ldquo;Voodoo Queen,&amp;rdquo; Baron Blood, and Brother Voodoo. It is, unfortunately, the middle point of a five-issue arc, so there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; backstory to catch up readers, but other details are left unstated&amp;ndash;although I never felt like I was really lost at any point. This issue (from 1990) is well before the era of plot decompression for the sake of publishing an eventual TPB collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art by Jackson Guice seems very &amp;ldquo;workhorse&amp;rdquo; in comparison to the early &amp;lsquo;90s Image style explosion, but I appreciate it now in a way that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could have at age 9 (not that I owned it then&amp;ndash;I think I picked up this issue in a lot of &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; comics around 2001). Stephen Strange looks like an older doctor. Poses seem relatively realistic, save for when characters/phenomena suggest they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be (like someone floating upside-down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awkward moment: during a fight with vampires&amp;ndash;in an alley in Port-au-Prince, of course&amp;ndash;Morgana Blessing calls out both to &amp;ldquo;Mr. Drumm&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dr. Morbius&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; poor Brother Voodoo getting &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; credit for his educational credentials until he took up the mantle of Sorcerer Supreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome moment: Dracula making a &lt;em&gt;phone call&lt;/em&gt; in order to set up an attack on an enemy. This is easily the best dialogue of the issue (the panel art is similarly wonderful):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dracula: &amp;ldquo;I want you to set a &lt;strong&gt;trap&lt;/strong&gt; for my accursed descendant, &lt;strong&gt;Frank Drake&lt;/strong&gt;, upon his arrival in Brazil. You will be richly rewarded.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danny Summers: &amp;ldquo;You bet your bat I will, Drac! &lt;strong&gt;Danny Summers&lt;/strong&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t do &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;nothin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reread this issue, I found myself really annoyed that Baron Blood, despite having an absolutely fantastic character name, has a pretty weak schtick&amp;ndash;or, at least, they really play up his weaknesses in this issue. If he changed up his costume&amp;rsquo;s color scheme, he might seem more intimidating. If he seemed like more of a mastermind, he might seem more dangerous. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t know: has Baron Blood ever been the big threat in a horror-oriented story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I think Doctor Strange casts a total of three spells in this issue, and none of them really plays up the surreal trip that Ditko originally demonstrated could (and &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;) be at the center of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s arcane/occult aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with luck my future reviews will become more coherent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>