<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justice League Europe on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/justice-league-europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Justice League Europe on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:10:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/tags/justice-league-europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice League Europe 008</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:10:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Justice-League-Europe-008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JUSTICE LEAGUE EUROPE! Possibly the greatest Europe-based superhero team from one of the big two comics companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Justice League Europe&lt;/em&gt; / &lt;em&gt;Justice League International&lt;/em&gt; were incredible series in the late 80s/early 90s that really embraced the goofiness of shining a spotlight on a band of B- and C-list heroes. Keith Giffen and Bart Sears worked so well together to make the comic so believable and staunchly ridiculous at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JLE featured two of my favorite DC characters: Animal Man and Metamorpho. Ralph Dibny is also great (and his partnership with his wife really should be emulated more, in terms of having a hero in a healthy committed relationship).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to this issue is suitably dramatic and goofy: members of the JLE and JLI (from left to right, at varying distances from the &amp;ldquo;camera&amp;rdquo;: Batman, Rocket Red, Captain Atom, Booster Gold, Fire, Metamorpho, Guy Gardner, Animal Man, Flash, Martian Manhunter, Power Girl, and Blue Beetle) stand, with their backs to the viewer, in the middle of a small town square, with moutnains looming in the background. There&amp;rsquo;s a large and ominous dark shadow spreading in the space between the mountains and the town. Blue Beetle says, &amp;ldquo;Uh oh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Justice-League-Europe-008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Justice League Europe #008, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Justice League Europe issue 008&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>