<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Green Lantern on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/green-lantern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Green Lantern on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 14:50:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/green-lantern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Lantern (2005) 001</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lantern-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 14:50:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lantern-001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For today&amp;rsquo;s post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the first issue of Geoff Johns&amp;rsquo; run on &lt;em&gt;Green Lantern&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a new series, you might expect that the comic provides a lot of exposition &amp;amp; setup for the epic story to come. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; do that much if at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover, painted by Alex Ross in his realistic style, features Green Lantern Hal Jordan flying among the clouds on a bright, sunny day, reaching out toward the reader. His power ring leaves a green trail behind him.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Green-Lantern-001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Green Lantern (2005) 001, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Green Lantern (2005) issue 001&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first five pages or so provide a brief retelling of the origin, tweaked just enough to suit Johns&amp;rsquo; future purposes. The rest of the story requires pretty significant knowledge of the Green Lantern mythos published up to this point&amp;ndash;most notably Hal Jordan&amp;rsquo;s tenure as Parallax, the personification of fear, who engaged in some genocide-level violence before Hal died (and was attached to the Spectre, the agent of God&amp;rsquo;s wrath) and was brought back to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of these details aren&amp;rsquo;t really covered at all, or at least not substantially or explicitly; there are moments where Johns almost gives the reader enough detail to understand everything. In particular, if a reader approaches this comic without having read the &lt;em&gt;Green Lantern: Rebirth&lt;/em&gt; miniseries, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine they comprehend much of what&amp;rsquo;s going on here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken in the context of Johns&amp;rsquo; ovverall epic story, this is a solid, slow beginning. As a standalone issue? It kind of sucks&amp;ndash;at least for someone looking to get a full GL adventure. Hal and John Stewart investigate a satellite orbiting the planet, but the villain (a Manhunter, the robotic predecessor of the GL Corps) does not engage them&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s off killing civilians in a quest to end all human life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous that I have to qualify the quality of the comic, but here we are nonetheless. Is it really so hard to write a complete 22-page story that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; a component of a larger story that only Grant Morrison seems to be able to pull it off (shout-out to &lt;em&gt;All-Star Superman&lt;/em&gt;!)?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Lantern (2005) 046</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lantern-046/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 10:17:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lantern-046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve noted elsewhere, I own more &lt;em&gt;Green Lantern&lt;/em&gt; comics than any other title/franchise, so I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising that the random selection of the comics I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing would hit multiple GL issues so early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Lantern&lt;/em&gt; 046 is smack in the middle of Geoff Johns&amp;rsquo; epic space opera run on the character, so this issue is pretty much 100% action&amp;ndash;a stark contrast to the laser-focused character development of some other comics I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover shows Green Lantern (Hal Jordan) flying through space, toward the viewer, next to Sinestro, with Star Sapphire position between and behind the others. Each of the ring-wielders is glowing in a light the color of their rings. Text along the bottom of the page reads &amp;ldquo;Uneasy Alliance.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Green-Lantern-046.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Green Lantern (2005) 046, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Green Lantern issue 046&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This issue is part of the &amp;ldquo;Blackest Night&amp;rdquo; storyline, a pretty genius concept by Johns to introduce a spectrum of colored light rings &amp;amp; corps to wield them, each corresponding to a different emotion (green = willpower, yellow = fear, orange = green, red = rage, blue = hope, indigo = compassion, violet = love). All of the corps, despite their signficant and fundamental ideological differences, had to come together to fight the threat of the Black Lantern Corps, an army of undead beings seeking to kill and assimilate all life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of moving plot parts in this issue that only make sense if one reads the whole storyline; for example, John Stewart appears in space for a page or two, but it&amp;rsquo;s entirely unclear what the hell is going on there in the context of this issue alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of focus on Sinestro here, which I really dig. Despite the fact that Sinestro is a brutally fascist rogue Green Lantern, I find the examination of his psyche fascinating&amp;ndash;he works so well as a character because he&amp;rsquo;s clearly the logical extension of the GL Corps&amp;rsquo; goals. At what point should one&amp;rsquo;s willpower be limited? How can we be sure that someone with a strong will is also pure of heart or bound to an ethical worldview? (Obviously, we can&amp;rsquo;t, but we take it for granted that Hal &amp;amp; his allies are infallible in this regard &amp;hellip; other than that whole Parallax situation.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinestro has one really interesting action moment where, after beating Mongul one-on-one, he drops his Corps&amp;rsquo; giant power battery on his enemy. It&amp;rsquo;s so ludicrous that it should be played for laughs, but the absurdity of this entire comic&amp;rsquo;s concept makes it seem just believable enough to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, I never really found myself interested in the Star Sapphires as characters. They&amp;rsquo;re often depicted as oversexualized, hormone-crazed women who are out to ruin the lives of the men they supposedly love. &lt;em&gt;Surely&lt;/em&gt; there&amp;rsquo;s a better way to approach this component of the GL franchise, right? Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, this issue ends with the Black Lantern Corps arrival of Abin Sur (Hal Jordan&amp;rsquo;s predecessor and Sinestro&amp;rsquo;s mentor) and his sister Arin, a character who&amp;ndash;it turns out in a future issue&amp;ndash;was Sinestro&amp;rsquo;s love before she died. So there&amp;rsquo;s a big cliffhanger! The storyline is certainly interesting and compelling, but not in its individual serialized components &amp;hellip; which is a shame, because I really dig almost everything about the GL franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Lanterns 007</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lanterns-007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:16:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Green-Lanterns-007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think that this might be the newest of all the comics I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; is a series starring Simon Baz and Jessica Cruz, two novice members of the Green Lantern Corps, each saddled with their own hang-ups about being a hero. They were paired up by Hal Jordan and tasked with protecting Earth while he went out into outer space to locate the rest of the Green Lantern Corps (as they had gone missing at the time). Also, like any good buddy cop story, the two despise each other at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first arc of &lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; does a pretty respectable job of following Simon and Jessica through their trials of overcoming self-doubt, an irritating partner, and a potential invasion of earth by the Red Lanterns. This issue marks the beginning of a new story arc (and the denouement to the previous arc), so we get to see what the next phase of the protagonists&amp;rsquo; relationship looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to &lt;em&gt;Green Lanterns&lt;/em&gt; 007 features Simon and Jessica standing next to one another, in their uniforms, in front of a series of floating GL insignias. Simon holds his ring hand in front of him while Jessica raises hers high above her head.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Green-Lanterns-007.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Green Lanterns 007, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Green Lanterns issue 007&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue, set on Halloween, begins with a focus on Jessica&amp;rsquo;s perspective, coming to grips with being a GL and having to spend time with Simon&amp;rsquo;s family. In a pretty funny move, she bails out of family activities (readying treats for Halloween), claiming to herself that she&amp;rsquo;s not a people person, and instead tries to &amp;ldquo;find Darkseid and see what he&amp;rsquo;s doing for dinner,&amp;rdquo; even going so far as to ask her ring to call him (the ring: &amp;ldquo;Call sent to voice mail.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Simon catches her and begs for her help dealing with his family&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s clear that they have that much in common&amp;ndash;and the two do some baking as a way to contribute to the household and get to know one another better. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice chiasmus where Simon decides to bail on the baking (it&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; the way his mother makes it), and it becomes Jessica&amp;rsquo;s turn to talk her partner down from doing something stupid. After Simon explains his relationship with his mother to Jessica, the two have an epiphany to cook with the aid of their power rings (allowing them to multitask much more easily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: after revealing himself as a GL to his mom, Simon convinces her to try a cookie &amp;hellip; and she doesn&amp;rsquo;t hate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all of this, Farid (Simon&amp;rsquo;s nephew) has been screwing around with Rami, a Guardian of Oa hiding out in the family&amp;rsquo;s attic. Rami senses that some threat (revealed to be the Dominators) is coming, and &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; bails from the house. The two GLs recognize they need to go after him, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this issue is pretty solid in terms of character development. Action-wise, it&amp;rsquo;s very &amp;ldquo;boring,&amp;rdquo; but in the context of the preceding six issues, it&amp;rsquo;s a really enjoyable moment of rest. There had been a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of action in those issues focusing on the problems that Jessica and Simon each felt about their ability to be a hero, and the interaction between them&amp;ndash;and the rest of Simon&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;ndash;here becomes a useful and satisfying progression from their overcoming some of those problems in their fight against the Red Lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was not initially sold on Simon Baz as a GL (because he used a gun! which I still think is kind of a lame early gimmick), I have come to really enjoy the presentation of his character in this series. I think that he works well with Jessica&amp;ndash;a character I wasn&amp;rsquo;t well-versed in before this series&amp;ndash;to give the GL franchise a pairing that feels fresh and innovative. (I mean, as iconic as Hal Jordan is, it&amp;rsquo;s not really that fascinating to watch a guy who believes, and often proves, he can do anything he wants.) Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just the longtime Marvel fan in me, but the relatability of Simon &amp;amp; Jessica as heroes-who-don&amp;rsquo;t-always-think-they-live-up-to-the-role really do a lot to make this series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>