<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Image on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/image/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Image on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 23:08:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/image/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kurt Busiek&#39;s Astro City 009</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 23:08:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, another Astro City post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the original six-issue series, Kurt Busiek, Brent Anderson, and Alex Ross began a new volume whose second storyline has remained, arguably, their best: &amp;ldquo;Confession.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Confession&amp;rdquo; story arc deals with a young man, Brian Kinney, who heads to Astro City from a small town to escape the hardships he&amp;rsquo;d experienced there (mostly dealing with poverty while his father, a doctor, worked thanklessly&amp;ndash;often without pay&amp;ndash;to help his community). After Brian arrived, he eventually became the sidekick to Astro City&amp;rsquo;s most mysterious hero, the Confessor (a clear Batman stand-in, although the comparison&amp;rsquo;s not perfect). Brian&amp;rsquo;s hero persona, by the way, was Altar Boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil everything about this story because it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; well-crafted and, for me, quite powerful emotionally. Suffice it to say that, by the time issue 009&amp;ndash;the final issue in the story&amp;ndash;comes around, the Confessor has died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the cover of this issue, the members of religious super-team The Crossbreed stand in the shadows, a light cast on them from off-panel. Together, the members hold the Confessor&amp;rsquo;s outfit in their hands.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Astro-City-009.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Kurt Busiek&amp;#39;s Astro City 009, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Kurt Busiek&amp;#39;s Astro City issue 009&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After seeing the Confessor die, Brian has to come to terms with his understanding of the world. What does he want to do? Why be a hero at all? Plus, he has to do so in the middle of a MASSIVE crisis&amp;ndash;and not surprisingly, he ends up overwhelmed and shocked by everything he&amp;rsquo;s experienced. The Crossbreed get a hold of Brian and take him to their refuge to rest. There, Noah offers a question to Brian that echoes for me as one of the greatest demonstrations of the superhero ethos I&amp;rsquo;ve read: &amp;ldquo;What is more important? The burdens we bear&amp;ndash;or the way we bear them?&amp;rdquo; I think about this passage a lot. I mean a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Brian makes peace with his past, his family, the Confessor&amp;rsquo;s memory, and he figures out a plan for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s easy for me to see myself in Brian (especially as I was closer to his age when I first read &amp;ldquo;Confession&amp;rdquo;). Maybe I just love a great Batman &amp;amp; Robin story. Maybe this particular story just has everything I wanted to see in a coming-of-age hero tale, plus it tugs on my Catholic upbringing too. Whatever the case &amp;hellip; this is a solid-gold comic. Admittedly, on its own it&amp;rsquo;s a bit tricky to enter into easily, although there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; effort to help a new reader (that said, this is definitely the payoff to several issues&amp;rsquo; unfolding).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also really cool to revisit this story in the context of the Astro City universe&amp;rsquo;s 1:1 time lapse scale to the real world; in the current volume, Brian is older, wiser, and has a ton of tricks up his sleeve regarding superheroics. But I&amp;rsquo;ll admit I miss the old Confessor, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway: this is essential reading material for the superhero comics fan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>