<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wolverine on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/wolverine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wolverine on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 17:33:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/wolverine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Comics Presents 072</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 17:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Comics Presents&lt;/em&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt;) is a series that interested me for the longest time: it was an anthology comic that tended to have four stories (each 8 pages) of varying length, by which I mean that one story might have 8-10 parts, another might have 4-6, another might only be a single 8-page story, and so on. So a reader was likely to get some really fascinating story turnover in any given collection of issues. When I was young, &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; introduced me to some characters that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever would have checked out otherwise, most notably (for me) Shang-Chi, but also minor characters like Stingray or the Collective Man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary story of many &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; issues featured Wolverine&amp;ndash;unsurprising, given his ability to sell pretty much any comic where he appeared on the cover. &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; 072, however, is important because it begins the tale of an incredibly significant part of Wolverine&amp;rsquo;s backstory, written &amp;amp; drawn by Barry Windsor-Smith: the Weapon X experiments that bonded adamantium to his skeleton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover for issue 072, like all of the &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; covers, is wraparound, with the primary (Wolverine) story featured on the front and the characters of the other three stories&amp;ndash;Daredevil, Shanna the She-Devil, and Red Wolf&amp;ndash;on the back. On the front half, Wolverine stands, the right half of his body covered by his classic brown-and-yellow suit, and his left half naked with a number of protruding spikes in preparation for his adamantium injections. Behind him is a large skull (likely his own), with similar spikes. Flames beneath a blank blue canvas comprise the background, layered (from top down) yellow, orange, and red. At the top of the page, below the comic&amp;rsquo;s title/logo, are the words: &amp;ldquo;Before Wolverine there was Weapon X.&amp;rdquo; On the back half of the cover, Shanna is posed crouching (with a caption box that declares &amp;ldquo;Her &lt;strong&gt;jungle&lt;/strong&gt; reeks of &lt;strong&gt;evil&lt;/strong&gt;, and SHANNA must &lt;strong&gt;confront&lt;/strong&gt; it.&amp;ldquo;), while Red Wolf leaps behind her, up and to her left (captioned &amp;ldquo;RED WOLF &lt;strong&gt;faces&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;death&lt;/strong&gt; of his &lt;strong&gt;partner Lobo&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;ldquo;). Behind her, down and to the right, Daredevil similarly jumps forward, swinging his billy club (caption: &amp;ldquo;DAREDEVIL is &lt;strong&gt;helpless&lt;/strong&gt; when things come to a &lt;strong&gt;head&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;New York&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;). What appears to be the back side of the large skull from the front cover looms behind the figures.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Marvel-Comics-Presents-072.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Marvel Comics Presents 072, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Marvel Comics Presents issue 072&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Weapon X&amp;rdquo; story in this issue must have been &lt;em&gt;ridiculously&lt;/em&gt; confusing to everyone when it initially came out, since it consists of three threads: (1) Wolverine down on his luck in the Yukon, drinking and getting in fights; (2) flashes of the Weapon X experiments themselves, provided without explanation/context; (3) panels of a scientist performing some sort of experiment that may or may not be (but almost certainly is) related to the Weapon X project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually pick up this issue until last year, but I already knew the general beats to this story. I have to say, in its serialized form, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed since there&amp;rsquo;s no real room for anything to breathe here (although I get that BWS is trying to let things unfold in a somewhat-similar manner to Logan&amp;rsquo;s ability to comprehend what happened to him). The art style and the narration is solid&amp;ndash;it does its job of leaving me wanting more. I&amp;rsquo;m just torn in both wanting more and not feeling like I really had &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; in this portion to really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shanna comic provided is part 5 of its story. I&amp;rsquo;m stoked going in because there&amp;rsquo;s Paul Gulacy art&amp;ndash;which I know is not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea but he is great at &amp;ldquo;realistic&amp;rdquo; comic stories (such as his run on &lt;em&gt;Master of Kung Fu&lt;/em&gt;) so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting strong work here. Shanna and some others are tracking diamond smugglers and poachers through/near Tanzania. This part of the story does a really successful job at showing the violence and tragedy that accompanies such acts, and the cliffhanger&amp;ndash;where Shanna discovers someone (a local?) buried up to his neck amid massive anthills&amp;ndash;is creepy and suspenseful. Unlike with the Wolverine story, I have a clear sense of where this is going (without bringing in retrospective knowledge of the overall plot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to explain the Daredevil component (it&amp;rsquo;s part 4 and the final part, apparently, of a story). There&amp;rsquo;s apparently been a heat weave, and tensions are running high as people get frustrated. A woman named Ms. Pinkwater, whose defining feature is a Carmen Sandiego hat, is doing &amp;hellip; something? I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure it out. Anyway, apparently a bunch of people hold hands and sing or something, and it causes rain to fall and all tensions in the city to relax. Daredevil doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do anything other than read a handwritten note that asks him not to do anything. What the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Red Wolf story&amp;ndash;which I think is a standalone story&amp;ndash;is equally weak. Red Wolf begins in a lodge, ruminating on the loss of his wolf partner Lobo, while a truck full of drunks look for something to hunt. They eventually discover a mother wolf feeding her cubs and proceed to kill almost all of them (save one), when Red Wolf finally acts. Even then, he&amp;rsquo;s nearly taken out until one of the hunters decides they&amp;rsquo;ve gone too far and has a standoff with his buddy. Red Wolf, meanwhile, takes the surviving cub (presumably to raise himself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this issue is a decent representative for &lt;em&gt;MCP&lt;/em&gt; in general: there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting experimentation happening and some solid, compelling story work &amp;hellip; but there are also stinkers that don&amp;rsquo;t feel really worthwhile or well-realized. Does the former cancel out the latter? Yes and no&amp;ndash;certainly enough, for me, to not absolutely hate the series, but not so much that I forget nostalgia is a big part of my enjoyment of this series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>