<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Captain America on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/captain-america/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Captain America on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 10:48:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/captain-america/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Captain America 358</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Captain-America-358/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 10:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Captain-America-358/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, a Mark Gruenwald issue of &lt;em&gt;Captain America&lt;/em&gt;! And part of &amp;ldquo;The Bloodstone Saga,&amp;rdquo; to boot! But how well does it stack up to my memory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My youngest brother, Patrick, is far more of a Captain America fan than I am. I think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that he, like me, really digs the Brubaker era most of all (which brought us the Winter Soldier and the assassination of Steve Rogers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mid-late 300s to 400s (issue-wise) of the original &lt;em&gt;Captain America&lt;/em&gt; run were not always great. &amp;ldquo;The Bloodstone Saga&amp;rdquo; stands out, though&amp;ndash;it involved the magical gem of Ulysses Bloodstone (nigh-invulnerable/immortal monster hunter) and introduced Red Skull crony Crossbones to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover to issue 358 shows Captain America crouching in tight quarters, in pit trap with a spiked floor. Cap&amp;rsquo;s shielding himself (literally) from a spiked ceiling trying to crush or impale him. In a text box in the bottom right corner, there&amp;rsquo;s text reading, &amp;ldquo;To rescue Diamondback, Cap enters the Caverns of Death!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Captain-America-358.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Captain America 358, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Captain America issue 358&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The issue ends up not really doing a whole lot well, pacing-wise. The first third of the comic is Cap&amp;rsquo;s navigation of a dungeon (the aforementioned &amp;ldquo;caverns of death&amp;rdquo;), but all related narration comes from thought bubbles as he recaps the relevant plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Cap meets up with Diamondback (a character who&amp;rsquo;s always annoyed me, as she seems incompetent in the worst ways). Together, they manage to track down a fragment of the bloodstone&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s in the headdress for a racially insensitive portrayal of an indigenous South American chieftain, who&amp;rsquo;s captured Batroc the Leaper, Baron Zemo, and others on what appears to be a giant roulette wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I buy this comic? (Actually, I know why. I wanted the complete &amp;ldquo;Bloodstone Saga&amp;rdquo; story to offer context for the early appearances of Crossbones. At the moment, I regret this decision.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>