<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Astro City on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</title>
    <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/astro-city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Astro City on From the Long Box: Half-formed Reviews of Comic Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 23:08:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/categories/astro-city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kurt Busiek&#39;s Astro City 009</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 23:08:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, another Astro City post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the original six-issue series, Kurt Busiek, Brent Anderson, and Alex Ross began a new volume whose second storyline has remained, arguably, their best: &amp;ldquo;Confession.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Confession&amp;rdquo; story arc deals with a young man, Brian Kinney, who heads to Astro City from a small town to escape the hardships he&amp;rsquo;d experienced there (mostly dealing with poverty while his father, a doctor, worked thanklessly&amp;ndash;often without pay&amp;ndash;to help his community). After Brian arrived, he eventually became the sidekick to Astro City&amp;rsquo;s most mysterious hero, the Confessor (a clear Batman stand-in, although the comparison&amp;rsquo;s not perfect). Brian&amp;rsquo;s hero persona, by the way, was Altar Boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil everything about this story because it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; well-crafted and, for me, quite powerful emotionally. Suffice it to say that, by the time issue 009&amp;ndash;the final issue in the story&amp;ndash;comes around, the Confessor has died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the cover of this issue, the members of religious super-team The Crossbreed stand in the shadows, a light cast on them from off-panel. Together, the members hold the Confessor&amp;rsquo;s outfit in their hands.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Astro-City-009.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Kurt Busiek&amp;#39;s Astro City 009, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Kurt Busiek&amp;#39;s Astro City issue 009&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After seeing the Confessor die, Brian has to come to terms with his understanding of the world. What does he want to do? Why be a hero at all? Plus, he has to do so in the middle of a MASSIVE crisis&amp;ndash;and not surprisingly, he ends up overwhelmed and shocked by everything he&amp;rsquo;s experienced. The Crossbreed get a hold of Brian and take him to their refuge to rest. There, Noah offers a question to Brian that echoes for me as one of the greatest demonstrations of the superhero ethos I&amp;rsquo;ve read: &amp;ldquo;What is more important? The burdens we bear&amp;ndash;or the way we bear them?&amp;rdquo; I think about this passage a lot. I mean a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Brian makes peace with his past, his family, the Confessor&amp;rsquo;s memory, and he figures out a plan for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s easy for me to see myself in Brian (especially as I was closer to his age when I first read &amp;ldquo;Confession&amp;rdquo;). Maybe I just love a great Batman &amp;amp; Robin story. Maybe this particular story just has everything I wanted to see in a coming-of-age hero tale, plus it tugs on my Catholic upbringing too. Whatever the case &amp;hellip; this is a solid-gold comic. Admittedly, on its own it&amp;rsquo;s a bit tricky to enter into easily, although there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; effort to help a new reader (that said, this is definitely the payoff to several issues&amp;rsquo; unfolding).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also really cool to revisit this story in the context of the Astro City universe&amp;rsquo;s 1:1 time lapse scale to the real world; in the current volume, Brian is older, wiser, and has a ton of tricks up his sleeve regarding superheroics. But I&amp;rsquo;ll admit I miss the old Confessor, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway: this is essential reading material for the superhero comics fan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astro City 024</title>
      <link>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 18:50:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/post/Astro-City-024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Green Lantern remains perhaps my favorite character-specific franchise, &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt; is far and away my single favorite series, ever. It is superhero comics world-building done expertly, pulling together and twisting tropes in a way that has not been done as fully, consistently, or enjoyably by anyone else. Kurt Busiek has it all together here and presents it in full force with Alex Ross covers and (usually) Brent Anderson art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt; is a comic whose stories focus on the titular city (located on the west coast, standing in the place of San Francisco or Seattle), which is populated by more than a century of superhero history. There&amp;rsquo;s an homage or parody to pretty much every superhero type; the very first issue provides an incredible Superman tale via the stand-in Samaritan, the greatest storyline in the title involves a Batman and Robin pair, there&amp;rsquo;s a wisecracking acrobat who annoys &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; he runs into or teams up with, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue, in the third (current) volume, focuses on a talking gorilla from the fabled antarctic Gorilla Mountain. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. What does the gorilla&amp;ndash;who goes by the name &amp;ldquo;Sticks&amp;rdquo; (a nickname for his drumming and because his original name was apparently &amp;ldquo;Stekk&amp;rdquo;)&amp;ndash;want to do with his life? Play music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous issue detailed his initial arrival in Astro City, trying out for a band, and getting caught up in the world of superheroics (after all, he&amp;rsquo;s a talking gorilla! and he has some military training from the Gorilla Mountain forces).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover features Sticks in action, fangs bared, arms raised, and drumsticks in hand(s) as he&amp;rsquo;s in the middle of &lt;em&gt;pounding&lt;/em&gt; on a drum set (whose bass drum features the iconic Astro City &amp;ldquo;rocket&amp;rdquo; icon). An explosion of purple and green motion lines suggest this is a snapshot of an incredibly wild performance.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://brocktopus.github.io/longbox/img/Astro-City-024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover to Astro City 024, described above&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Astro City issue 024&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In this issue, we learn about Sticks&amp;rsquo; past&amp;ndash;why he left Gorilla Mountain and how it&amp;rsquo;s impacted his decision to try being a superhero, since he fits in more easily with them than with the average Astro City resident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the while, Sticks struggles with doing the right thing and &lt;em&gt;wanting&lt;/em&gt; to do the right thing, namely whether or not he should be a superhero just because he can, or if it&amp;rsquo;s better left to those with the drive to pursue it. As he states in a thought/narrative caption: &amp;ldquo;It takes the right kind of &lt;strong&gt;person&lt;/strong&gt; to do this kind of thing. To make it their life, their &lt;strong&gt;mission&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, he quits and reconnects with his old bandmates. Unfortunately, they don&amp;rsquo;t all agree on whether or not to keep associating with Sticks; after all, as a talking gorilla, he draws attention by super-villains and that could be dangerous for his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he&amp;rsquo;s understandable about it, Sticks is nonetheless hurt, and it shows (there&amp;rsquo;s something a bit astounding about feeling a sympathetic connection to a gorilla in a t-shirt). While he sits on a roof at night, Samaritan comes to visit and offers the sort of advice that the best Superman stories always allow him to provide: genuine empathy and consideration that lead toward an optimistic future always left in the listener&amp;rsquo;s hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samaritan acknowledges Sticks doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to be a superhero and doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to convince him otherwise. Instead, he demonstrates that he believes &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a way. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; a way. I &lt;strong&gt;believe&lt;/strong&gt; that. Don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;give up&lt;/strong&gt;. Find a way to do what you love. If I can help, you can call on me. I&amp;rsquo;ll give you an alert code. But find a &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much more of a &lt;em&gt;samaritan&lt;/em&gt; can one be, if not to help lift up another and assist them toward their goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sticks decides to take on the temporary identity of &amp;ldquo;Tuxedo Gorilla&amp;rdquo; in order to make a few higher-profile busts to draw the press so that he can make an announcement: he&amp;rsquo;s having auditions for a super-powered band. His superhero contacts provide security so that no one can disrupt the proceedings (including blocking any sensors attempting to learn the secret identities of auditioners), and he manages to get together a group that have music-oriented abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a record contract ready, Sticks and company decide to record some tricks and &amp;ldquo;fight a little crime along the way&amp;rdquo; as the group &lt;em&gt;Powerchord&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that I love every issue of &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt;, and this is no different. Sticks&amp;rsquo; story is a fantastic origin tale and an accessible jumping-on point for new readers (well, assuming they read issue 023 first). There are so many clear nods to existing comic characters and ideas&amp;ndash;most obviously being Gorilla Mountain&amp;rsquo;s debt to Gorilla City from &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ndash;and they&amp;rsquo;re all taken in really interesting and new directions while feeling familiar or comfortable in the best way(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could only read one comic series from this point forward, it would be &lt;em&gt;Astro City&lt;/em&gt;, without question. And I would stand by that decision happily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>